<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: link | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/link/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-01-25T13:17:49+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shocking ‘Game Of Thrones’ Finale Concludes With Arrest Of 5 Million Viewers For Piracy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/06/17/shocking-game-of-thrones-finale-concludes-with-arrest-of-5-million-viewers-for-piracy/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-17T11:26:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/06/17/shocking-game-of-thrones-finale-concludes-with-arrest-of-5-million-viewers-for-piracy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Onion at its best.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook to Buy WhatsApp for $16+ Billion]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/02/20/facebook-to-buy-whatsapp-for-16-billion/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T12:16:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/02/20/facebook-to-buy-whatsapp-for-16-billion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Re/code:</p>

<blockquote>The move marks the social giant’s biggest acquisition to date, as Facebook paid $16 billion in cash and stock for the company. In addition, the deal includes another $3 billion in restricted stock units for WhatsApp employees, which will vest over a period of time.</blockquote>


<p>Wow. Congratulations to the WhatsApp team, that&rsquo;s an amazing deal. $16 billion is a huge amount of money, but Mark Zuckerberg has historically been very clever when acquiring other companies, even at prices that seemed insane at the time (think Instagram, for example).</p>

<p>I think this makes sense for Facebook, clearly they&rsquo;re interested in reaching WhatsApp&rsquo;s large user base. For me as a user, unfortunately, it means yet another reason not to trust WhatsApp.</p>

<p>The problem is, right now there&rsquo;s no clear alternative. The most interesting one is <a href="https://telegram.org">Telegram</a>, but even though their goal to protect their users&#8217; privacy is noble and their implementation seems serious, it still smells too much of vaporware to me. They refuse to accept money or show adds, so I&rsquo;m not clear on how that bodes for its long-term survival. For now, I think it will have to do, but this is obviously a great opportunity for another player to step in. With a serious proposition, they could grab a significant piece of the market.</p>

<p>For a messaging app, being ubiquitous is the ultimate goal of course, which is why WhatsApp has been able to negotiate such a great deal. Being reliable and gaining your users&#8217; trust, though, is just as important. We&rsquo;ll see how it goes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The One-Person Product]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/05/21/the-one-person-product/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-21T08:13:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/05/21/the-one-person-product</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment, on Yahoo&rsquo;s acquisition of Tumblr:</p>

<blockquote>Anyone who knows David can tell, very clearly, that he wrote every word of his announcement post. Not only did Yahoo let him end it like that, but the subhead on their official press release shows that Tumblr and Yahoo are seeing eye-to-eye on quite a lot already. In many ways, this feels more like a merger than an acquisition.</blockquote>


<p>A great insider&rsquo;s look at Tumblr&rsquo;s history. This deal has so much potential for both companies, I really hope things work out between them. And it goes to show how passionate people can make a difference. Congratulations to everyone over at Tumblr (and Yahoo!). And congratulations to Marco, as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Loop Magazine updated and an apology]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/05/14/the-loop-magazine-updated-and-an-apology/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T09:03:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/05/14/the-loop-magazine-updated-and-an-apology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jim Dalrymple, on the subscription bug that plagued the first two releases of the excellent <a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2013/05/09/the-loop-magazine-for-iphone-and-ipad-released/">The Loop Magazine</a> app:</p>

<blockquote>You deserved a better experience than what we delivered, and we expected more from ourselves. Please accept my apology and know that we are working hard to deliver a great app for you.</blockquote>


<p>Relax Jim, you&rsquo;re trying too hard. Bugs in 1.0 versions are not uncommon, and easily forgivable. Especially when developers react timely and work their asses off to release an update. And yes, even if the update doesn&rsquo;t immediately fix the problem, there&rsquo;s still no harm done. As the saying goes: &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Edward_Hickson">If at first you don&rsquo;t succeed&hellip;</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>We don&rsquo;t expect you guys to be perfect, we just expect you to be professional and respectful towards your customers. And in my book, you certainly have.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Return of NetNewsWire | Black Pixel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/03/21/the-return-of-netnewswire/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-21T09:54:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2013/03/21/the-return-of-netnewswire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is great news for all RSS users out there (myself included), especially given <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/13/4101144/google-shuts-down-reader-rss-aggregation-service">Google Reader&rsquo;s imminent demise</a>.</p>

<p>There is something else worth mentioning though:</p>

<blockquote>As far as sync is concerned, we knew we would likely need an alternative to Google Reader as early as last year. At the time, the option that seemed to make the most sense was to embrace iCloud and Core Data as the new sync solution of choice. We spent a considerable amount of time on this effort, but iCloud and Core Data syncing had issues that we simply could not resolve.

iCloud hasn&#8217;t worked out for us and Google&#8217;s announcement solidified and accelerated our plans.</blockquote>


<p>This isn&rsquo;t the first high-profile developer that wanted to embrace iCloud but was forced to look elsewhere due to Core Data&rsquo;s shortcomings. That&rsquo;s the alarming reality of iCloud today as far as third-party developers are concerned. If Apple wants iCloud to become the de-facto standard in cloud-based data sharing services, they need to step up their game and they need to do it yesterday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
