<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bags | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/bags/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-13T10:46:32+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GORUCK Wire Dopp review over at Tools &amp; Toys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/01/the-goruck-wire-dopp-review-over-at-tools-and-toys/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-01T16:18:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/01/the-goruck-wire-dopp-review-over-at-tools-and-toys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the <a href="http://www.goruck.com/wire-dopp-black/p/GEAR-000128">GORUCK Wire Dopp</a>, an organizational sleeve designed to fit the front slant pocket of the GORUCK backpacks, was published today on <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/22819932434_de0dc081b8_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This was one of those cases when I actually changed my mind about a product after owning it and using it for a while. That’s why I always try to spend a substantial amount of time with any product before reviewing it.</p>

<p>For the first few days after receiving it, I wasn’t entirely sure what the point of it was, and whether I could recommend buying it as an accessory for your GORUCK rucksack. It just seemed too bulky for something designed to hold small items, and stuffing a relatively big sleeve in an already space-constrained pocket didn’t seem like a particularly smart approach.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/22821170453_4c9e3740de_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Then I gave it some thought. On one hand, at $25 it’s well within the impulse-buy price range, and it’s just as well made as all GORUCK products. On the other hand, I didn’t think there was anything wrong with my GORUCK bags that this accessory could solve.</p>

<p>Then I thought about it some more, and realized how I never actually used the front slant pocket on any of my GORUCK bags.</p>

<p>The truth is, as cool-looking as it is, that front pocket is not exactly practical. When the bag is full — which is to say, always — this pocket is so compressed by the rest of the bag’s contents that getting my hand inside to grab anything was hard enough for me to avoid using the pocket entirely.</p>

<p>If that pocket was supposed to act as a convenient place to store a few small items for quick and easy access, it wasn’t really performing as intended.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/22821175433_830afa1e80_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It turns out, the Wire Dopp solves this problem beautifully. By keeping everything inside a sleeve that folds in on itself like a bifold wallet, grabbing an item is as simple as getting the Wire Dopp out of the front pocket, and then finding the item inside.</p>

<p>After a few weeks with it, I now use that front pocket more than ever. I also use the Wire Dopp with my other non-GORUCK bags, and even as a standalone item.</p>

<p>It’s not a perfect accessory, but at $25, the benefits of the Wire Dopp are well worth the price of admission. If you’d like to read more about it, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for the full review.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Ortlieb Back Roller City bicycle panniers on Tools &amp; Toys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/a-review-of-the-ortlieb-back-roller-city-bicycle-panniers-on-tools-and-toys/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-02T17:33:33+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/a-review-of-the-ortlieb-back-roller-city-bicycle-panniers-on-tools-and-toys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> review, by yours truly, touches on a topic near and dear to my heart: the bicycle. In many ways, this article is a love letter to the bicycle as much as it is a review of a bag:</p>

<blockquote><p>On bicycles, humans become the most efficient animals in the world. Whether you’re going for your daily commute or for a week-long adventure surrounded by nature, the bicycle is a great means of transportation that lets you easily move from point A to point B while staying in touch with your environment. Feeling the spring wind in your face as you pedal your way to your destination is one of the greatest pleasures of riding a bike.</p>

<p>Don’t believe it? You need only watch a kid’s face whenever they ride. That invariable expression of pure, unadulterated joy is a tell-tale sign that the bicycle is something special.</p></blockquote>

<p>English author H.G. Wells once said: “<em>Every time I see an adult on a bicycle, I no longer despair for the future of the human race”</em>. I couldn’t agree more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GORUCK GR Echo review on Tools &amp; Toys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/24/the-goruck-gr-echo-review-on-tools-and-toys/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-24T17:19:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/24/the-goruck-gr-echo-review-on-tools-and-toys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the GORUCK GR Echo was published today on Tools &amp; Toys. I love GORUCK bags. I use the GR Echo almost every day for a million different things, and I never leave my house for more than three days without my GR2. In my mind, these are easily some of the best bags money can buy, and I’m thrilled to have had the chance to review the two that I own for Tools &amp; Toys.</p>

<p>I think Tools &amp; Toys is definitely becoming the best place on the Web for in-depth reviews of quality items, and I couldn’t be more proud to see my own work up there on the homepage. It’s an absolute privilege to be able to work with such talented people, and I can’t get enough of it.</p>

<p>As a side note, I arranged my first photo shoot ever with a model for this article and I have to say, I’m super happy with the results. I hope you guys enjoy it as well. And if you’d like to check out all the pictures from the session, I’ve prepared <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/analogsenses/sets/72157651044260567/">a Flickr album</a> with the full-size images.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GORUCK GR2 review over at Tools &amp; Toys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/13/the-goruck-gr2-review-over-at-tools-and-toys/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-13T17:06:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/13/the-goruck-gr2-review-over-at-tools-and-toys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few weeks I’ve had the amazing opportunity to work with <a href="http://shawnblanc.net">Shawn Blanc</a> on a review of the GORUCK GR2 for his gorgeous Tools &amp; Toys website. It’s been an incredible experience, and I had <em>tons</em> of fun along the way. Tools &amp; Toys is one of my favorite websites, and seeing my own work on their homepage is a tremendous honor. I hope you guys enjoy the result as much as I enjoyed the process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
