<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: post | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/post/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-05T11:52:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Déjà vu]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/05/02/deja-vu/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T00:54:34+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/05/02/deja-vu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I collect memories.</p>

<p>This is the story of one of my favorite ones. It&rsquo;s the best kind of story: the one that doesn&rsquo;t have an ending yet. It&rsquo;s about character, and it involves two cities, two airports, and two friends.</p>

<p>The first city is Tampere, Finland. The time is 2006 and it is the last night of my Erasmus year. It&rsquo;s 4 a.m. after a terrific Brazilian dinner, and it&rsquo;s time to leave. Everyone else has left already and when I stand up, I immediately feel the wine in my head. There have been too many glasses, and everything around me seems to move in slow motion. Still, it&rsquo;s time and I need to keep moving. I pick up my luggage, adjust my tie, and I mentally prepare to leave the flat for the last time. I&rsquo;m exhausted and drunk, but it&rsquo;s time.</p>

<p>Then I feel an easy hand on my shoulder. When I turn around, Daniel is still there. He has been there since the beginning. He&rsquo;s just as tired and drunk as I am, but he&rsquo;s still there. He&rsquo;s holding my tennis racket for me, and smiles widely as he walks me out of the flat. We close the door and go out on the street together, where a taxi is waiting to take me to the airport. Behind we leave a place that we have filled with many great memories over the last year.</p>

<p>Daniel doesn&rsquo;t live there anymore. He moved to the city center about four months earlier, but he wanted to keep me company on my last night, and he decided that it should be something special. He cooked dinner, a Brazilian traditional recipe, and he made sure that we would have enough red wine to last the entire night. We ate, drank and talked, and now it was time to say goodbye. This is a tough moment for me, the end of the Erasmus and going back to my life as I knew it, but somehow having Daniel besides me makes it right. He was the first person I met in Finland. It was only fitting that he would also be the last.</p>

<p>He will still spend a couple more months in Finland before flying back to Brazil, and we have agreed to meet in Spain before he leaves, so we both know that it&rsquo;s not really a goodbye. Not yet anyway. It is with that small comfort that we hug each other and shake hands for the last time, just before I get into the taxi and head to the Tampere Airport.</p>

<p>The second city is Berlin, Germany, and the time is now. As I type these lines I&rsquo;m in a Lufthansa flight, heading back to Madrid after spending a weekend there with Daniel. I hadn&rsquo;t seen him since August 2006, when I got to show him a little bit of Spain, including Madrid and my home town, Plasencia. When he emailed me a few months ago because he was planning a trip to Europe and asked if we could meet, it was a no-brainer. It took us a while to work out our schedules, but there was never any doubt that we would meet somewhere in the Old Continent.</p>

<p>I arrived in Berlin on Friday afternoon. He had been there for a couple days already so he offered to pick me up at my hotel. Right away it felt like it was two weeks ago that we were having beers in Tampere, instead of five years. It felt great to recognize his smile, his calm demeanor and his slow, careful and precise movements. To prove that, even after not seeing each other for so long, we remain simply two very good friends that get along pretty damn well. I also got to meet his good friend Henrieke, a charming, lovely girl that was his host in the city, and that was nice enough to take great care of me as well and show us around.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a fantastic weekend, filled with good laughs, great beer, and even a quiet, relaxing morning in one of the nicest parks of the city, drinking <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mate_(beverage">mate</a>) under a bright, yellow sun. Unfortunately, time flies when you&rsquo;re having fun, and soon it was already Sunday and we were at the Berlin-Tegel airport again, getting ready to leave. He&rsquo;s going on to Finland to continue his month-long trip around Europe, and I&rsquo;m going back home. Henrieke was so nice that she even came to the airport with us, and I leave Germany knowing that I have made a new friend, and written a new chapter with an old one. When I hugged him goodbye, I had a strangely familiar feeling, but this time around I&rsquo;m confident that it was not really a goodbye, but rather a &ldquo;see you next time&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Daniel is an authentic person. He remains the most clear example I know of someone who values and treasures his personal relationships more than anything. To him, time and attention are two precious things that must not be taken for granted. Until just a while ago, he didn&rsquo;t even have a cell phone, but in my experience living with him this was never a problem. Whenever we wanted to meet or do anything, we would always find a way to make it work. He&rsquo;s proof that we don&rsquo;t really need to bury ourselves in technology and social networks just for the sake of it, or because it&rsquo;s the norm. He taught me that there can be another way to connect with people, a way that starts by looking the other person in the eyes.</p>

<p>This time, Daniel and I have agreed that our next meeting will be in Brazil. It looks like December might be a good time. I honestly cannot imagine how a New Year&rsquo;s Eve in the Brazilian Summer must be like, but I do know one thing: I really want to find out.</p>

<p>Only time will tell if it&rsquo;s meant to happen. Until then, our memories will have to do. And now, we have a great new one to hold onto.</p>

<p>Cheers, my friend. Take care, and see you next time.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/analogsenses/5678188902/"><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5262/5678188902_c1e0cc1c01.jpg" alt="Mate in Berlin" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Licence to Cure]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/04/14/licence-to-cure/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T14:16:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/04/14/licence-to-cure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These are interesting times to be an engineer. For the past 3 years I have been working as a researcher in the <a href="http://lobezno.gbt.tfo.upm.es/portalGBT/index.php?lang=english">Bioengineering and Telemedicine Group</a> at <a href="http://www.upm.es/internacional">Technical University of Madrid</a> (GBT-UPM), where I&rsquo;ve been lucky enough to be involved in a number of exciting projects. I feel very fortunate to be a part of this group, because every day I get to work with extremely talented people who are just as passionate about their work as I am.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always found the engineering occupation to be very rewarding. It is an engineer&rsquo;s privilege, and his duty[1. DISCLAIMER: The male form &ldquo;his&rdquo; is used throughout this article simply as a convenience. There are plenty of female engineers out there, you know.], to summon every ounce of human knowledge and use it to build something that will actually improve people&rsquo;s lives. In a way, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biomedical_engineering">biomedical engineering</a> is perhaps one of the truest engineering disciplines: it lies very close to the core values of our profession.</p>

<p>As biomedical engineers, we don&rsquo;t cure patients; our goal is to use technology to create the kind of tools that will help doctors do their job better. We analyze their problems, and imagine new ways to solve them. We make sure they have exactly what they need, exactly when they need it, to the best of our ability. This is an exciting and demanding challenge that constantly requires us to push the state of the art and find new ways to innovate. We are the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Q_(James_Bond">Q Branch</a>) at the service of a medical James Bond, only instead of jet packs and explosive pens, we come up with <a href="http://lobezno.gbt.tfo.upm.es/portalGBT/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=17&amp;Itemid=1000">artificial pancreases</a> and <a href="http://lobezno.gbt.tfo.upm.es/portalGBT/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=9&amp;Itemid=1000">virtual reality surgical simulators</a>.</p>

<p>And it&rsquo;s not only doctors that we get to help. Our job has a huge impact on their patients&#8217; lives, too. We build <a href="http://lobezno.gbt.tfo.upm.es/portalGBT/index.php?option=com_content&amp;&amp;task=view&amp;id=84&amp;Itemid=1000">systems and devices</a> that allow people struck by accident or disease to regain control of their lives. We offer them a chance to be self-sufficient again, to overcome their challenges, and move on.</p>

<p>These are some of the reasons why I love doing what I do. Also, they resonate very well with the purpose of Analog Senses. As <a href="http://popwatch.ew.com/2011/03/02/ipad-2-steve-jobs/">a certain somebody</a> already said, I have always felt that technology alone is not enough. I suppose this is also in no small part why I love Apple. For them, technology is at its best when connected with the liberal arts. In my job, it is at the service of the medical sciences. For Analog Senses, it should be a way to enhance human interaction, while still keeping it human.</p>

<p>If you were to casually browse through the archives, you would notice that most of the posts and links here reference Apple. This is not intentional, I assure you, but it isn&rsquo;t coincidental, either. It is only a by-product of a simple reality: when it comes to technology and humans, Apple gets it, most others don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>And so, it is with great excitement that we take on the new challenge of iOS development in the group, specifically targeting the iPad. Analyzing the current technological landscape, it&rsquo;s easy to see why. Not only is it a great device for normal people to use (some might disagree, but that&rsquo;s a whole other article), but its potential in the medical field is unmatched. The form-factor, the battery life, the connectivity features, the robust aluminum shell&hellip; all these things make the iPad the ultimate medical gadget. Even though its official adoption by clinical centers is still in the early stages, many doctors around the world <a href="http://articles.boston.com/2011-04-04/business/29380774_1_ipad-tablet-computers-ulcer">are personally embracing it</a> as part of their everyday equipment:</p>

<blockquote>Other devices available at the hospital — computers on wheels, static workstations, laptops, tablet computers — fall short in critical ways, said Feldman and Dr. Larry Nathanson, an emergency physician and fellow iPad evangelist. Size, weight, and battery life get in the way, they said, and nothing can be flipped around and used at the bedside like an iPad.</blockquote>


<p>The iPad&rsquo;s hardware is ideally suited to be a doctor&rsquo;s constant companion, but its greatest strength is undoubtedly the software. iOS is a solid foundation to build upon, and the official SDK allows us to turn the iPad into a swiss army knife of medical applications. We can build an app that allows doctors to check the electronic health records of their patients with just a few taps. We can enable them to monitor their progress and adjust their treatment in real-time. We can help them be closer to their patients, so that they&rsquo;re able to guide and educate them through recovery much more efficiently, eliminating the need to be physically at their side, but also letting them know that they are never alone.</p>

<p>And while doctors can benefit greatly from using an iPad, the advantages for patients are even more impressive. From a doctor&rsquo;s standpoint, it is a great tool to increase efficiency, but for patients it can actually be the device they use to receive their treatment.</p>

<p>A perfect example of this situation is the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telerehabilitation">telerehabilitation</a> field, where our group has considerable experience. Thanks to technology, patients are able to train and recover from traumatic brain injury or stroke, from the comfort of their own homes. By creating simple rehabilitation exercises, clinically designed to target and engage their cognitive functions, we can help them regain as much of their lost capacity as possible. This is not only about managing resources and cutting costs, but about delivering a more personalized treatment and ensuring <a href="http://www.aafp.org/online/en/home/policy/policies/c/continuityofcaredefinition.html">continuity of care</a>, two of the critical aspects of neuro-rehabilitation.</p>

<p>Technology has made all of this possible, and the iPad is the perfect instrument to take it one step further. It fits very well into a patient&rsquo;s home, eliminating all the clutter and the technical difficulties commonly associated with computers (not to mention that these are people affected by cognitive impairment). Instead, the clean, intuitive interface of the iPad allows them to focus more easily on the task at hand. When technology becomes human, it can really make a difference.</p>

<p>For all the talk and speculation about the iPad&rsquo;s usefulness, it has been a runaway success. In less than a year, it has changed the way we interact with computers, forever. And it will change the way medical devices are conceived, too. What&rsquo;s most fascinating is that its potential remains largely untapped. We are only beginning to understand the possibilities of such a device, and people are coming up with amazing new applications every day. From an engineering perspective, as we embark on this new challenge, I&rsquo;m incredibly excited about the future.</p>

<p>The reason I get up and go to work every day is not just to tinker with XCode, but to build something that will change people&rsquo;s lives for the better. That&rsquo;s deeply engraved in my DNA, and I cannot think of a better way to do it. As we go back to the lab and start planning our next step, I can&rsquo;t help but play a scene in my mind, wherein a white-coated figure greets us, and we say:</p>

<blockquote>Morning, Dr. Bond. Here&#8217;s your new iPad. Complete, of course, with all the usual refinements.</blockquote>


<p>007 has Q. Doctors have us. And now, we have the iPad. Together, villains don&rsquo;t stand a chance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weekend Edition Linked-List]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/28/the-weekend-edition-linked-list/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-28T09:43:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/28/the-weekend-edition-linked-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Admittedly, I&rsquo;ve been giggling over the iPad 2 like a little girl since <a href="http://analogsenses.com/2011/03/25/enter-the-ipad-2/">I got it on Friday</a>, which hasn&rsquo;t left me much time to write a decent post, or compile the hottest stories of the past two days. That is not to say that there weren&rsquo;t any stories, on the contrary: some of them were pretty good, and a couple were simply hilarious.</p>

<p>The problem with being a little late is that most of these stories have already been reported in many fine places all over the Web, so instead of sounding like broken record, I&rsquo;m just going to point you towards them and let you see for yourself.</p>

<p>All right, let&rsquo;s do this!</p>

<ul>
<li><p>First, there was <a href="http://mike3k.posterous.com/best-app-store-review-ever">an Epic Color review</a> in the App Store. Just read it all the way through, it is worth it. Via <a href="https://twitter.com/gruber/status/52010186084327424">@gruber</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Also, <a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/158849/2011/03/macalope_noyes.html">The Macalope went nuts</a> over Katherine Hayes and her dislike <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/223204/why_tablets_are_just_a_fad.html">for tablets in general</a>, and <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/businesscenter/article/221306/why_the_ipad_2_leaves_me_cold.html">the iPad 2 in particular</a>. Via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2011/03/26/macalope">Daring Fireball</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>TechCrunch reported that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/03/26/ios-5-likely-pushed-to-the-fall-after-a-cloud-unveiling-at-wwdc/">iOS 5 will be delayed</a>, possibly until Fall, and probably in the September iPod event. They claim that the iPhone 5 will debut in June as expected, but no iOS5 goodness just yet.</p></li>
<li><p>Marco Arment broke down <a href="http://www.marco.org/4073734086">the numbers of Instapaper usage</a> across devices and iOS versions. Turns out pretty much everyone is running on new hardware, and at least iOS 4.</p></li>
<li><p>A 14-year-old (!) named J-P Teti absolutely nailed <a href="http://jpteti.com/post/4072771125/the-ipad-is-99-more-open-than-any-other-computer">why the iPad is massively misunderstood</a> by its competitors. Turns out there are more regular people than geeks out there. Via <a href="http://minimalmac.com/post/4076312420/j-p-teti-the-ipad-is-99-more-open-than-any-other">Minimal Mac</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>To stay with the youth theme, there was another teenager, this time a 15-year-old (I know, it seems way too old after the last story) who <a href="http://mattrichman.tumblr.com/post/4076905315/blackberry-asp-in-q4-2011">explained the Average Selling Price</a> (ASP) of RIM&rsquo;s Blackberry devices. RIM hasn&rsquo;t reported these numbers since last quarter and, surprise surprise, everything indicates that&rsquo;s because the numbers are going down. In a hurry. RIM is in trouble. Via <a href="https://twitter.com/asymco/status/51232234962821121">@asymco</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Finally, Mashable reported that Google <a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/24/honeycomb-delay/">is not ready to release Honeycomb&rsquo;s source code</a> just yet. This flies right in the face of the &ldquo;open&rdquo; philosophy that Google likes to brag about. Looks like it&rsquo;s not so easy to maintain a platform when everyone is free to tinker with it. They say it will be released eventually, just like Adobe says Flash is going to run smoothly on mobile devices, like, tomorrow. Call me a cynic, but it seems to me that tomorrow never actually becomes today.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And that was pretty much it over the weekend. I will leave you with a note regarding my first impressions of the iPad 2:</p>

<p>You know how it is when you have a brand new device: you just can&rsquo;t stop playing with it, installing apps, configuring it, arranging it so that it is exactly right. Well, after a weekend of Geek Abuse &trade;, the iPad 2 managed to get through to Sunday night and still have an impressive 15% battery life remaining. I had to plug it occasionally in order to sync it, but never for more than 5 minutes at a time.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s big.</p>

<p>Now have a good one! Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enter the iPad 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/26/enter-the-ipad-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-26T01:14:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/26/enter-the-ipad-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As of today, I&rsquo;m the proud owner of a 32 GB, WiFi-only white iPad 2. If you don&rsquo;t get it on Day One, it doesn&rsquo;t count ;)</p>

<p>I have to admit that this is not the first time I&rsquo;ve done something like this: I waited more than 6 hours in line to get my iPhone 3G, the first one that was sold in Spain, on July 11th 2008, Day One. I still use it as my one and only phone.</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t get the original iPad when it was released here, but after this year, I have realized that this is a revolution I want to be a part of.</p>

<p>And this time I only had to wait for 30 minutes&hellip; Great :)</p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s get this party started!</p>

<p><a href="http://instagr.am/p/Ch1x6/"><img src="http://images.instagram.com/media/2011/03/25/7e502f67d8ac4d7289ac966b31ac82a9_7.jpg" alt="Apple's iPad 2" /> </a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martinis on the Titanic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/22/martinis-on-the-titanic/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-22T22:03:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2011/03/22/martinis-on-the-titanic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the interest of full disclosure, let me get something out of the way:</p>

<p>Sometimes I can be an ass.</p>

<p>In my usual state I&rsquo;m a laid-back kind of guy. I&rsquo;m relaxed, I don&rsquo;t obsess over things, and I don&rsquo;t give in to the &ldquo;<a href="http://www.randsinrepose.com/archives/2004/03/14/were_doomed.html">We&rsquo;re Doomed!</a>&rdquo; frenzy when things look bad. However, there are certain moments when I&rsquo;m working, writing, or simply focused on doing something I like, that I find it extremely irksome to be interrupted by someone who just wants to talk, has a few minutes to spare and decides to poke me for a quick chat. If you&rsquo;re on the other end of the phone and I seem irritated to be talking to you, I most probably am, but do not worry, that is just me being an ass. Please, accept my heartfelt apologies. I know that my behavior is considerably rude and, though I try to get better at it, I know that sometimes I fail. Deeply.</p>

<p>But, since I can&rsquo;t promise you that my behavior will magically stop one day, the least I can do is tell you what you can do to minimize the chances of me going haywire on you. First, let me explain what the source of many of my frustrations here in the 21st Century is:</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperconnectivity">Hyperconnectivity</a> kills.</p>

<p>All right, not quite, fair enough, but it can be annoying as hell. We are so intertwined with the fabric of the Internet that we have reached a point where it is way too difficult to pull back and disappear. To find solitude amidst the army of Twitters, Google Talks, MSN Messengers, Facebook chats, emails, SMSs&hellip; you name it. We have created a Babel Tower of connectivity so steep that I fear we may have lost our ability to function somewhere along the way towards always-ON status.</p>

<p>Nowhere is this more evident than when you absolutely must focus on the very single task at hand, to the point of banishing everything and everyone else from your mind. At that precise moment, under pressure, the Universe will mercilessly bomb you with instant messages, unread emails and friend requests, and you need to know when to say no. If you are an easy procrastinator, managing these distractions can be daunting.</p>

<p>However, there is hope. Hyperconnectivity is an annoyance that is endemic to the Internet and, as such, there is no point in fighting it. You have to learn how to tame it, make it work with you rather than against you. As a general rule, I am almost never signed into GTalk, or MSN. I do very rarely check my Facebook page, because honestly I don&rsquo;t care for it, and Twitter is something I only check on my iPhone, which is conveniently silenced and tucked away in my coat during working hours. If something is so urgent that it cannot wait, your best bet is an email, or the office phone. All this may seem excessive, but even with my sheer determination in the quest for ninja-like invisibility, distractions still manage to find their way towards me almost every day. And then, when all the other carefully deployed measures have failed, is when I need to master the most difficult skill of all: dealing with people who &ldquo;just want to talk&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I respect my peers, and my friends. I firmly believe that their time and attention are precious resources that should not be taken lightly. And so, I try to never abuse them. This means I will probably never call you unless I actually have something to tell you. Sounds simple, right? Well, apparently it&rsquo;s not.</p>

<p>The fundamental problem is that whenever I am contacted by someone, I assume (erroneously, of course) that they operate under the same code of conduct, and since they&rsquo;re calling me they must surely have a powerful reason to do so, so I feel compelled to answer. It&rsquo;s not like me to leave someone hanging, and I find it really difficult to ignore the call (because, again, I don&rsquo;t like to be ignored when I call to say something important). Therefore, I will most likely pick up the phone or answer to your chat, if only out of pure social etiquette.</p>

<p>Unfortunately for you, that is not to say that I will be pleased to hear your voice. For courtesy&rsquo;s sake, I will try to mask my impatience and I will endure a little bit of small talk while my brain allocates 100% of its resources to figuring out why the hell you&rsquo;re calling me and, most importantly, what I need to do in order to end this call as soon as possible. Since I have a short fuse, this process typically only lasts a few seconds, and if you&rsquo;re not quick to reveal your intentions, I will ask you point-blank. At this point, I have stopped whatever it is that I was doing, and I am completely focused on you, which means that if there is something you wanted to tell me, you would do well in telling me now. Of course, I understand that sometimes people just want to talk, and there&rsquo;s nothing wrong with that. But if that&rsquo;s what you want, please say so. I will either politely tell you that I&rsquo;m busy at this point and that I will call you back, or I will make up my mind and stop trying to put an end to the conversation so we can both relax and talk about the movie we watched the other night.</p>

<p>It may seem irrelevant to the untrained eye, but there is a profound difference between the two mental scenarios described above: in one, I am dealing with your call as a short interruption of my workflow. An interruption that should be managed and terminated as quickly as possible so that we can both resume what we were doing, which was surely more important. As such, I am listening to what you&rsquo;re telling me, but I&rsquo;m not <em>really</em> focused on you just yet: deep down, I&rsquo;m still processing my main task. You may steal some brain cycles from me, but the ship is staying its course. A good example would be you calling me because you need me to send you some file, remind you of a phone number, etc.</p>

<p>The other scenario requires a complete interruption of my current activity, and a mental relocation in order to ensure that we are both on the same page. It&rsquo;s a conversation that may extend for a few minutes, and that requires my full attention. You may be having a terrible day, or you just got fired, or maybe you can&rsquo;t stop thinking about the pretty girl that smiled at you in the bar last Saturday. Either way, I&rsquo;m not getting off the hook so easily. It is a Titanic-like wreckage, and you and me will be sipping Martinis on the deck until the band stops taking requests, so I might as well sit back and enjoy it.</p>

<p>My point is that in any normal conversation between human beings, context is necessary. When you call me, you need to be aware that I don&rsquo;t have any way of knowing which of the above scenarios I&rsquo;m dealing with. It&rsquo;s that lack of information that I find extremely annoying. My lizard brain reaction is just an attempt to figure out the context of the situation, and once I have that context I can function properly, and stop being an ass.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
