<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: weekly linkage | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/weekly-linkage/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-05T12:24:58+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Coffee, To Go Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/05/morning-coffee-to-go-edition/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-05T13:22:09+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/05/morning-coffee-to-go-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there, welcome to this special, to go edition of <em>Morning Coffee</em>.</p>

<p>Life’s been particularly busy around these parts lately, and I’m afraid I’ll continue to be pressed for time for the next few days at least. As a result, there will be no essay this week, and instead I’ll leave you with the usual selection of some of the best pieces of writing on the Internet — and yes, that’s Internet with a capital “I”.</p>

<p>It’s important to keep a flexible enough work schedule. That will help you accommodate most changes without disrupting your plans, most of the time. It’s just a smart thing to do, and provides some extra peace of mind. I always try to do that.</p>

<p>Eventually, however, a day will come when circumstances change beyond your control and/or ability to anticipate those changes, and you’ll have to adapt. And sometimes, you’ll need to accept there’s nothing you can do about it. Learning to be OK with that can be quite difficult, but it’s also a very valuable skill, as it allows you to keep your eye on the ball despite the occasional hiccup.</p>

<p>I suppose there’s a lesson to be learned from that.</p>

<h2>Issue #43: Motorcycle-proof cameras and the death of the Internet</h2>

<p>No animals, domestic or otherwise, were harmed in the selection of these pieces. Enjoy responsibly.</p>

<h3><a href="https://theringer.com/the-day-the-internet-became-internet-9d884194abe3#.i4etjwvau">The Day the Internet Became “internet” | Alyssa Bereznak →</a></h3>

<p>The Associated Press has now officially changed their <em>AP Stylebook</em> to de-capitalize the words “internet”, and “web”. Moreover, many important publications, including <em>The New York Times</em>, have announced they will follow suit. No offense, but the AP, the NYT, and whoever else has a problem with capitalizing the Internet can kiss my ass on this one.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h3><a href="https://brooksreview.net/2016/06/home-office/">Crafting My Home Office | Ben Brooks →</a></h3>

<p>Great piece from Ben on how important it is to ruthlessly defend your working space. I wholeheartedly agree — and by the way: nice office, Ben.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<h3><a href="https://medium.com/@sdw/two-and-a-half-years-13-countries-1-camera-the-leica-m-review-6fb09b84d8b3#.l6vbg6f2h">Two and a half years, 13 countries, 1 camera: The Leica M Review | Sebastiaan de With →</a></h3>

<p>This is without a doubt the best Leica M review you’ll see on the Web — see what I did there?</p>

<p>In fact, this review is so good that it had me looking at used Leica M3’s on eBay for a good long while after I finished reading it. And if you’re a <a href="http://www.candid.fm">Candid</a> listener, you know I don’t say that lightly.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>


<h3><a href="http://espn.go.com/tennis/french16/story/_/id/12187672">Rafael Nadal a victim of his own mental and physical strengths | Greg Garber →</a></h3>

<p>Rafael Nadal is one of the best tennis players ever, but his incredibly physical playing style has been taking a tremendous toll on his body for many years now, and he may be close to breaking down for good.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h3><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/06/01/sports/basketball/golden-state-warriors-oklahoma-city-thunder-nba-playoffs.html">Comparisons? Golden State Warriors Are Playing a Different Game | Harvey Araton →</a></h3>

<p>The Warriors are making history, and there are two very good reasons for that: Stephen Curry and Klay Thompson.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h3><a href="http://swanh.net">Star Wars Episode IV in one picture | Martin Panchaud →</a></h3>

<p>This bonus link for the week was absolutely brilliant.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<h2>Afterword</h2>

<p>Just like the foreword, I’m afraid the afterword will have to be cut short this week. Life permitting, the usual Morning Coffee format will be back next week. Until then, have a wonderful Sunday, and thank you for reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/29/morning-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-29T14:27:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/29/morning-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there, welcome to another issue of <em>Morning Coffee</em>.</p>

<p>This week I want to take a look at the final game of the UEFA Champions League, which was contested by Real Madrid and Atlético de Madrid yesterday in Milano. For the second time in just three years, these two teams from the same city competed for the most prestigious title in European football — wait, I mean soccer.</p>

<h2>Issue #42: The UEFA Champions League trophy goes back to Madrid</h2>

<p>What a game. Not that we haven’t seen it before, though.</p>

<p>Two years ago, Real Madrid won the title in heroic fashion, after Sergio Ramos scored a goal in the nick of time to tie the scoreboard at 1-1 and send the game into the overtime, saving his team from certain defeat. In the overtime, Real Madrid were just fresher and capitalized on the shift in momentum, taking the game 4-1. It was a cruel defeat for Atlético’s fans, who saw the trophy slip right through their fingers, despite almost touching it for the better part of 90 minutes.</p>

<p>This time around, it was once again Real Madrid that took the trophy home, and it was an even tougher defeat for Atlético, if that’s even possible. An early goal by Sergio Ramos — again — put Real Madrid in the lead, and Atlético were forced to adjust their strategy, playing in a way that does not come naturally to them.</p>

<p>Much to their credit, they did an excellent job and managed to create a few clear goal chances, only to see them foiled at the last second. They even missed a penalty kick in the beginning of the second half, something that is extremely difficult to put behind when the stakes are this high.</p>

<p>But if Atlético have one character trait as team, it is their absolute refusal to give up. They kept pressing on and eventually, Yannick Carrasco somehow found the perfect way to finish a tremendous offensive play and put the scoreboard back on level terms. It was back to square one.</p>

<p>By that point there were only 15 minutes left and both teams were understandably cautious, so there weren’t any more serious chances for either team before the referee signaled the end of the 90-minute game. Just like in Lisbon two years ago, the final was headed into the overtime.</p>

<p>However, this year there would be no glorious victory in the overtime, no epic goals and, frankly, not much to speak of at all. Both teams were exhausted due to the extreme physicality of the game, and most players were just trying to make it to the end, fighting the cramps and the pain in order to remain in play. Some, like Filipe Luis, didn’t make it and had to be replaced. Others, like Gareth Bale, managed to hold on through sheer force of will.</p>

<p>It was time for the penalties.</p>

<p>Whenever a game of this magnitude has to be decided by a penalty shootout, there’s always drama. Some people say penalty shootouts are cruel, and unfair. I disagree. I believe in sports, you need to make your own luck.</p>

<p>Losing by the narrowest of margins always stings, but such is the way of the game. And so, when Juanfran missed the penalty that would ultimately bring down Atlético, the look on his face was heartbreaking, but he shouldn’t be the one to blame. After all, both teams had 120 minutes to earn the trophy and the simple truth is, both failed to do so. Just like victories are team efforts, defeats too must be endured collectively.</p>

<p>I have no doubt Atlético will recover. Another admirable character trait they share is their utter belief in hard work as the only valid path to greatness. They believe soccer is a meritocracy, and that the best team is the one that wins. That sounds like a simple enough philosophy, but Atlético have proven time and time again that they actually live by it, which is a lot harder than it seems, especially on nights like this.</p>

<p>For Real Madrid, last night was one for the history books: 11 Champions League titles, and counting. No other team comes even close to those numbers, and it’s time for a well-deserved celebration. For Atlético, on the other hand, it’s time to get back to work.</p>

<p>Fortunately, nobody does it better than them.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h2>Top Five: Uncharted 4, a missing parrot, Google’s CEO, and the perils of losing our free will</h2>

<p>This week’s selection comes to you fresh off the presses. Enjoy.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/culture/news/uncharted-4-director-neil-druckmann-on-nathan-drake-sexism-in-games-20160524">’Uncharted 4’ Director Neil Druckmann on Nathan Drake, Sexism in Games (SPOILER ALERT) | Chris Suellentrop →</a></h3>

<p>This was a really great interview with Uncharted 4’s creative director Neil Druckmann for Rolling Stone. I love how straightforward and down-to-earth this guy is. It’s kind of crazy when you realize he’s been responsible for several of the greatest video games of all time, some of which have budgets comparable to Hollywood blockbuster movies.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h3><a href="http://allenchou.net/2016/05/a-brain-dump-of-what-i-worked-on-for-uncharted-4/">A Brain Dump of What I Worked on for Uncharted 4 | Allen Chou →</a></h3>

<p>Another Uncharted 4 link for you, this time from Allen Chou, one of the developers who worked on the game. I love these behind-the-scenes pieces, and it’s always interesting to learn just how much work it takes to create a game like Uncharted 4. really impressive stuff.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<h3><a href="http://digg.com/2016/parrot-witness-protection">The Strange Tale of Echo, the Parrot Who Saw Too Much | Laurel Braitman →</a></h3>

<p>This is priceless. A parrot that used to belong to a New Orleans crime boss has disappeared, and people are looking for him because, get this, they want to put him in a witness protection program.</p>

<p>Apparently, the parrot was saying things he really shouldn’t be saying, and some people think he could provide critical testimony that could help put his owner away. I know how ridiculous that sounds, but it looks like it’s not all BS:</p>

<blockquote><p>Certain species in particular, can be spot-on imitators of the sounds around them—from the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXUrVXtCprU">mundane cell phone conversation</a> of their owners to <a href="https://youtu.be/GcbYHWUnE0I?t=23s">calling the family dog by name</a> and then <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G268RE6GR4Y">bark just like them</a>. They can mimic the beep of a microwave or a cell-phone ring so closely that it’s confusing. Sometimes they mimic <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2M8jxB0LZeA">other things people do too</a>.</p></blockquote>

<p>I know this is a serious matter, but it’s hard not to laugh at that last one.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>


<h3><a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/mathonan/searching-for-google-ceo-sundar-pichai-the-most-powerful-tec">Searching for Sundar Pichai | Mat Honan →</a></h3>

<p>This was an interesting profile on Google’s CEO. Come to think of it, I knew almost nothing about the man, which seems kind of crazy considering how huge a company Google is, and how much media attention it garners.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h3><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/06/theres-no-such-thing-as-free-will/480750/">There’s No Such Thing as Free Will  | Stephen Cave →</a></h3>

<p>And here’s your existential piece of the week. There are lots of troubling ideas to consider here:</p>

<blockquote><p>Determinism not only undermines blame, Smilansky argues; it also undermines praise. Imagine I do risk my life by jumping into enemy territory to perform a daring mission. Afterward, people will say that I had no choice, that my feats were merely, in Smilansky’s phrase, “an unfolding of the given,” and therefore hardly praiseworthy. And just as undermining blame would remove an obstacle to acting wickedly, so undermining praise would remove an incentive to do good. Our heroes would seem less inspiring, he argues, our achievements less noteworthy, and soon we would sink into decadence and despondency.</p></blockquote>

<p>So basically, the day we stop believing in free will, we become total assholes. Food for thought.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h2>Afterword</h2>

<p>How’s your week been? Mine has been interesting. I’m now working on a review of <a href="http://amzn.to/1OVriPq"><em>Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End</em></a>, after thoroughly enjoying the heck out of that game. It’s been a truly impressive experience, and definitely the prettiest game I’ve ever seen. If I had to rank it, it would place a close second to <a href="http://amzn.to/1TQgU0X"><em>The Last of Us</em></a> in my all-time list, but that’s only because <em>The Last of Us</em> is so emotional and character-driven that it really transcends the medium.</p>

<p>Other than that, things seem a bit quieter than usual on the Internet, although the calm is definitely not going to last. With WWDC just around the corner, we’re about to go from 0 to 60 in the blink of an eye, so I’ll happily take the down time now.</p>

<p>Thank you for reading, and have a great Sunday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/15/morning-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-15T14:29:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/15/morning-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there, welcome to another issue of <em>Morning Coffee</em>.</p>

<p>Yesterday I started playing one of the most widely anticipated video games of all time: <em><a href="http://amzn.to/1Tc2LfU">Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End</a></em>. This is perhaps the first game that pushes the PS4 hardware clearly beyond what last-gen consoles were capable of doing, and it’s remarkable in its own right for being the last entry in Naughty Dog’s extremely popular <em><a href="http://amzn.to/1qlvVvK">Uncharted</a></em> series.</p>

<p><em>Uncharted 4</em> has been a long time in the making. This series is the reason I bought a PS3 a few years ago, and I have to say I’ve enjoyed each chapter with the wide-eyed enthusiasm of a ten-year-old kid. These games offer a cinematic experience that is easily on par with big budget Hollywood films, and now with <em>Uncharted 4</em>, Naughty Dog has raised the bar significantly, delivering a true work of art in video game form.</p>

<p>Not that it’s their first time, mind you.</p>

<p>Naughty Dog has a long and rich history of delivering masterpieces, but in my mind there’s one particular game that sits head and shoulders above everything else we’ve ever seen in the industry. That’s what I’d love to tell you about today.</p>

<h2>Issue #41: The Last of Us (No Spoilers)</h2>

<p>Let me preface this by saying I don’t consider myself a gamer in the popular sense of the term. I’ve only played a handful of PS3 games — literally — and I only bought the PS4 this week to be able to play <em>Uncharted 4</em>. I’m not crazy about beating skill-based games, or spending hundreds of hours building a character in a made-up universe — with perhaps one or two <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A3sBZ5Nr4hc">notable exceptions</a>.</p>

<p>My ambitions when it comes to gaming are fairly modest: have fun, and experience truly compelling stories. That’s why I love the <em>Uncharted</em> series, and the recent <em><a href="http://amzn.to/1TeJ561">Tomb Raider</a></em> reboot. They’re just lots of fun to play, but they’re also incredible stories, told in a medium with an unparalleled capacity for immersion. If you’ve ever cried at the movies, you probably know what I’m talking about. Great games offer the same experience, only dialed up to eleven.</p>

<p>However, every once in a while there comes a game so remarkable that it fully and completely transcends the previously known limitations of the medium and becomes something else entirely. These are incredibly rare, and may come only once in a generation. <em><a href="http://amzn.to/251XIEq">The Last of Us</a></em> is exactly that kind of game.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/26419667804_fa85a50272_k.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>On its face, the premise of the game seems fairly simple: set in a dystopian future where a virus has wiped out most of the human race and turned them into fungi-shaped zombies, two mean-spirited scavengers are tasked with smuggling a teenage girl out of a quarantine zone. So far, nothing seems out of the ordinary: just another zombie-ridden survival game, right?</p>

<p>Wrong.</p>

<p>What sets <em>The Last of Us</em> apart from many other games is the depth and complexity of its characters. There are zombies in the game, yes, but the story is never about them. It’s not even about the Fireflies, a so-called resistance group that’s apparently looking for a cure. <em>The Last of Us</em> tells a story that is much smaller in scope, but much bigger in relevance. It’s the story of a broken man and a lost girl, both of whom stubbornly refuse to give up even in the face of insurmountable odds. It’s a story about family, and love. A story about growing up, and learning to let go.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/26751418010_8ffafe4e7e_o.jpg" width="960"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Right from the beginning, <em>The Last of Us</em> punches you in the stomach with a scene so poignant and tragic that you have no choice but to instantly empathize with Joel, the main playable character in the game. By bearing witness to this traumatic event, we’re prepared to understand — if not quite forgive — Joel for any questionable actions he may go on to commit over the course of the story. And boy, does he commit them. Clearly, you don’t get to survive long in a zombie apocalypse by being nice.</p>

<p>Ellie, on the other hand, represents the polar opposite of Joel. She was born after the world had already ended, so this life is all she’s ever known. She hasn’t had to go through the incredibly difficult process of losing everything we take for granted, and that has given her the rare ability to remain innocent in a world dominated by cruelty and violence. While Joel broke a long time ago, Ellie somehow manages to bend instead.</p>

<p>And so, while there’s a fair amount of killing to do — both zombie and human killing, mind you — and lots of huge areas to traverse and gorgeous sets to explore, to me the most compelling aspect of <em>The Last of Us</em> is being able to witness the complex and nuanced relationship that slowly develops between Joel and Ellie. He teaches her to find the strength to do whatever it takes to survive, and she teaches him that there’s more to life than surviving. It’s a long and powerful journey during which both characters change profoundly — and hopefully, so do we.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/26931010882_a98f566555_o.jpg" width="960"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>I won’t get into any more specifics here, because if you haven’t played the game, spoiling it would be cruel. Suffice it to say that Naughty Dog managed to make Joel, Ellie and many of the supporting characters feel surprisingly like real people, with their own problems and ambitions, instead of random stereotypes. This is storytelling at its absolute, unequivocal best.</p>

<p>Of course, when it comes to telling a compelling, believable story, it never hurts to have the best voice actors in the industry, and <em>The Last of Us</em> most definitely does. The amazing cast led by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Troy_Baker">Troy Baker</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ashley_Johnson">Ashley Johnson</a> deliver Oscar-worthy performances across the board, and help make this a truly unforgettable experience.</p>

<p>And last but certainly not least, there’s the wonderful <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_of_Us:_Left_Behind">Left Behind</a></em>, a roughly 3-hour-long DLC that was released about a year after the main game. <em>Left Behind</em> helped bridge a particular gap in the story of the main game, and also gave us a lot more insight into Ellie as a character. It not only further developed the story of <em>The Last of Us</em>, but it also gave us the opportunity to spend a few more precious hours in the company of these characters we’ve come to know so well. In my mind, it is quite possibly the best DLC ever, and it’s only fitting that it would put one heck of a finishing touch on such a remarkable game.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/26991650716_5ddbb76804_o.jpg" width="960"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><em>The Last of Us</em> will always be remembered as an excellent game, perhaps the crowning achievement of the previous generation of consoles. To me, however, it will go down as one of the most compelling and emotional stories I’ve ever experienced, and one of the most polished and inspired pieces of creative work I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at some of the week’s most interesting pieces of writing.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h2>Top Five: The Panic sign, China’s twilight, Apple and podcasting, colorizing vintage photos, and being a whistleblower</h2>

<p>As usual, this week’s selection is strong, and varied. In no particular order:</p>

<h3><a href="https://panic.com/blog/the-panic-sign/">The Panic Sign | Cabel Sasser →</a></h3>

<p>Panic put up a new sign on their headquarters, and it went exactly as you’d expect. Brilliant.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h3><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/06/chinas-twilight-years/480768/">China’s Twilight Years | Howard W. French →</a></h3>

<p>This was an interesting take on the social and economic issues that China is likely to face in the future. Some scary stuff in there, definitely.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<h3><a href="https://marco.org/2016/05/07/apple-role-in-podcasting">Apple’s actual role in podcasting: be careful what you wish for | Marco Arment →</a></h3>

<p>Marco shared his take on the recent rumors that Apple may be getting more closely involved with podcasting in the future. Lots of good points here, although Marco is definitely an interested party, so take them with a grain of salt. So am I, for that matter.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>


<h3><a href="http://petapixel.com/2016/04/07/10-colorized-vintage-photos-famous-landmarks-built/">10 colorized vintage photos of famous landmarks being built | Michael Zhang →</a></h3>

<p>Your weird and oddly mesmerizing photography project of the week.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h3><a href="https://theintercept.com/2016/05/03/edward-snowden-whistleblowing-is-not-just-leaking-its-an-act-of-political-resistance/">Inside the Assassination Complex | Edward Snowden →</a></h3>

<p>Terrific piece by Edward Snowden on what being a whistleblower is really like:</p>

<blockquote><p>One of the challenges of being a whistleblower is living with the knowledge that people continue to sit, just as you did, at those desks, in that unit, throughout the agency, who see what you saw and comply in silence, without resistance or complaint. They learn to live not just with untruths but with unnecessary untruths, dangerous untruths, corrosive untruths. It is a double tragedy: What begins as a survival strategy ends with the compromise of the human being it sought to preserve and the diminishing of the democracy meant to justify the sacrifice.</p></blockquote>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h2>Afterword</h2>

<p>It’s been an interesting week. I’d love to stay and write a proper farewell, but I’m afraid I left Nate hanging from a particularly steep cliff, so I’m just going to head back now and give him a hand.</p>

<p>Have a wonderful Sunday, and thank you for reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/24/morning-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-24T14:03:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/24/morning-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there, welcome to another issue of <em>Morning Coffee</em>.</p>

<h2>Issue #40: I find your lack of honesty disturbing</h2>

<p>Whenever I’m reading a product review, I expect one thing from the reviewer: honesty. I may not agree with every criteria or personal opinion, but a modicum of honesty is a must. It is essential for trust to be established, and let’s not kid ourselves, the reason most reviewers out there are able to make a living is precisely the trust they’ve built over the years with their audiences.</p>

<p>Honesty is also a two-way street. Just as we expect reviewers to give it to us straight, we too must hold up our end of the deal whenever we see some inappropriate behavior. We shouldn’t just blindly accept it and move on. We shouldn’t just give them a pass.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="extra-width">
<img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1717/26587315366_aa12818e47_o.png"/></p>

<p class="photo-credit">We probably shouldn’t use the Darth Vader disciplinary method, though.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Sometimes it’s easy to lose perspective. I’m well aware that reviewers, especially those who have a working relationship with the manufacturers of the products they review, are under tremendous pressure, and that pressure often translates into biases they may not be fully aware of themselves. That’s where we, the readers, come in. Sometimes it’s up to us to keep them honest.</p>

<p>This week I feel like I have to do just that, hence the lengthy commentary on the last linked piece below. There are some strong words there, but I assure you it comes from a good place. It’s not my intention to criticize those people’s motives, or to judge them. I want to make it very clear that I have the utmost respect for their work and trajectory, which is precisely why I expect better from them. We all do.</p>

<p>And now without further ado, let’s get to it.</p>

<h2>Top Five: Moving to Medium, the upcoming tech bubble, the problems with East New York, color management in the Retina era, and reviewers vs the Sony 85mm GM lens</h2>

<p>This week there’s a very strong selection, if I may say so myself. In no particular order:</p>

<h3><a href="https://mariusmasalar.me/on-medium-e40916701b15">On Medium | Marius Masalar →</a></h3>

<p>My friend and co-host Marius finally decided to move his blog over to Medium, and he explained the reasons behind the change in this great piece. If you’re considering moving your existing blog or starting a new one on Medium, this is obligatory reading.</p>

<p>I personally disagree with Marius on the merits of using Medium as a publishing platform vs maintaining your own, but there’s no denying that the recent changes Medium implemented are making this more of a philosophical stance than a practical one. I definitely appreciate the convenience and polish of the Medium platform, and I’d go as far as to say that I’m not totally opposed to testing the waters myself down the road.</p>

<p>For that reason, I’ll be very interested to know what Marius’ opinion of the platform is a few months from now. If you don’t want to miss out on it, I suggest you subscribe.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h3><a href="http://abovethecrowd.com/2016/04/21/on-the-road-to-recap/">On the road to recap | Bill Gurley →</a></h3>

<p>This is a great piece on the many problems with the way VC-funded startups operate these days. It’s admittedly a bit technical, but totally worth your time, especially if you have skin in the game. Via <a href="http://thenewsprint.co/2016/04/23/why-the-unicorn-financing-market-just-became-dangerous-dot-dot-dot-for-all-involved/">Josh Ginter</a>.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<h3><a href="http://digg.com/2016/what-the-hell-happened-in-east-new-york">What the hell happened in East New York? | Kevin Heldman →</a></h3>

<p>Terrific — and terrifying — investigative story by journalist Kevin Heldman. This is a co-production with <a href="http://www.thebigroundtable.com">The Big Roundtable</a>, and it includes a 4-episode podcast you totally should listen to, plus <a href="http://digg.com/2016/broken-what-the-hell-happened-in-east-new-york">a final written piece</a> by Heldman. It’s incredible. Here’s an excerpt from the final piece:</p>

<blockquote><p>For at least the last twenty years East New York has had the highest number of crimes and arrests in New York City — in every single category, for every single year. The crime is astounding: The average annual number of felonies committed in the seventy-six NYC precincts (averaging from 2000 to 2013) is about 1,059. East New York averages 2,622 felonies a year.</p>

<p>In misdemeanors, too, East New York is a leader. In 2013, the 75th Precinct recorded 12,510 misdemeanor arrests, by far the most in the city. (By comparison, in Brooklyn’s Bushwick precinct — gritty but gentrifying — there were 4,808 misdemeanor arrests that year.) Also in East New York in 2013 the police issued 1,890 violations (for lesser offenses like harassment, disorderly conduct, marijuana possession, and trespass) — the highest total in the city and more than double the city average.</p></blockquote>

<p>In every single category, for every single year, for over 20 years straight. Wow.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>


<h3><a href="http://blog.iconfactory.com/2016/04/looking-at-the-future/">Looking at the future | Craig Hockenberry →</a></h3>

<p>The Iconfactory’s Craig Hockenberry published a standout piece on the importance of color management now that more capable high-resolution displays are starting to become the norm:</p>

<blockquote><p>It also wouldn’t surprise me to see these wider color gamuts coming to the cameras in our devices. All iOS devices currently create images in the sRGB gamut, while professional gear can produce images in ProPhoto or AdobeRGB. High dynamic range (HDR) photos need a wider range of color, too.</p>

<p>We’re quickly reaching a point where more pixels don’t make better photos. Think about how much Apple likes to tout the camera and how better saturation improves photos. These new displays are the first step in a process were wider gamuts become a part of the entire iOS photography workflow. The number of places where your code assumes everything is sRGB will be both surprising and painful.</p></blockquote>

<p>As a photographer, I’ve been asking for better color management in iOS <a href="/2015/08/12/ios-and-color-management-how-to-export-jpeg-files-from-lightroom-for-mobile-viewing/">for almost a year</a>, and it looks like I’m finally about to get my wish. As a developer, I may be in for a painful transition, but I’m more than willing to power through the pain in order to reap the benefits.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h3><a href="http://thenewsprint.co/2016/04/23/five-minutes-with-the-sony-85mm-f-slash-1-dot-4-gm/">Five minutes with the Sony 85mm f/1.4 GM | Josh Ginter →</a></h3>

<p>Josh had a chance to test the new Sony lens for a few minutes, and he came away impressed with its quality. However, there were also a few caveats to consider, like its poor AF speed and loud noise. And then there’s the weight aspect:</p>

<blockquote><p>In comparison to the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00WII52ZU/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00WII52ZU&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=thenews02-20&amp;linkId=Y6Z7TLMTTJSCEYAI">Batis 85mm f/1.8</a> however, the GM is far and away the heavier lens. I went into my little hands-on after watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XBgM1lLcSEQ">this video</a> from Jason Lanier. If you skip to the 19:50 mark, you’ll see Jason hand both the Batis and the GM lens to different passersby to see which lens is heavier. Each person in the video says the weight difference is either “imperceptible” or “negligible”. Perhaps each person was amped up and filled with excitement when holding the lenses, causing their muscles not to feel a difference between the two. Regardless, I flat out disagree with each of those people. There is undoubtedly a weight difference, both on the spec sheet and in use. Spec-wise, the GM lens is 28.82 ounces, while the Batis comes in at 16 ounces. That makes the Batis just more than half the weight of the GM. It’s noticeable. Not detrimental, but noticeable.</p></blockquote>

<p>I’m so glad Josh decided to set the record straight here. I’ve long had a problem with reviewers like Lanier or Steve Huff, whose reviews usually contain nothing but praise. The 85mm GM lens is definitely a great, stunning piece of glass, but it’s not perfect, and it is indeed heavy. However, you’d never guess it by reading or watching those reviews.</p>

<p>Take <a href="http://www.stevehuffphoto.com/2016/04/20/the-sony-85-1-4-g-master-lens-review-a-lens-full-of-wow/">Steve Huff’s</a>, for example, which I found to be particularly offending in this regard. He doesn’t even mention the Batis lens in the entire piece, not even in passing. In fact, Steve’s main conclusion in the weight department is that the Sony lens is <em>lighter</em> than the gargantuan <a href="http://amzn.to/1MQz8hR">Canon 85mm f/1.2 L</a> lens. Seriously.</p>

<p>When it comes to product reviews there’s some wiggle room, of course, because certain aspects are subjective. You can prefer one type of bokeh to another, or find the AF speed fast enough for your needs, whereas others may find it lacking. That’s fine, but we as readers expect reviewers to be honest. And while it is technically true that the Sony GM lens is lighter than the Canon, it is profoundly misleading to use that statement to imply that the Sony lens isn’t heavy.</p>

<p>However, while Steve Huff’s claims about the weight may be misleading, Lanier’s are downright false. You just can’t say that there isn’t a noticeable weight difference between the Batis and the GM when one is almost twice as heavy as the other. That’s not misleading, that’s flat out lying to your audience.</p>

<p>And then there’s the matter of the AF noise.</p>

<p>Amidst the usual torrent of enthusiastic praise, Steve Huff states in his review that his copy of the lens wasn’t noisy at all. For reference, the folks over at LensRentals <a href="https://www.lensrentals.com/blog/2016/04/sony-fe-85mm-f1-4-gmaster-emergency-tear-down/">recently</a> inspected 40+ copies of the lens and found that every single one of them exhibited loud AF behavior, to varying degrees. Call me nuts, but I’d take their word over Steve’s any day of the week.</p>

<p>When reviewers downplay, ignore, or flat out lie about the negative aspects of a product, they’re doing a great disservice to their audience. That being said, it is ultimately your responsibility as a reader to take any grandiose claims with a grain of salt and, if it comes to that, cull your product review sources accordingly.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h2>Afterword</h2>

<p>Life is back to normal these days, and even the weather seems to be in better spirits. The cold and rain of the past few weeks are finally giving way to sunshine and more gentle temperatures, and it won’t be long now before coats are once again stored in the closet, hopefully to remain there for good this time.</p>

<p>I really like spring in Spain, and everything it represents. I’ve said so <a href="/2015/03/12/the-arrival-of-spring-street-photography-in-madrid-with-the-olympus-17mm-f-slash-1-dot-8-lens/">before</a>. It’s probably my favorite time of the year: sleeves — and skirts — become shorter, streets light up with people every day, and there’s always something exciting to do. If you’re a street photographer, this presents ample opportunity to capture the magic of life as it’s lived. It’s wonderfully energizing.</p>

<p>It also couldn’t have come at a better time, because I’ve been in a bit of a writing slump lately. Now that the days are longer, though, my spirit will hopefully rise to the occasion. It certainly won’t be for lack of trying.</p>

<p>Thank you for reading, and have a lovely Sunday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morning Coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/16/morning-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-16T17:52:52+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/16/morning-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there, welcome to another issue of <em>Morning Coffee</em>.</p>

<p>Today I want to talk to you about one of my favorite means of transportation: trains.</p>

<h2>Issue #39: The 9:50pm night train to Lisbon</h2>

<p>The allure of long-distance travel is something I appreciate well, but no other form of transportation captures my imagination like trains.</p>

<p>Like most things in life, my love of trains probably comes from every book I’ve read, and every movie I’ve seen. Many of my favorite scenes in fiction happen on trains. Heck, some of my favorite <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murder_on_the_Orient_Express">books</a> occur almost entirely on trains.</p>

<p>In my mind, a train is not just a way to get from point A to point B, but a place for the unexpected to happen. It’s a vehicle — quite literally — for strangers to meet, an excuse to share a few hours of honesty in the middle of everything else. A truce with the real world.</p>

<p>It seems that on some trains, the only baggage people carry is packed away in their suitcases, and once the cars start moving, everybody gets a clean slate. By some sort of alchemy, things that elsewhere would defy reason suddenly become possible. Likely, even. Every day, people who normally wouldn’t give each other the time of day become best friends in the dining car of some night train, as drinks are dispatched and borders left behind.</p>

<p>Europe is a continent that begs to be explored by train, particularly in the summer. Go to sleep in Budapest and wake up in Berlin. Spend a Sunday in Madrid’s La Latina, then sleep your way to Paris for some croissants and café au lait in the morning. Leave Paris at night and wake up in Venice, then continue on to Istanbul. The geography of the old continent lends itself beautifully to such crazy itineraries, but it’s the trains — and the people on them — that make the experience <em>fun</em>.</p>

<p>If you’ve ever watched <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112471/">Before Sunrise</a>, you probably know what I mean. Who hasn’t dreamed of meeting an interesting person on a train? Especially if that person looks like Julie Delpy.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1449/25876804813_5c533ab6bc_o.png" width="960"/></p>

<p class="photo-credit">Yep.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Another one of my favorite train scenes in fiction occurs in <a href="http://amzn.to/268u4eK"><em>The Club Dumas</em></a>, a novel by Spanish writer Arturo Pérez-Reverte. It’s a mystery novel full of adventure, intrigue and really wonderful characters, and probably the book I’ve read most times in my life. We all have a book we enjoy revisiting every now and then. A guilty pleasure, of sorts. <em>The Club Dumas</em> is mine.</p>

<p>In that scene, Lucas Corso, the book’s main character, is on the night train from Madrid to Lisbon, when he “accidentally” runs into Irene Adler, the young female character who remains elusive and mysterious — is she friend or foe, we wonder — for the entire book. The exchange that ensues between them, however brief, perfectly encapsulates what I love about trains. It’s so deliciously meta — they talk about their own love of trains, after all — that it somehow ends up working incredibly well.</p>

<p>Best of all, the Madrid-Lisbon night train is <a href="http://www.renfe.com/EN/viajeros/larga_distancia/productos/trenhotel.html">an actual, real-life train</a> you could hop on today if you felt so inclined. But why would you? Planes are, after all, faster and yes, cheaper, so why would anyone want to spend more money <em>and</em> time to get somewhere?</p>

<p>Well, you know how they say the important part is to enjoy the journey, not the destination? On a train you get to do just that. It’s traveling at a different speed, both physically and mentally. It gives you time to think, and to assimilate the travel experience, to really take it all in.</p>

<p>Whenever I travel by plane, I dread the entire experience, and I can’t wait for it to be over. It’s not that I dislike planes per se, but the way air travel is designed and arranged. It’s a hassle. All the airport security checks, the nonsensical baggage rules, the insane regulations. It may seem faster on paper, but when you account for all the time you waste in the airport both before and after the actual flying part, you end up saving very little time, if any, especially on shorter trips.</p>

<p>By comparison, everything is more relaxed on a train. For starters, train stations are often in the cities themselves, not a few miles away. You can even walk there sometimes, depending on where you’re staying. Also, you can get to the station 15 minutes before your train leaves and still know you have plenty of time to make it. No one will bother asking what size your suitcase is, or how much it weighs. And speaking of baggage, there’s virtually no chance for it to get lost along the way. If you’ve ever had a bag lost by the airline, you know what I mean.</p>

<p>But the best part comes when the train starts moving. None of that “seat in the upright position” crap. You can do as you please for the duration of the trip: cell phones, tablets, laptops, you name it. It’s all cool. You can also walk, and even <em>talk</em> to people. Imagine that. If you get bored, just take a stroll to the dining car, or the bar, and start talking to someone. Anyone. Unlike on planes, I find people actually love talking to strangers on trains, particularly after the first drink. It’s like an unwritten rule; that special alchemy I alluded to earlier, working its magic.</p>

<p>Some of the most interesting conversations in my life I’ve had on trains. I remember talking to a young man who had just enlisted in the army and was heading in for the first time. He was scared, but also emboldened by a sense of duty I found admirable. I also remember meeting a girl on a 3-hour train trip, and exchanging mailing addresses. I assumed that would be that, but much to my surprise, I arrived home one day, weeks later, to find an actual, hand-written letter from her in my mailbox.</p>

<p>These things you would only expect to see in movies, or in cheesy romance novels. And yet, they do happen out there in the real world too, apparently. Trains have a way of getting people to connect like that.</p>

<p>In Porto Alegre, Brazil, there’s <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com.br/Attraction_Review-g303546-d7817542-Reviews-Escadaria_24_de_Maio-Porto_Alegre_State_of_Rio_Grande_do_Sul.html">a beautiful stairway</a> filled with colorful tiles with hand-written messages on them. One of them reads “<em>Não esqueças que os estranhos são amigos que ainda não conheces</em>”. It means “<em>Don’t forget that strangers are just friends you haven’t met yet</em>”.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="extra-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/17090045725_2e5d3b566d_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Next time you find yourself on a train bound to some exotic location, don’t just stay in your seat. Go to the dining car, or the bar, and pay attention to the people around you. It won’t be long before you see a complicit smile, or an inviting gesture. That’s the moment when the magic happens, and all you got to do is smile back.</p>

<p>Enjoy the ride.</p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at some of the week’s most interesting pieces.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<h2>Top Five: The rules of the Internet, the voyeur’s motel, bad art, a week in New York City, and Acros vs fish</h2>

<p>I really like this week’s selection of pieces. I’m doing away with the individual commentary this time, though, so just click on the links and enjoy.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/4/13/11387934/internet-moderator-history-youtube-facebook-reddit-censorship-free-speech">The secret rules of the Internet | Catherine Buni &amp; Soraya Chemaly →</a></h3>

<h3><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/04/11/gay-talese-the-voyeurs-motel">The voyeur’s motel | Gay Talese →</a></h3>

<h3><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2016/04/why-do-we-love-bad-art/476502/">For the love of bad art | Katharine Schwab →</a></h3>

<h3><a href="http://www.mbs-p-b.com/mbs-p-b/2016/4/11/a-week-in-new-york-city-the-ipad-pro-97">A week in New York City and the iPad Pro 9.7 | Mike Bates →</a></h3>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/marius-masalar/photo-essay-b4d90fdb00e6#.yzxwbdahe">Photo essay: Acros underwater | Marius Masalar →</a></h3>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<h2>Afterword</h2>

<p>I’m still riding the tail end of a monstrous cold that’s had me on the ropes for over a week now, but I’m glad to report than I’m feeling much better already. It’s been rough, but all that’s left of it now is an irksome cough that I hope will fade away as quickly as possible.</p>

<p>I’m starting to feel more energized, too, so you can expect more activity around here over the coming days and weeks, too.</p>

<p>Until then, thank you for reading, and have a wonderful Sunday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
