<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-11T19:58:39+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bond By Design: The Art of the James Bond Films]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/27/bond-by-design-the-art-of-the-james-bond-films/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-27T15:20:55+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/27/bond-by-design-the-art-of-the-james-bond-films</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gorgeous upcoming book on the art and design of the EON Productions’ James Bond films:</p>

<blockquote><p>Accessing EON Productions’ vast archive of more than 50 years of art and design, featuring the work of legendary Bond film designers such as Ken Adam, Peter Lamont and Syd Cain. The book provides a unique, spectacular and fascinating insight into the longest-running film franchise of all time. Reveals the craft behind the creation of famous sets, such as Stromberg’s <em>Atlantis</em> base in <em>The Spy Who Loved Me</em> and Drax’s shuttle launch site in <em>Moonraker</em>, as well as technical drawings of Bond’s gadget-laden Aston Martin DB5. Includes two exclusive, full-colour prints of Bond film designs.</p>

<p>Bond By Design also brings the James Bond story right up to date with behind-the-scenes artwork from the newest film, <em>SPECTRE</em>.</p></blockquote>

<p>Bond films have always featured impressive set designs, and this book gives an incredible sneak peek at the creative process behind it all. A must-have for all design-conscious Bond fans out there.</p>

<p>The book will be released in the U.S. on October 6. You can preorder it on Amazon <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1465437908/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1465437908&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=3UI3KDW264PSJKX6">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Bicycle Diaries’, by David Byrne]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/02/bicycle-diaries-by-david-byrne/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-02T21:10:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/02/bicycle-diaries-by-david-byrne</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across this book while doing some research for a bicycle-related photography project I’m dreaming up for the next few months. From the <a href="http://www.davidbyrne.com/archive/art/books/bicycle_diaries/">official website</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Since the early 1980s, David has been riding a bike as his principal means of transportation in New York City. Two decades ago, he discovered folding bikes and started taking them with him when travelling around the world. DB&rsquo;s choice was initially made out of convenience rather than political motivation, but the more cities he saw from his bicycle, the more he became hooked on this mode of transport and the sense of liberation, exhilaration, and connection it provided. This point of view, from his bike seat, became his panoramic window on urban life, a magical way of opening one’s eyes to the inner workings and rhythms of a city’s geography and population.</p></blockquote>

<p>I ordered it on Amazon as soon as I read that. I have a feeling this is going to be a great read. Stay tuned for more detailed commentary; I’ll probably have a <em>lot</em> to say when I’m done reading it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
