<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: traveling | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/traveling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2024-04-01T15:21:06+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Alila Purnama, a pirate ship turned luxury hotel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/20/introducing-alila-purnama-a-pirate-ship-turned-luxury-hotel/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-20T00:35:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/20/introducing-alila-purnama-a-pirate-ship-turned-luxury-hotel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Messy Nessy:</p>

<blockquote><p>I would probably walk the plank if it meant getting myself aboard <em>Alila Purnama.</em> Fortunately, aboard this handcrafted ship, entertainment is less about sword fights and more about mojitos served with a view of the Indian Ocean. Puff Daddy can have his shiny show-off yacht, I want to travel the seas like Francis Drake (or at least like Francis Drake in retirement).</p></blockquote>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t have said it better myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Stamatiou on traveling and photography]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/15/paul-stamatiou-on-traveling-and-photography/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T16:48:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/15/paul-stamatiou-on-traveling-and-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Paul Stamatiou creates some fantastic photo stories of the trips he makes. I first discovered him last year, when I saw the one he made after returning from <a href="http://paulstamatiou.com/photos/japan/two-weeks-in-japan/">Japan</a>. These photo stories are gorgeous, beautifully designed, and the pictures are stunning. In this article — the first of two parts — he does a wonderful job of explaining how he approaches the issue of planning for a trip. If you appreciate travel photography, this is a must-read:</p>

<blockquote><p>A result of moving apartments just about every year since 2004, I&rsquo;ve been pretty good at keeping my posessions to a minimum (camera gear aside, obviously :D). I try to own fewer, higher quality items and often they&rsquo;re only items that augment my travel experiences — portable stuff like good clothes, camera gear or simply last minute airline tickets and car rentals. I&rsquo;d rather spend money on experiences than things that will tie me down to one place.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
