<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: guides | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/guides/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-12T17:06:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best Full Frame lenses for the Sony E-mount system (August 2017)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/01/13/gear-guide-the-best-full-frame-lenses-for-the-sony-e-mount/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-24T20:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/01/13/gear-guide-the-best-full-frame-lenses-for-the-sony-e-mount</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in late 2013, Sony surprised the photography world with the release of the Sony Alpha α7, a remarkable interchangeable lens mirrorless camera with a top-of-the-line, 24-Megapixel Full Frame sensor. Since then, the company has relentlessly built on the α7’s success, releasing a steady stream of camera bodies in both Full Frame and APS-C flavors. In 2017, Sony took things to a whole different level with the release of the Sony Alpha α9, a high-end professional camera aimed straight at Canon and Nikon’s last remanining stronghold in the market: high-speed action and sports photography.</p>

<p>As great as Sony’s camera bodies are, however, the true value of a system is measured by its lenses. No mater how many resources you throw at the problem, it takes time to build a new camera system from scratch. Especially when your stated goal is as ambitious as capturing the high-end of the professional market, where only the very best will do. Luckily, in just a few years, Sony has done a terrific job of covering all of the fundamental focal lengths with excellent offerings and they’re now expanding the lineup with higher-end, more specialized tools like ultra-wide angle and super long telephoto zooms.</p>

<p>It’s been a few years in the making, but with such great cameras and lenses, it looks like the Full Frame E-mount system is finally ready to sit at the grown-ups’ table — and if the rumors are any indication, there’s plenty more to come.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28168210924_e491c940a9_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>In practical terms, the Full Frame E-mount system can be considered a joint venture between Sony and Zeiss. The two companies have a long-standing relationship, and have combined efforts to release more than 30 Full Frame lenses for the E-mount system to date. Best of all, that number doesn’t even include native lenses from 3rd-party manufacturers like Samyang and Voigtlander. And make no mistake, some of these are so good it’s very hard to tell them apart from 1st-party lenses.</p>

<p>With so many new and shiny things to choose from, it can sometimes be tough to make the right choice for your needs. To help make the system a bit more approachable from the outside, in this guide we’ll go over the best pieces of glass for the Full Frame E-mount system.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h2 id="excerpt-point">Table of contents</h2>


<p>Due to the length of this guide, here’s a handy table of contents. Click/tap on each link to go to the corresponding section.</p>

<p><section class="toc">
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#criteria">Criteria for inclusion</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#ultra-wide-angle-primes">Ultra-wide angle primes</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#batis-18">Zeiss Batis 18mm f/2.8</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#wide-angle-primes">Wide angle primes</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#batis-25">Zeiss Batis 25mm f/2</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#standard-primes">Standard primes</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#distagon-35">Sony Zeiss FE 35mm f/1.4 Distagon T*</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#planar-50">Sony Zeiss FE 50mm f/1.4 Planar T*</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#sonnar-55">Sony Zeiss FE 55mm f/1.8 Sonnar T*</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#portrait-primes">Portrait primes</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#batis-85">Zeiss Batis 85mm f/1.8</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#85-gm">Sony FE 85mm f/1.4 G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#100STF-gm">Sony FE 100mm f/2.8 STF G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#batis-135">Zeiss Batis 135mm f/2.8</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#macro-lenses">Macro lenses</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#90-macro">Sony FE 90mm f/2.8 Macro G OSS</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#zoom-lenses">Zoom lenses</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#12-24-f4">Sony FE 12–24mm f/4 G</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#16-35-f4">Sony Zeiss Vario-Tessar T* FE 16–35mm f/4 ZA OSS</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#70-200-f4">Sony FE 70-200mm f/4 G OSS</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#16-35-gm">Sony FE 16-35mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#24-70-gm">Sony FE 24-70mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#70-200-gm">Sony FE 70-200mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#100-400-gm">Sony FE 100-400mm f/4.5-5.6 G-Master</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#manual-focus-lenses">Manual focus lenses</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#zeiss-loxia">The Zeiss Loxia lenses</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#aside-24-70">A brief aside on the Sony Zeiss 24-70mm f/4 lens</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#wishlist-rumors">Wishlist for upcoming lenses and/or existing rumors</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#buying-advice">So what do I buy first?</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#final-words">Final words</a></p></strong>
</section></p>

<p>Got it? Good. Let’s get started.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h2 id="criteria">Criteria for inclusion</h2>


<p>First and foremost, this guide focuses specifically on lenses that can be considered great long-term investments. While there are certainly other lenses compatible with the system that may be more affordable, every single one of the lenses included here can be thought of as best-in-class, and is therefore guaranteed to hold its value and perform flawlessly for many years to come.</p>

<p>Secondly, the guide focuses exclusively on Full Frame lenses. Sony also makes APS-C E-mount lenses and cameras, but those are outside the scope of this article. To avoid confusion, Full Frame E-mount lenses are commonly referred to as FE lenses, and the Full Frame E-mount system as the FE system.</p>

<p>Thirdly, the guide only considers native E-mount lenses. The E-mount system is famous because, thanks to its short flange distance, its cameras can use almost every DSLR lens in existence with adapters. This includes all of Canon’s EF lenses and Sony’s own line of A-mount lenses. Using adapted lenses, however, presents its own set of issues, not the least of which is unreliability. There’s also great variation in lens behavior depending on the particular lens + adapter + camera combination. For these reasons, adapted lenses are also outside the scope of this article.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/23729140464_f3b4b1ee63_o.jpg" width="832"/>
    <p class="caption">Besides native FE lenses, E-mount cameras are compatible with a wide array of DSLR lenses via the use of adapters, but those are outside the scope of this guide.</p>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Finally, the guide is structured in several categories, arranged by focal length and/or primary application. These categories were created based on the current available lens lineup for the system. In the future, additional categories such as fisheye lenses and super telephoto primes may be added, as lenses meeting the corresponding criteria are released. Given the youth of the FE system as a whole and the pace at which new lenses are being announced, the addition of at least some of these categories in the near future appears very likely.</p>

<p>Now, without further ado, let’s take a look at the best Full Frame lenses for the E-mount system.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="ultra-wide-angle-primes">Ultra-wide angle primes</h2>


<p>For the purpose of this guide, ultra-wide angle lenses are those with a focal length wider than 24mm. They are perfect for landscape, travel and architecture photography, but they can also be used to great effect indoors, especially in confined spaces where you still want to give a sense of scale. These lenses allow you to play with perspective in a way that is completely different from how our eyes see the world, which is why they encourage creativity and serve as great tools to learn composition and framing.</p>

<h3 id="batis-18">Zeiss Batis 18mm f/2.8</h3>


<p>The Batis family of lenses was announced by Zeiss in April 2015. They are designed and built by Zeiss, but unlike the lenses they make for Canon, Nikon and others, the Batis lenses are fully native for the E-mount system and include autofocus, weather sealing, an OLED screen that displays the depth of field scale, and a solid metal design. They also pack some serious image quality, as we’ve come to expect from the German manufacturer.</p>

<p>Another interesting and defining aspect of the Batis lenses is that they strike a great combination between top-notch image and build quality, moderately fast apertures, compact size, and light weight. These lenses are clearly designed to take full advantage of mirrorless technology and make for a terrific setup. If you prefer to own smaller lenses in exchange for that last stop of speed but don’t want to compromise on image quality, the Batis family is just the thing for you.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28481846610_a34e6f9d60_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01E8OBQS8&amp;uk=B01E8OBQS8&amp;es=B01E8OBQS8">Zeiss Batis 18mm f/2.8</a></strong> is an ultra-wide angle prime lens. It’s currently the widest lens in the Batis family. At $1,499, it is clearly intended to be a top-notch optical instrument for landscape photographers. Like most of Zeiss’ wide angle primes, the Batis 18mm lens uses a Distagon design, as well as Zeiss’ own T* multi-coating to reduce flare, making it a truly outstanding lens capable of delivering impressive image quality under the most demanding circumstances.</p>

<p>The Zeiss Batis 18mm lens is also noteworthy for having virtually zero coma which, together with its large aperture and impressive corner-to-corner sharpness, makes it a great lens to use for astrophotography.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01E8OBQS8&uk=B01E8OBQS8&es=B01E8OBQS8"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30378704466_b5a7ae32bc_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>




<h2 id="wide-angle-primes">Wide angle primes</h2>


<p>The wide angle category includes lenses with focal lengths between 24 and 35mm. Like ultra-wide angle lenses, they are also well suited for landscape, travel and architecture photography. Many of the benefits of the wider lenses still apply, but these are just long enough to be a bit more versatile. As a result, unless you’re positive you need an ultra-wide angle, lenses in this range are usually a safer choice for general purpose shooting.</p>

<h3 id="batis-25">Zeiss Batis 25mm f/2</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00WIHXBK4&amp;uk=B00WIHXBK4&amp;es=B00WIHXBK4">Zeiss Batis 25mm f/2</a></strong> is substantially longer than the Batis 18mm lens in terms of field of view, while still being pretty wide itself. Like many of its siblings, this lens uses a tried-and-true Distagon design, as well as Zeiss’ own T* multi-coating to reduce flare.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/23728519784_3691b44913_b.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Boasting impressive resolution and contrast right from its maximum aperture, the 25mm Batis is a great all-around performer and will produce excellent images in almost any situation. Like the rest of the Batis family, it is also weather sealed and has an all-metal body and an OLED screen to display depth of field. Its only weak spots are some chromatic aberration wide open and a bit of coma, but these are extremely minor nitpicks for what is overall a superb lens.</p>

<p>At $1,299, the price of the 25mm Batis is in line with premium wide-angle lenses for other systems, but its optical quality certainly appears to be a step above its peers.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00WIHXBK4&uk=B00WIHXBK4&es=B00WIHXBK4"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30298004562_5f6b5cc459_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h2 id="standard-primes">Standard primes</h2>


<p>The barrier between the wide angle and standard focal lengths is somewhat open to interpretation. For some people, wide angle lenses go up to 35mm inclusive, with 50mm being the first true standard focal length. Others, however, think 35mm is already long enough to be considered standard. Although this is purely a personal preference, this guide considers 35mm lenses to be part of the standard range.</p>

<p>Standard lenses are very intuitive to use for most people. These lenses render the world around us in a very familiar way, which makes composing your images a very straightforward affair. Just point, click and in most cases, what you see with your own eyes is what you’re going to get in the picture.</p>

<p>Standard lenses are the perfect entry-point into the photography world for the vast majority of people, but their applications don’t stop there — far from it, actually. A great standard lens is a valuable asset to have in any kit, so let’s take a look at what we have here.</p>

<h3 id="distagon-35">Sony Zeiss FE 35mm f/1.4 Distagon T*</h3>


<p>35mm is arguably the most versatile focal length. From street photography, photo-journalism, environmental portraits and even the occasional landscape shot, most everyday scenes look “just right” through a 35mm lens. And at f/1.4, there’s plenty of control over depth of field — can you say <em>bokeh</em>? — as well as enough speed for low light photography. It will come as no surprise, then, that 35mm f/1.4 lenses are a staple of every Full Frame camera system out there.</p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00U29GNBO&amp;uk=B00UJRSOB6&amp;es=B00UJRSOB6">Sony Zeiss FE 35mm f/1.4 Distagon T*</a></strong> is the first such lens for the Full Frame E-mount system, and what a lens it is. Designed as a collaboration between the two companies, it is manufactured by Sony up to Zeiss specifications. It’s currently the fastest 1st-party lens for the E-mount system, together with the 50mm f/1.4 and 85mm f/1.4 primes. But more on those later.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/23729877683_c3c014ecc8_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>On the technical front, the lens features a Distagon design with 12 elements in 8 groups and 9 rounded aperture blades. These two design treats give it a superior bokeh when compared to similar lenses for other systems. Sharpness is excellent across the frame right from f/1.4, and the lens becomes razor-sharp when stopped down a bit, even in the extreme corners. It also uses Zeiss’ T* coating, and has weather sealing.</p>

<p>Besides its speed, the 35mm Distagon is also noteworthy in that it features a physical switch that changes the clicky-ness of the aperture ring: with just a simple flick you can choose between having nice and reassuring clicks every 1/3rd of a stop, or having a completely click-less aperture ring that is smooth and silent, and therefore better suited for video recording.</p>

<p>Finally, the 35mm Distagon is a rather big and heavy lens, especially for a mirrorless system. And at $1,598, it’s also towards the more expensive end of the FE lens lineup. In fact, it is one of the most expensive 35mm lenses for any camera system. However, its optical performance and excellent build quality more than make up for its high price and considerable heft. If you value lenses as long-term investments, you’ll be absolutely delighted by this one.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00U29GNBO&uk=B00UJRSOB6&es=B00UJRSOB6"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30379702356_febed3861f_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h3 id="planar-50">Sony Zeiss FE 50mm f/1.4 Planar T*</h3>


<p>If 35mm is the most versatile focal length, then 50mm is by far the most popular. Traditionally, 50mm f/1.4 lenses used to provide a significant step-up from your average kit lens in terms of image quality and speed, while still maintaining a relatively small size. Then along came Sigma with their superb <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00JPL7CK6&amp;uk=B00JPL7CK6&amp;es=B00JPL7CK6">50mm f/1.4 Art</a></strong> lens, and Zeiss with their legendary <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00HEBQSGS&amp;uk=B00HEBQSGS&amp;es=B00HEBQSGS">55mm f/1.4 Otus</a></strong> lens, and we suddenly realized that, in order to be optically superior, these lenses would inevitably need to be bigger as well.</p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01IALYGU0&amp;uk=B01IFMCARK&amp;es=B01IFMCARK">Sony Zeiss FE 50mm f/1.4 Planar T*</a></strong> definitely embraces this need. Just like the 35mm Distagon, this lens was designed as a collaboration between the two companies, and manufactured by Sony up to Zeiss specifications.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28166525203_f5eb8a8843_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The lens features a Planar design with 12 elements in 9 groups and 11 rounded aperture blades. It also uses Zeiss’ T* coating, and is rated as dust and moisture resistant by Sony. Just like the 35mm Distagon, the 50mm Planar features a dedicated aperture ring and a switch that changes its clicky-ness. However, this lens also features an additional AF/MF switch, which makes it even easier to switch between the two modes. These high-end hardware controls are making their way into more and more FE lenses, which is very good news for Sony shooters.</p>

<p>At 778g the 50mm Planar is noticeably heavier than the 35mm Distagon, which was already not the lightest lens in the system. And at $1,498, it’s also one of the most expensive 50mm lenses in existence, only surpassed by the likes of Leica and Zeiss’ own Otus line. This is further exacerbated by the fact that there’s another excellent standard lens in the FE system which is very similar in focal length, just a touch slower, and has very similar optical performance. Keep on reading to find out about the stunning 55mm Sonnar lens, and how it compares to this more expensive Planar design.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01IALYGU0&uk=B01IFMCARK&es=B01IFMCARK"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30379701996_95c09daf8c_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h3 id="sonnar-55">Sony Zeiss FE 55mm f/1.8 Sonnar T*</h3>


<p>50mm f/1.8 lenses, commonly known as “nifty-fifties” have been bundled as kit lenses by nearly all manufacturers for decades, and with good reason: they’re very good optically, and they’re <em>very</em> cheap to make. What’s not to love?</p>

<p>Sony, however, took a different approach when planning the first few lenses for their FE system. What if a 50mm lens didn’t have to be cheap? What if you took price out of the equation and simply focused on making the best 50mm lens that you could? What would such a lens look like?</p>

<p>The answer is, it would probably look a lot like the <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00FSB799Q&amp;uk=B00FYRLSK0&amp;es=B00FYRLSK0">Sony Zeiss FE 55mm f/1.8 Sonnar T*</a></strong> lens. Here we have a standard lens with a maximum aperture of “only” f/1.8, and a price tag of just a hair under $1,000. Something doesn’t add up here, because these price points are usually reserved for more exotic, faster lenses with f/1.4 or even f/1.2 maximum apertures.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/24248468412_a69714d6cb_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Luckily, specs aren’t everything. With an all-metal, weather-sealed body, the Sonnar 55mm lens packs professional-grade image quality in a relatively light and compact package. This is one of the sharpest FE lenses to date, being incredibly sharp right from f/1.8. That means it’s fully usable in any situation, and you’ll never need to stop it down just to get acceptable image quality, as you often would with cheaper lenses.</p>

<p>The Sonnar 55mm lens also happens to have one of the most beautiful bokehs of any standard lens out there. Now, bokeh is a notoriously subjective aspect, but the Sonnar 55mm renders very smooth and creamy images with incredibly abrupt transitions between the in-focus and the out-of-focus areas. This helps it achieve the classic Zeiss “pop” and 3D effect that so many photographers crave. And while there may be some onion rings in the bokeh balls due to the use of aspherical elements, these are never pronounced enough to become a problem.</p>

<p>By comparison, the newer 50mm f/1.4 Planar lens gives you an aperture ring, slightly smoother bokeh without onion rings and similar sharpness — although the corners are a bit weaker — but it comes in a package that is over twice as big and heavy, and about $500-600 more expensive. Whether the tradeoff is worth it to you personally, only you can say.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, if all you want is a cheap nifty-fifty, then this lens clearly isn’t for you. But if you want a <em>great</em> standard lens, one that you’ll want to keep and use for decades, the Sonnar 55mm f/1.8 lens definitely fits the bill.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00FSB799Q&uk=B00FYRLSK0&es=B00FYRLSK0"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30118002780_669e156018_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>




<h2 id="portrait-primes">Portrait primes</h2>


<p>If a good standard lens is essential for every camera system, an outstanding portrait lens is often described as a system seller, the lens that makes photographers choose one system over another.</p>

<p>Portrait lenses are longer than standard lenses, and typically have focal lengths in the 80-135mm range. If we go longer than that, we’re really talking about telephoto lenses, which are commonly used for sports, wildlife photography, astrophotography, and the like. These are all situations where there’s a limit to how physically close to your subject you can get and therefore, greater magnification from the lens is needed.</p>

<p>Portrait lenses are often described as short telephoto lenses as well, which can understandably lead to confusion sometimes. Although that’s technically true, each type has clearly different applications, and this guide will consider them as separate categories. As of this guide’s publication date there are no prime lenses longer than 135mm for the FE system, so the distinction between the two groups is a rather moot point anyway. This is likely to become relevant in the future, though.</p>

<h3 id="batis-85">Zeiss Batis 85mm f/1.8</h3>


<p>The Batis 85mm was the first classic portrait lens for the FE system, and it just so happens to be one of the best portrait lenses for <em>any</em> system.</p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00WII52ZU&amp;uk=B00WII52ZU&amp;es=B00WII52ZU">Zeiss Batis 85mm f/1.8</a></strong> lens finds itself in pretty much the same situation as several other lenses featured throughout this guide: at $1,199, it is certainly more expensive than similar lenses for other systems, but its build quality and optical performance are up there with the very best lenses money can buy, making it a worthwhile investment in the end.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/23729877603_92083475c9_b.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>In addition to weather sealing, a metal body and an OLED display, the 85mm Batis also features built-in optical image stabilization technology. This will work on its own to provide 2-3 stops worth of real-world stabilization, or together with the in-body image stabilization technology (IBIS) found in modern Sony cameras to achieve up to 4 stops of stabilization. Not bad, indeed.</p>

<p>At this price point some people will no doubt still be unfazed by the lens’s modest maximum aperture of f/1.8, but if you’ve ever shot with an 85mm Full Frame lens, you know that depth of field at most working distances is already razor-thin at this aperture. If you were to use an even faster lens you’d quickly run into frequent focusing issues, such as only having one eye in focus, or placing focus on the nose and missing the eyes.</p>

<p>Despite what speed evangelists say, if you want great portraits, f/1.8 is more than enough, and the 85mm Batis excels at doing just that. Faster lenses definitely have their place, and can be used to great effect in some situations, but they are by no means a requirement for doing awesome portraiture work.</p>

<p>In exchange for that extra bit of light-gathering ability, the 85mm Batis gives you a whole lot more in terms of image quality. Sharp across the frame wide open, this lens is fully usable right from f/1.8 and its color, contrast and pop are all classic Zeiss-like.</p>

<p>That being said, as of mid-2017 there’s an odd elephant in the room. The $599 Sony FE 85mm f/1.8 lens is just as sharp and comes in at half the price of the Batis. That lens is an excellent bargain, but you do give up image stabilization and the excellent T* coatings that greatly reduce chromatic aberration and improve flare resistance. Besides, those coatings are largely responsible for much of the classic rendering and character of Zeiss lenses, which is a big reason why they are so appreciated by photographers.</p>

<p>This one is admittedly a tough call, but I’m still giving the edge to the Batis despite the significant price gap. The Sony is a fantastic choice if your budget is a bit constrained, but if you want the best compact portrait prime in the FE system, the Batis is the one to get.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00WII52ZU&uk=B00WII52ZU&es=B00WII52ZU"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30118033270_0a62953374_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h3 id="85-gm">Sony FE 85mm f/1.4 G-Master</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01BESR5KO&amp;uk=B01BUAVL7E&amp;es=B01BUAVL7E">Sony FE 85mm f/1.4 G-Master</a></strong> belongs to Sony’s G-Master line of professional lenses. These are designed and manufactured with a 50 lines-per-mm resolution target, which is a significant step up from the previous standard, and should ensure G-Master lenses will be able to resolve the finest details, even when shot on future high-resolution sensors somewhere around the 75 Megapixel mark, or even more.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28166523663_6dd5031360_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The 85mm G-Master lens features 11 elements in 8 groups, which is a considerable amount of glass. As a result, the lens is quite a bit slower to focus than both of the f/1.8 lenses. It’s also been widely reported that AF is a bit noisy with this lens, so videographers may want to test it and see for themselves before buying. AF speed is quick enough for most everyday scenes, but the lens certainly lacks the snappiness of the 85mm Batis.</p>

<p>A new extreme aspherical (XA) element, which is manufactured to extremely small tolerances, allows these lenses to deliver smooth bokeh without the typical onion rings associated with traditional aspherical elements. Plus, its 11 circular aperture blades ensure bokeh highlights remain circular throughout most of the frame, and produce a more neutral bokeh compared to the swirly effect you can see with other lenses like the 85mm Batis. Of course, bokeh is by definition a subjective aspect, and I just so happen to prefer the swirly bokeh of the Batis lens. That being said, if you like your bokeh balls to remain round, this 85mm G-Master lens is definitely the way to go.</p>

<p>Apart from specific image quality enhancements, the 85mm G-Master lens features several high-end hardware controls like a dedicated aperture ring that can be de-clicked for video, an AF/MF switch, and a focus hold button. However, the 85mm G-Master lens is significantly larger than the Batis and at 820g, it comes in at almost twice the weight. Furthermore, it doesn’t have built-in image stabilization, so if you plan on using the lens with an APS-C Sony camera — other than the α6500 — then the Batis may be the better choice.</p>

<p>In terms of raw sharpness, it’s worth pointing out that the Batis is ever-so-slightly sharper from f/1.8 up to f/2.8, but from then on both lenses are basically identical. These two portrait primes are both phenomenal choices, and both deserve a place in this guide.</p>

<p>At $1,798, the 85mm G-Master lens is a no-compromises optical instrument, with all the benefits that entails, but also a few not insignificant tradeoffs. In that sense, the $1,199 Batis does seem like a more balanced approach. At the end of the day, it’s up to you to decide which tradeoff you’ll be most happy with.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01BESR5KO&uk=B01BUAVL7E&es=B01BUAVL7E"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/29783994073_0f09da7c63_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h3 id="100STF-gm">Sony FE 100mm f/2.8 STF G-Master</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B06WRMXVKK&amp;uk=B06VTFT32D&amp;es=B06VTFT32D">Sony FE 100mm f/2.8 STF G-Master</a></strong> is Sony’s first lens for the FE system to feature an apodization element (APD). This element is analogous to a radial neutral density filter that darkens the outer part of the diaphragm, which translates into much smoother edges in the bokeh. Between the APD element and the 11-bladed aperture diaphragm, those seeking ultimate softness in their bokeh highlights will no doubt be impressed by the rendering of this lens.</p>

<p>That being said, keep in mind that the apodization element does affect light transmission, so even though the lens is rated as f/2.8, in reality its T-stop — the actual amount of light that gets through — is T/5.6. That means you lose a full stop of light in exchange for the nicer looking bokeh, so this may not be the best lens to use in low light.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36625152861_55b8ab07d0_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Going beyond the apodization element, Sony hasn’t compromised on any other aspects of image quality with this lens. The 100mm STF G-Master is blisteringly sharp across the frame at all apertures, which gives its images an even more striking contrast between the perfectly detailed in-focus areas and the completely soft out-of-focus bits.</p>

<p>AF is also great, especially when shot on the most recent Sony cameras, and the lens even has a Macro mode that allows it to focus as close as 1.87 ft (0.57 m). And in typical G-Master fashion, the lens sports a plethora of physical controls, all of which make operation a breeze. These include an aperture ring, switchable aperture ring click stops, a Focus Hold button, and an AF/MF focus select switch.</p>

<p>All in all, the 100mm STF G-Master is a very unique lens that enables photographers to shoot in a different way, and it’s one of the most interesting lenses in the FE system.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B06WRMXVKK&uk=B06VTFT32D&es=B06VTFT32D"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36611363802_9689df2037_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h3 id="batis-135">Zeiss Batis 135mm f/2.8</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B06Y2YV1N5&amp;uk=B06Y2YV1N5&amp;es=B06Y2YV1N5">Zeiss Batis 135mm f/2.8</a></strong> belongs to the Zeiss Batis family of lenses and is the first 135mm prime lens to be released for the FE system. Thanks to the increased compression effect, this focal length works very well for medium-distance portraits, events, landscapes and so on. The 135mm prime is definitely a staple in many a photographer’s kit.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36625153091_7ae442d4fa_o.jpg" width="494"/></p>

<p>This particular flavor of the classic 135mm prime lens, however, differs from many others in a few interesting ways.</p>

<p>For one, it’s an f/2.8 lens, as opposed to the more common f/2 or even f/1.8 apertures we’ve seen from other manufacturers. This is admittedly disappointing, but f/2.8 at 135mm should still provide plenty of subject isolation for those craving bokeh. The flip side to that is that, at only 1.35 lb (614 g), this lens is considerably smaller and lighter than most of its main competitors.</p>

<p>Another important difference is that this lens is optically stabilized, a first among 135mm primes. Which means that, if you’re shooting stationary subjects, the 135mm Batis will actually perform better in low light than any of the other 135mm lenses despite its slower aperture.</p>

<p>There seems to be a very clear design ethos when it comes to the Batis family: moderately fast aperture, compact size, light weight, weather sealing, an OLED display, and uncompromising image quality. It’s certainly an interesting strategy that plays to the strengths of mirrorless technology, and so far it’s proven to be a very successful one.</p>

<p>However, the new 135mm deviates from the rest of the Batis family in one very important aspect: price. While the other Batis lenses aren’t cheap, they aren’t ridiculously expensive either. This lens, on the other hand, clocks in at $2,000, which makes it the most expensive prime lens in the FE system by far. That’s a hard pill to swallow for a lens with an f/2.8 maximum aperture, no matter how good it is. Especially when the rest of 135mm lenses out there are also superb in their own right and cost several hundred dollars less.</p>

<p>To make up for this rather high price tag, the 135mm Batis brings a unique element to the table: its Apo Sonnar design. Apochromatic designs effectively eliminate all chromatic aberrations even when shooting wide open without reducing sharpness. Add to that the gorgeous colors, the classic Zeiss rendering, and the virtually nonexistent distortion, and you have an absolute powerhouse of a lens when it comes to image quality and optical performance.</p>

<p>With the Batis family, Zeiss is taking a stand. These lenses are their way of saying that there’s much more to lens design than maximum aperture, and I wholeheartedly agree. None of the Batis lenses are the fastest in their class, but they are without a doubt some of the best pieces of glass money can buy. If you can look past the boring f/2.8 aperture, you’ll realize the 135mm Batis is a phenomenal lens, and yet another worthy addition to the family.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B06Y2YV1N5&uk=B06Y2YV1N5&es=B06Y2YV1N5"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/35386717625_762bf4bf12_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h2 id="macro-lenses">Macro lenses</h2>


<p>Macro lenses serve a very specific purpose, which is why they have their own category. Designed to take pictures of small subjects at very close focusing distances, macro lenses depict subjects at greater than life size.</p>

<p>The difference between close-up photography and macro photography is therefore defined by the <strong>reproduction ratio</strong>, which measures the amount of magnification achieved by the lens on the sensor. In layman’s terms, as explained by <a href="http://nzphoto.tripod.com/3d/520_3dmacro.html">John Wattie</a>: <strong>“If a 24mm vertical object is too tall to fit in the camera viewfinder, you are taking a macro photograph.”</strong> Since Full Frame sensors have a size of 24x36mm, this would mean that the object is being rendered on the sensor at greater than life size. This is a great example to intuitively understand the difference.</p>

<p>With that in mind, <strong>true macro</strong> lenses are those capable of achieving a reproduction ratio of 1:1, meaning that the size of the subject on the sensor is <em>exactly</em> the same as in real life. A 1 cm long ant, for example, would take up exactly 1 cm on the sensor when shot with a 1:1 macro lens. This rate of magnification allows for capturing exceptional levels of detail, and for making subjects appear much greater in pictures than they are in real life.</p>

<h3 id="90-macro">Sony FE 90mm f/2.8 Macro G OSS</h3>


<p>With a maximum magnification rate of 1:1, the Sony 90mm is a true macro lens. As befitting a G-series lens — Sony’s branding for their premium line of lenses — it also has an all-metal body, weather sealing and, for the first time in a Full Frame macro lens, optical image stabilization (called Optical SteadyShot by Sony, or simply OSS) built right into the lens. So whether you own one of the 1st-generation α7-series cameras, or a later model with 5-axis SteadyShot in the body, you’ll be able to get sharp, crisp shots handheld, which is a huge win for macro shooters.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/24061123240_1bf7c9311b_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>On the image quality front, the Sony 90mm macro lens is super sharp right from f/2.8, and color and contrast are also excellent. And since you’ll be focusing at extremely close distances most of the time, you’ll be able to get plenty of bokeh in your shots as well.</p>

<p>Aside from being a great macro lens, the Sony 90mm macro lens does an excellent job of doubling as a portrait lens. While f/2.8 certainly won’t blow your mind, it’s still more than enough to achieve a decent amount of subject separation when shooting conventional portraits, and the impeccable optical quality of the lens ensures excellent results when used this way.</p>

<p>If portraiture is your bread and butter as a photographer, you’ll probably be better off getting one of the 85mm primes instead, but if you want an extremely capable macro lens that can more than hold its own when used as a portrait lens, you can’t go wrong with this one.</p>

<p>In fact, I know some people who actually bought this lens because they were tired of waiting for the Batis 85mm to ship in volume, and once they used it they never looked back. It really is that good. And at $1,098, it’s even a bit cheaper than the Batis.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00U29GNEG&uk=B00ULLSWSU&es=B00ULLSWSU"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30118173230_a385778923_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="zoom-lenses">Zoom lenses</h2>


<p>Traditionally, prime lenses have always offered three distinct advantages over zoom lenses: size and weight, image quality, and speed. Those are very compelling features in a lens, which is why many photographers choose to go prime-only when building their kit. You can indeed cover a reasonably wide focal range with just a few primes, and your entire kit would stay nimble enough to carry anywhere, all while enjoying the benefits of fast glass and excellent image quality.</p>

<p>If that sounds like a great proposition to you, that’s because it is. Unfortunately, there are many situations when shooting with only prime lenses is just not very practical. Event photography, for example, requires the utmost flexibility to recompose and frame your shot from scene to scene, all of which needs to be done in a fraction of a second. In that kind of situation, zoom lenses provide much more flexibility, and will make your life a lot easier.</p>

<p>Zoom lenses are also not what they used to be, and for the most part, that’s a good thing. Image quality has improved dramatically in recent years, to the point where modern zooms actually rival prime lenses in terms of sharpness and overall image quality. If you decide to go with a zoom lens as part of your kit, the only thing you’ll be potentially missing from an equivalent set of primes is speed. However, it’s worth keeping in mind that this improved optical performance usually comes at a cost in terms of both price and size/weight: good, fast zooms are expensive, and they’re <em>big</em>.</p>

<h3 id="12-24-f4">Sony FE 12-24mm f/4 G</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B072J4B6WS&amp;uk=B07236Z9C6&amp;es=B07236Z9C6">Sony FE 12-24mm f/4 G</a></strong> is the widest zoom lens available for the FE system, and one of the best ultra-wide angle zooms available for any system.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36367820190_fc8dcc4345_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Let’s start with the obvious: 12mm on Full Frame is wide. Like, <em>really</em> wide. It’s a great deal wider than 16mm, because at the ultra-wide angle range, every mm has a profound impact on your field of view. That means you’ll be able to get way more into your frame than with a classic 16-35mm lens.</p>

<p>If you want a set of three zooms lenses as your main kit, instead of the classic holy trinity, I’d argue that it’s better to combine this lens with the 24-70mm and 70-200mm G-Master lenses. That way you get significantly more reach at the wide end of the range without any overlap between lenses. I always felt the overlap between 16-35mm and 24-70mm lenses was a bit redundant so if you already own a 24-70mm lens, I’d much rather get this one instead of the 16-35mm to complement it.</p>

<p>As for image quality, this appears to be another fantastic offering from Sony. It’s very sharp at all apertures and all focal lengths across the entire frame, even in the corners. Color and contrast are also up there with what we expect from Sony these days, which is to say they’re both excellent.</p>

<p>The 12-24mm f/4 is a G-series lens, which means it was designed and built entirely by Sony without participation from Zeiss. As such, the lens doesn’t have the excellent T* coatings because those are a proprietary Zeiss formula. Flare resistance may not be perfect with this lens, but it will still be pretty good. The same thing applies to the 70-200mm  f/4 G lens, which I own, and while I have seen some occasional flaring with that lens, I’ve never had a shot ruined because of it. I expect the 12-24mm’s performance to be similar on that front.</p>

<p>Build quality is also very good, and even though this is not a G-Master lens, it’s still among the best-built lenses for the system. And at $1,699, it’s not unreasonably priced for an ultra-wide angle zoom.</p>

<p>One potentially important downside of the 12-24mm f/4 lens is that, since the front element is curved and protrudes from the front, you can’t use screw-on filters with it. That’s a bit of a bummer if you rely on polarizing or neutral-density filters for your landscape work. That being said, this is no different from most other ultra-wide lenses out there, nearly all of which feature similar front-element designs.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, the Sony FE 12-24mm f/4 G is an extremely competent ultra-wide angle lens for your Sony camera, and easily earns a spot on this guide.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B072J4B6WS&uk=B07236Z9C6&es=B07236Z9C6"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/35386717365_9329d1e9b8_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>




<h3 id="16-35-f4">Sony Zeiss Vario-Tessar T* FE 16–35mm f/4 ZA OSS</h3>


<p>This lens gives Sony shooters a window into the ultra-wide to moderate wide angle focal range, with the convenience that an f/4 zoom brings to the table.</p>

<p>Being another collaboration between Sony and Zeiss, the <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00NGTN25C&amp;uk=B00NVA7J1Y&amp;es=B00NVA7J1Y">Sony Zeiss Vario-Tessar T* FE 16–35mm F4 ZA OSS</a></strong> shares many of the features found in some of the other lenses on this guide. That includes an all-metal design, weather sealing, built-in image stabilization (OSS), and the use of Zeiss’ T* multi-coating.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/24061123220_257819e2c2_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Sharpness-wise, the lens renders crisp and detailed images in the center right from f/4 and at all focal lengths. The corners are still perfectly good at f/4, but they don’t reach the same resolution as the center, something that is to be expected in a lens of this nature. The corners sharpen up nicely by f/8, where the lens is super-sharp across the entire frame. As with most zoom lenses, though, resolution dips slightly at both ends of the zoom range. In this particular case, the resolution drop is most noticeable at the 35mm end.</p>

<p>Vignetting is surprisingly low at the wide end, something difficult to achieve in a wide angle lens. Distortion, however, is a bit more pronounced, but is very well corrected by software, either in-camera if you shoot JPEG, or in Adobe Lightroom with the included lens profile. Neither is a problem in real-world usage.</p>

<p>Finally, being a wide angle lens, there isn’t a whole lot of bokeh to speak of, even at f/4, but what little there is does look acceptable, if not spectacular. On the other hand, thanks to its seven aperture blades this lens renders beautiful sunstars when stopped down.</p>

<p>All in all, a very good ultra-wide angle lens for your Sony camera. If you shoot lots of landscapes and want a versatile lens, this one is definitely worth adding to your kit. It currently retails for $1,348.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00NGTN25C&uk=B00NVA7J1Y&es=B00NVA7J1Y"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30415405255_ebb8e8a36a_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>




<h3 id="70-200-f4">Sony FE 70-200mm f/4 G OSS</h3>


<p>Just like the 16-35mm lens at the wide end, this was the first telephoto zoom to be released for the FE system. These days, however, there’s the more expensive f/2.8 version to consider, too.</p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00I8BICEO&amp;uk=B00G9UJW36&amp;es=B00G9UJW36">Sony FE 70-200mm f/4 G OSS</a></strong> is a moderate telephoto zoom. This is a very versatile focal range, which is why 70-200mm lenses are extremely popular among many different kinds of photographers: sports shooters, event photographers, portrait photographers&hellip; you name it. As a result, every Full Frame camera system out there offers one or more lenses in this focal range.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/23728519604_e54e4dcffe_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>While 70-200mm f/2.8 zooms are considered the workhorse lens of the professional event photographer, it’s entirely understandable why Sony chose not to offer such a lens in the early days of the FE system. The reality is that, for most uses, f/4 gets you most of the way there and it does so while keeping the lens reasonably small and light. That’s a perfectly valid tradeoff to make, and I’m sure many people will actually prefer the f/4 version even now that the f/2.8 version has been announced. A massive f/2.8 zoom doesn’t really do you any good if it’s sitting on the shelf at home instead of in your bag.</p>

<p>This 70-200mm lens is a G-series lens, meaning it was designed and manufactured entirely by Sony. The G-series is their premium line of lenses, and is supposed to offer exceptional image and build quality. Judging by the performance of this lens, the G label seems more than appropriate.</p>

<p>The Sony 70-200mm f/4 is built like a small tank: not very heavy considering what it is, but impressively solid. It has an all-metal body with weather sealing, and comes bundled with a metal tripod collar, which is a nice touch. The focus and zoom rings are made of textured rubber and they’re both very smooth and pleasant to use. Furthermore, there are three focus hold buttons on the barrel, something that clearly shows this is a high-end piece of glass.</p>

<p>The lens also has optical image stabilization (OSS) built in, and can provide up to four stops of real-world stabilization when used on modern Sony cameras with IBIS. Other niceties include dedicated switches for focus mode, focus range, OSS, and panning mode. These make using the lens everyday much easier and more convenient.</p>

<p>Image quality-wise, there’s hardly anything to complain about here: sharpness is very good across the frame at all focal lengths, bokeh is excellent, distortion is minimal and vignetting is essentially invisible in real world usage. Flare resistance is good — but not great — and focusing speed and accuracy are top notch. If you don’t like this lens, I can assure you it’s not the lens’s fault.</p>

<p>At $1,498, this isn’t a cheap lens by any means, but it’s worth every penny. The Sony 70-200mm f/4 gets so many things right that improving upon it seems like an exceedingly tall order.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00I8BICEO&uk=B00G9UJW36&es=B00G9UJW36"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30329114611_ee8782be23_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h3 id="16-35-gm">Sony FE 16–35mm f/2.8 G-Master</h3>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B071LHLS11&amp;uk=B071LJZKJL&amp;es=B071LJZKJL">Sony FE 16-35mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></strong>, released in mid-2017, completes the holy trinity of fast zooms for the FE system, together with the 24-70 mm f/2.8 and 70-200 mm f/2.8 G-Master lenses.</p>

<p>Fast, constant aperture zooms are the staple of the working photographer’s kit, and this three-lens combo makes for one hell of a setup for all kinds of professional photographers. If you need f/2.8 in the ultra-wide angle range — think low-light landscape photography — then this lens is as good as it gets within the system.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36367820370_20b7b68e66_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The 16-35mm f/2.8 G-Master lens features the same excellent build quality as the rest of the G-Master family, and also the same impeccable image quality. It’s significantly sharper across the frame at all apertures and focal lengths than the f/4 Zeiss lens, although this improvement does come at the cost of size. It doesn’t come at the cost of weight, though, with the lens weighing a mere 24 oz (680 g). This makes it the lightest G-Master zoom in the lineup, which is a nice surprise.</p>

<p>As for bokeh, there isn’t a whole lot of it to begin with, which is to be expected considering the ultra-wide angle range. Depth of field will be significant in this focal range even at the maximum aperture, but Sony hasn’t used that as an excuse to cut corners here. The 16-35mm f/2.8 G-Master still features the same 11 rounded aperture blades as the other two G-Master zooms, which should help keep bokeh highlights nice and circular across most of the frame, not just in the center.</p>

<p>Compared to the two main alternatives to this lens in the FE system, The 16-35mm G-Master lens isn’t quite as wide as the Sony FE 12-24mm f/4 G lens, but it is faster and, more importantly, it is compatible with filters. This may be more important to you if your workflow relies on them. The G-Master is also a full stop faster than the Sony Zeiss 16-35mm f/4, so if low light performance is a concern, the G-Master will be the one to get. Of course, at $2,198, you’re also paying quite a bit more for the G-Master than for any of the other two, so keep that in mind when making your choice.</p>

<p>If you can stomach the price tag, don’t mind the extra size, and don’t need to go wider than 16mm, then the Sony FE 16-35mm f/2.8 G-Master is the only wide angle lens you will ever need.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B071LHLS11&uk=B071LJZKJL&es=B071LJZKJL"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/35386717835_d6a14b215e_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>




<h3 id="24-70-gm">Sony FE 24-70mm F/2.8 G-Master</h3>


<p>The much-awaited f/2.8 standard zoom for the FE system was announced in February 2016 and released a month later. After the relatively uninspiring performance of the f/4 version, the pressure was on Sony to deliver a best-in-class zoom lens for the system, and they certainly didn’t disappoint.</p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01BESQYJW&amp;uk=B01BUAVMQY&amp;es=B01BUAVMQY">Sony FE 24-70mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></strong> lens belongs to Sony’s top-of-the-line G-Master collection. Just like the other G-Master lenses, this zoom features impressive build quality and optics, and is capable of delivering image quality that rivals that of prime lenses in the same focal range.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28166524533_fabbf9a179_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>With a whopping 18 elements in 13 groups, including one extra aspherical (XA) element, this lens packs some serious punch in the IQ department. It is every bit as sharp as the current gold standard, the Canon EF 24-70mm f/2.8 L II lens, but unlike that one, the Sony has all the advantages of a native lens. Both lenses are missing image stabilization, though, which is one of the extremely few issues I can find with either of them.</p>

<p>At 886g, size and weight are comparable to the Canon zoom lens, with the Sony being slightly bigger and heavier, but not by much. This is unfortunately necessary in order to achieve the fast f/2.8 aperture throughout the entire zoom range. Mirrorless technology helps design smaller cameras and lenses, but it hasn’t managed to circumvent the laws of Physics just yet.</p>

<p>In terms of bokeh, the 24-70mm G-Master lens is certainly not bad, although it can be a bit nervous on occasion, depending on your composition. Mind you, this is still an excellent performance for a zoom lens, but if you want the ultimate bokeh, you’ll be better served by a fast prime lens like the 35mm Distagon or the 50mm Planar instead.</p>

<p>Autofocus performance is also great, with the lens locking onto most subjects quickly and responsively, which makes it ideal for shooting in complex situations like events, weddings, etc. Together with a fast portrait prime like the 85mm Batis or the 85mm G-Master, this zoom would form an impressive two-lens combo.</p>

<p>What’s not so great, as is often the case with Sony lenses, is price. At $2,198, the Sony lens carries a significant premium over the $1,799 Canon for what is essentially the same optical performance and features. This may be because the Sony lens is still relatively new, while the Canon has been out for a while. At the end of the day, however, that’s irrelevant. Now, is it worth paying a $400 premium in order to get a native lens instead of an adapted one? In my mind, absolutely.</p>

<p>After waiting for nearly three years, Sony FE shooters finally have a truly outstanding native standard zoom lens for the system. It’s been a long time coming, but once you get your hands on the 24-70mm f/2.8 G-Master lens, you’ll quickly realize it’s been well worth the wait.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01BESQYJW&uk=B01BUAVMQY&es=B01BUAVMQY"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30118344320_b1eedc1c2a_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h3 id="70-200-gm">Sony FE 70-200mm F/2.8 G-Master</h3>


<p>The premium telephoto zoom is the money-making lens of tons of professional photographers around the world. With such a versatile focal range, fast AF performance and a fast f/2.8 aperture, this lens format excels at everything from event photography, sports, portraits, and even landscape photography.</p>

<p>Simply put, the <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01IDQEQ34&amp;uk=B01G2ZMUDQ&amp;es=B01G2ZMUDQ">Sony FE 70-200mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></strong> lens is a beast. The good news is, it apparently performs like one, too.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/28166524053_6f4c5105a0_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The lens features 23 elements (!) in 18 groups, including one extra aspherical (XA) element. It also has an all-metal body, as well as 11 rounded aperture blades. And in case that wasn’t enough to impress you, it also includes Optical SteadyShot, which is Sony’s terminology for image stabilization.</p>

<p>Hardware-wise, the lens features a similar array of controls as the f/4 lens. These include dedicated switches for focus mode, focus range, OSS, and panning mode, as well as three focus hold buttons. It also comes with a removable tripod collar. All in all, this is an extremely solid lens, and clearly the flagship in the FE system so far.</p>

<p>In terms of image quality, the lens improves upon the f/4 version in every possible way. If the 24-70mm G-Master lens matched the performance of the equivalent Canon L zoom, everything seems to indicate that this holds true for the 70-200mm G-Master lens as well. And that’s saying a lot, because that Canon zoom is as close to a perfect lens as it gets.</p>

<p>At $2,598, the Sony 70-200mm G-Master lens is definitely not cheap, not to mention about $600 more expensive than the equivalent Canon lens. However, if you’re a working photographer who needs this type of zoom, nothing will ever beat the performance of a native lens, and at least now you have an option that is every bit as good as any other lens out there.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01IDQEQ34&uk=B01G2ZMUDQ&es=B01G2ZMUDQ"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/29784769924_19f638c8a7_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h3 id="100-400-gm">Sony FE 100-400mm F/4.5-5.6 G-Master</h3>


<p>Released in mid-2017 alongside the Sony α9 camera, the <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B06ZYJ2MG7&amp;uk=B06ZYJ2MG7&amp;es=B06ZYJ2MG7">Sony FE 100-400mm G-Master</a></strong> lens is the first super telephoto zoom lens for the FE system aimed squarely at professional sports and action photographers.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36367820470_acc73267ef_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>The main credentials of the lens include an extremely long reach and quick and accurate autofocus, all while providing the same excellent image quality that is the hallmark of the G-Master family of lenses. When used on the new α9 camera, this lens will enable photographers to capture all sorts of fast-paced action like never before.</p>

<p>The 100-400mm G-Master lens features 22 elements in 16 groups, including one Super ED and two ED elements, as well as Sony’s Nano AR coating. It also has an all-metal body, 9 rounded aperture blades, and Optical SteadyShot, which is Sony’s terminology for image stabilization.</p>

<p>Physically, the lens features an array of dedicated controls similar to the ones on 70-200mm G-Master lens. These include dedicated switches for focus mode, focus range, OSS, and panning mode. It also has three focus hold buttons and comes with a removable tripod collar. Unlike the 70-200mm G-Master, though, the 100-400mm lens extends physically when zoomed in. This means that, even though at 100mm it is relatively small and compact — for a super telephoto lens — it becomes quite a bit larger as you zoom in all the way to 400mm.</p>

<p>The lens is compatible with Sony’s 1.5x and 2x teleconverters, meaning you can get all the way to 600mm on Full Frame, which is great. However, if you go the teleconverter route, do keep in mind you’ll lose some image quality and light transmission along the way.</p>

<p>Speaking of image quality, the 100-400mm lens packs impressive sharpness across the entire zoom range, being reportedly much sharper than the equivalent Canon lens. Considering this is a much more modern lens design that doesn’t come as a surprise, but it’s still nice to hear. Also, chromatic aberrations should be pretty minimal due to the use of special glass elements, and flare resistance should be excellent thanks to Sony’s Nano AR coatings. These are still not quite up to the same standard as Zeiss’ superb T* coatings, but they’re good enough to make flaring a non-issue in real-world shooting.</p>

<p>At $2,498, the Sony 100-400mm G-Master lens is up there with the 70-200mm G-Master in price, making it one of the most expensive lenses available for the FE system. Unfortunately, if you’re a sports and action photographer, you don’t really have any other options, so this will have to do. On the plus side, the lens does appear to deliver the performance and image quality that its price tag suggests, and should therefore be a sensible investment for those who need it.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B06ZYJ2MG7&uk=B06ZYJ2MG7&es=B06ZYJ2MG7"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/35386717475_aaf883d05f_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="manual-focus-lenses">Manual focus lenses</h2>


<p>Today, most people rely on autofocus for the vast majority of their shooting, so it’s understandable that AF lenses would represent the majority of this list. Still, some people just prefer shooting with true manual-focus glass, which is entirely different and carries some very important benefits of its own.</p>

<p>One such benefit is size. Since manual lenses don’t need to include AF motors, they are considerably more compact than comparable lenses with AF. This means you could potentially build a kit of all-manual lenses with exceptional image quality that would take up only a fraction of space in your bag. For some photographers, this is a huge win. It also comes in very handy when going on a trip and trying to pack light, for example, as it allows you to keep things nice and compact while still taking all of your lenses with you.</p>

<p>Another benefit is reliability. No electric moving parts means fewer elements that can go wrong and require servicing down the road. It also means more peace of mind on important shoots. Manual lenses are essentially lifetime purchases, unless you do something terribly wrong to them. As long as you don’t let dust get inside the lens elements, they should work flawlessly for decades.</p>

<p>A third benefit is build quality. Manual lenses, especially the ones Zeiss makes, are incredibly well built. They have all-metal bodies and focusing mechanisms, and an overall heft and build quality that puts most other lenses to shame. And since they’re built to last, they don’t need to be handled with gloves.</p>

<p>Finally, the main reason to shoot with a manual lens is that it’s just a more reflexive, more enjoyable experience. The act of focusing manually slows down the entire photographic process and forces you to be more proactive in the way you compose your images. This can help you discover new ways to shoot, and make you enjoy grabbing your camera every day.</p>

<p>Even though manual lenses are becoming more and more rare, Zeiss continues to be one of the most important manufacturers, and luckily, their offerings for the E-mount system show what they can still do when they mean business.</p>

<h3 id="zeiss-loxia">The Zeiss Loxia lenses</h3>


<p>As perhaps the best manufacturer of manual lenses — it’s basically a tossup between Zeiss and Leica — the news that Zeiss would release a family of true manual focus lenses for the FE system was received with enthusiasm by many. That family is called <strong>Loxia</strong>, and currently features four different models, with more sure to come in the near future.</p>

<p>All of the Loxia lenses share the same hallmark features: an all-metal design, a dedicated aperture ring, a nice and compact size, and an included metal hood. They also feature a click-less option for the aperture ring that can be enabled by turning a screw on the lens mount. This allows users to choose their preferred behavior for these lenses, and makes them well suited for video recording, too.</p>

<p>Please note that, being full manual lenses, <strong>the Loxia lenses will only work in Aperture Priority or Manual mode</strong>. Aperture always needs to be selected by the user by turning the ring on the lens, which means that <strong>Shutter Speed Priority mode will not work</strong> — or, to be more precise, it will operate just like Manual mode. This is unfortunate, since it makes the lenses poorly suited for situations where you may want to maintain a sufficiently fast shutter speed at all times to avoid motion blur. Luckily, several recent Sony cameras have a menu option to select the minimum shutter speed allowed with Auto-ISO, which goes a long way towards making the Loxia lenses usable in these situations. It’s not a perfect solution, but it works.</p>

<p>Besides that, the Loxia lenses are fully native E-mount lenses with electronic integration at all levels. That means all EXIF data is relayed to the camera, including focal length and aperture.</p>

<p>What’s perhaps more interesting about this electronic integration is the fact that the Loxia lenses can automatically trigger in-camera manual focus aids like focus peaking and magnification by simply turning the focus ring. This is a huge advantage that makes manual focusing a lot easier, and it’s a unique feature that no other manual lens for the system offers.</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at all four Loxia lenses so far:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/29632661974_1f7604df20_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B019OUCQ9Y&amp;uk=B019OUCQ9Y&amp;es=B019OUCQ9Y">Zeiss Loxia 21mm f/2.8 Distagon T*</a></strong> is currently the widest of the Loxia lenses, and at $1,499, it’s also the most expensive. This is arguably the best ultra-wide angle prime lens for the FE system, barely edging out the Batis 18mm in terms of image quality. Both lenses are similarly sharp, but the Loxia controls chromatic aberration just a tad better. On the other hand, it suffers a bit more from coma, so if you’re into astrophotography, the Batis lens may be the better choice. For everything else, the two lenses are nearly indistinguishable in real-world shooting. If you’re struggling to decide, my advice is to choose between the two based on your preferred field of view. Keep in mind that in the ultra-wide range every millimeter counts, so 18mm is actually quite a bit wider than 21mm.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B019OUCQ9Y&uk=B019OUCQ9Y&es=B019OUCQ9Y"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/29784893234_f5c3096bf0_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00Q2QAHOU&amp;uk=B00Q2QAHOU&amp;es=B00Q2QAHOU">Zeiss Loxia 35mm f/2 Biogon T*</a></strong> is a wonderful lens, and in my mind, the one worth getting first out of all the Loxias. The reason for that is that it’s almost as good optically and almost as fast as the 35mm Distagon, but it’s a whole lot smaller. If you can live without AF, this lens will probably be better for you than the Distagon, if only because you won’t be as limited when it comes to using it as a walk-around lens, which is one of the primary purposes of a 35mm lens to begin with. That said, keep in mind that the Loxia uses a Biogon design that will render images with a different character. In general, most people prefer the Distagon’s bokeh, but this is all entirely subjective. The point is, your mileage may vary, so be sure to try one if at all possible before buying, but rest assured, the 35mm Loxia is a <em>gorgeous</em> lens. It currently retails for $1,299.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00Q2QAHOU&uk=B00Q2QAHOU&es=B00Q2QAHOU"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30329324541_f94258644c_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00NW7B68S&amp;uk=B00NW7B68S&amp;es=B00NW7B68S">Zeiss Loxia 50mm f/2 Planar T*</a></strong> is the most affordable of the three at $949, but it’s also the least interesting to me. Part of that has to do with just how ridiculously good the 55mm Sonnar with AF is, of course. Both lenses are similar on paper, but the 55mm has the edge in terms of sharpness, bokeh, and overall usefulness. The Loxia is definitely better built, but again, it’s not as if the Sonnar isn’t well built itself. Price-wise, there’s not much difference between them, either. In this case, unless you need or totally prefer MF, I have to recommend going with the 55mm Sonnar instead of this one. From a future-proof point of view, however, both lenses are excellent investments, which is why the 50mm Loxia makes the list despite not being my personal preference.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00NW7B68S&uk=B00NW7B68S&es=B00NW7B68S"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/29784961004_1fefe8e0cb_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>


<p>The <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01M4O8RFK&amp;uk=B01M4O8RFK&amp;es=B01M4O8RFK">Zeiss Loxia 85mm f/2.4 Sonnar T*</a></strong> is a classic portrait prime and, at $1,399, it’s priced at the halfway point between two of the most popular portrait primes for the system: the 85mm Batis and the 85mm G-Master. Like its brethren, the 85mm Loxia is built like a tank, exceptionally sharp, and essentially distortion-free. Color rendition is typically Zeiss-like: contrasty with plenty of punch and excellent skin tones. Despite its moderate maximum aperture this lens is definitely a worthy addition to the Loxia line, which easily earns it a place on this list.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01M4O8RFK&uk=B01M4O8RFK&es=B01M4O8RFK"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/34577310973_aaf883d05f_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>

<p>At the end of the day, all of the Loxia lenses are excellent, and present a very interesting alternative for those who prefer or require manual focus. A time-tested classic with a modern twist, indeed.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="aside-24-70">A brief aside on the Sony Zeiss 24-70mm f/4 lens</h2>


<p>You might have noticed that there’s a high-profile omission in this guide: the <strong><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00FSB79FU&amp;uk=B00FYRLSIC&amp;es=B00FYRLSIC">Sony Zeiss Vario-Tessar T* FE 24-70mm f/4 ZA OSS</a></strong> lens. That lens has been omitted because I do not consider it to be a good long-term investment, which is the primary factor for inclusion in this guide.</p>

<p>Despite being a pretty good lens overall, the 24-70mm f/4 lens is clearly the weakest of all f/4 zooms currently in the lineup. At 24mm the lens is soft in the corners at all apertures, and it never really gets sharp.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/24061123030_fcf9da2a3e_o.jpg" width="500"/></p>

<p>Of course, there’s also the fact that Sony has now released the much-awaited <strong><a href="#24-70-gm">24-70mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></strong>, which is objectively superior in terms of optical quality, making it a considerably smarter long-term investment.</p>

<p>Again, just to be clear, we’re talking about lenses as long-term investments here. The 24-70mm f/4 lens is still a great lens, and in fact I own it myself. I’m very happy with it, and I’ve gotten many wonderful images out of it. My work does not require a big and heavy standard zoom like the G-Master, and its improvements in optical quality are largely lost on me. That makes the f/4 lens a much better fit for my actual needs, which is what matters most in the end.</p>

<p>If that sounds like you, my advice is to just buy the f/4 lens and enjoy the unmatched convenience it brings. It really is a very good lens, and it will serve you well. Just don’t expect to be able to sell it five years from now without losing some money.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h2 id="wishlist-rumors">Wishlist for upcoming lenses and/or existing rumors</h2>


<p>2017 has already brought a few new pieces of glass for the FE system, including several high-end zoom lenses and budget primes like the new 85mm f/1.8. Having said that, we will probably still see some more FE lenses announced very soon. Sony still has a few gaps to fill in their lineup, and the list of possible candidates includes:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>More G-Master primes</strong>, like the rumored 135mm prime lens. If it turns out to be an f/1.8 lens like the existing version for the A-mount, it’s going to be a system-seller for sure.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>More Batis lenses</strong>. There are still gaps at 35mm and 50mm. Not huge priorities, admittedly, but if you’d like to own a complete set of Batis primes, these are all that’s left.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>More Loxia lenses</strong>. A tilt-shift Loxia lens would have architecture photographers drooling in no time.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>More affordable primes</strong>, like the existing 28mm f/2, 50mm f/1.8, 50mm f/2.8 Macro, and 85mm f/1.8 lenses. A relatively affordable 35mm f/2 or thereabouts is probably the most glaring omission in the system to date.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Faster ultra-wide angle primes</strong> in the vein of the Sigma f/1.4 Art lenses.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Fast super telephoto primes</strong> for sports photography, like the rumored 400mm f/2.8 G-Master.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Native Sigma Art lenses</strong>. You can currently use the existing Canon and Sigma-mount versions with several adapters, including Sigma’s own MC-11, but nothing will ever beat the performance of a native lens. Sigma has publicly admitted to being working on native FE lenses and, according to the rumor sites, we should see a native FE version of their 35mm f/1.4 Art prime before the end of the year. Color me intrigued.</p></li>
</ul>


<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h2 id="buying-advice">So what do I buy first?</h2>


<p>Now that you know what the best FE lenses are, let’s answer the million dollar question: <em>where do I start?</em></p>

<p>If you’re just starting out your FE lens kit and price is not a concern, the <strong><a href="#24-70-gm">24-70mm f/2.8 G-Master</a></strong> zoom lens is probably the smartest investment. It will give you all the more frequently used focal lengths with an optical quality that rivals some of the best primes in the industry. Its only downsides are price, size, and weight, but it will still be smaller, cheaper and lighter than buying and carrying three or four primes to cover the same focal range.</p>

<p>If on the other hand you prefer to start your kit off with a prime lens, I highly recommend going with either the <strong><a href="#batis-25">25mm f/2 Batis</a></strong>, <strong><a href="#sonnar-55">55mm f/1.8 Sonnar</a></strong>, or <strong><a href="#batis-85">85mm f/1.8 Batis</a></strong> as your first lens depending on your shooting style. These lenses represent the best overall value and a great compromise between size, weight, image quality, build quality, and price. You can’t go wrong with any of them. If size and weight don’t bother you much and you don’t mind spending a bit more, the <strong><a href="#distagon-35">35mm f/1.4 Distagon</a></strong> is also an excellent choice as the foundation upon which to build up your kit.</p>

<p>From then on, it’s only a matter of expanding your lens arsenal in the direction you shoot most often. If you can, rent every lens you’re curious about before buying it and take your time to learn where you’re most comfortable. Go with your gut, but be aware that sometimes it takes a while to get used to a new focal length, so be patient and don’t be quick to dismiss any particular lens. And of course, above all, be sure to enjoy the process.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="final-words">Final words</h2>


<p>The whole idea of looking at lenses as long-term investments is born out of necessity. Lenses are expensive pieces of equipment, and very few people can afford to be upgrading them every couple of years.</p>

<p>The Sony FE system is a perfect example of this philosophy. Most of the available lenses for the system are incredible pieces of glass. Every single one of the lenses featured in this guide offers best-in-class performance not only within the context of the FE system, but arguably across any other camera systems as well. Lenses like the 35mm f/1.4 Distagon, the 50mm f/1.4 Planar and the 85mm f/1.4 G-Master — the holy trinity of fast f/1.4 primes for the system — have raised the bar for the industry, and we’re all better off for it.</p>

<p>Also, investing in high-end lenses is a great way to future-proof your kit.</p>

<p>Even now that Sony has released the 50mm f/1.4 Planar lens, the 55mm f/1.8 Sonnar is still an awesome lens. Likewise, the fact that the 85mm f/1.4 G-Master lens now exists doesn’t take anything away from the 85mm f/1.8 Batis. When you invest in quality optics, you are way less vulnerable to gear acquisition syndrome, and you can just be at peace with your equipment.</p>

<p>And finally, when it’s time to sell, ten or fifteen years from now, your lenses will have retained most of their value, allowing you to reclaim a sizable part of your original investment, or to make an eventual transition to a new system a whole lot less painful for your wallet.</p>

<p>Camera bodies come and go, but lenses are long-term investments. Invest in top-of-the-line glass, and never look back.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<p>Thank you for reading this far. If you found this guide helpful, please take a minute to share it on your preferred social network by using the links below. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best mirrorless cameras]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/the-best-mirrorless-cameras/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-21T16:20:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/the-best-mirrorless-cameras</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite some people’s complaints about lack of innovation in the industry, 2016 has been a very good year for photographers. Nearly all manufacturers announced one or more new cameras over the past 12 months, including several new flagship models across different systems, and the current landscape offers many excellent choices for pretty much every type of photographer out there.</p>

<p>Now, it’s true that most of the recent announcements have been more evolutionary than revolutionary, but that’s not necessarily a bad thing. Mirrorless technology has come remarkably far in just a few years, and the rising tide of technology is now making previously high-end features standard across different systems.</p>

<p>Features like touchscreens, IBIS and dual SD card slots are now available in many cameras, and the situation is only going to get better in the future. On top of that, as manufacturers continue to push high-ISO performance and dynamic range, sensor size is becoming less of a critical factor for those looking for solid image quality in a wide variety of scenarios.</p>

<p>With those aspects in mind, I’ve created this guide to help you figure out which camera is the right one to get depending on <em>your</em> particular needs. I’m also giving out the first Editor’s Choice award in the history of <em>Analog Senses</em> to the best camera of 2016, and the one I recommend for most people. To learn which camera took home this most prestigious award, just keep reading!</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="panorama">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30853190463_1406f12393_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><section class="toc"></p>

<h2 id="excerpt-point">Table of contents</h2>


<p>Due to the length of this guide, here’s a table of contents. Click/tap on each link to go to the corresponding section.
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#criteria">Criteria</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#categories">Categories</a></p></strong>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#travel">Best Travel Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#landscape">Best Landscape Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#action-sports">Best Action/Sports Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#wildlife">Best Wildlife Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#walkaround-street">Best Walkaround/Street Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#portrait-studio">Best Portrait/Studio Camera</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p><a class="toc-link" href="#low-light">Best Low Light Camera</a></p>
        </li>
    </ul>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#editors-choice">Editor’s Choice: The Best Camera of 2016</a></p></strong>
    <strong><p><a class="toc-link" href="#final-words">Final Words</a></p></strong>
</section></p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>




<h2 id="criteria">Criteria for inclusion</h2>


<p>This guide takes a look at the camera landscape as of December 2016, but cameras released in prior years are also eligible.</p>

<p>Also, while most modern cameras are also able to pull double duty as surprisingly competent video cameras, this guide focuses only on the photography side of things. The reason for that is that I’m admittedly not a videographer myself, so instead of trying to come up with some reasons to recommend a camera I’ve never even used, I’d rather just be honest and encourage you to find a more informed opinion elsewhere.</p>

<p>As for technology, this guide focuses exclusively on mirrorless cameras. I’m well aware that DSLRs are still very much relevant, but I remain convinced mirrorless is the future of photography and the best purchasing option for the vast majority of people. If you really need a DSLR these days, chances are you already know why, and which one. And if you <em>think</em> you need one but can’t clearly articulate why, then you probably don’t.</p>

<p>Then there’s the matter of what constitutes “the best” in any given category. For me, the best camera is the one that offers the most compelling set of features when it comes to usability, speed, ruggedness, lens selection, and image quality. It’s all about technical excellence here, and pushing the industry forward. More personal factors like character or whether a certain camera inspires the user to shoot more are not accounted for here. That’s what the Editor’s Choice award is for.</p>

<p>Finally, price is a secondary factor as far as this guide is concerned, which means that if you’re on a strict budget, there will probably be cheaper cameras out there that may be better suited to you personally. If you want the best, though, here’s where you’ll find it.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♤</p>




<h2 id="categories">Categories</h2>


<p>Whenever someone asks me “<em>what’s the best camera right now?</em>”, my response is always the same: “<em>depends on what you want to do with it.</em>”</p>

<p>You see, there’s not a camera that is universally the best for every person, or every situation. A camera that excels at being small and light may not be awesome for low light photography, and a camera that is excellent in a studio may not be the ideal travel companion. Photography is usually a game of tradeoffs.</p>

<p>To sort things out a bit, I’ve created several categories in this guide, and selected what I consider to be the best camera for each one. Hopefully this will be more useful than a meaningless blanket recommendation of any one camera.</p>

<p>Let’s get started.</p>

<p><article id="travel" style="margin-top: 100px;">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/645/31291152340_83fd10ba0d_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Travel Camera: The Olympus PEN-F</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>When it comes to traveling, the requirements are simple: a great travel camera needs to provide solid image quality in a small and light package. On top of that, having a great selection of high-quality lenses that still fit in a small bag and don’t weigh a ton is a huge bonus. The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01AW10GM8&amp;uk=B01AURIESW&amp;es=B01AURIESW">Olympus PEN-F</a> checks all of those boxes, and then some.</p>

<p>The PEN-F is inspired by Olympus’ classic PEN F line of half-frame 35mm film cameras<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, which goes back to the early 1960s. In the modern era, Olympus’ digital PEN cameras are somewhat of a hybrid between their SLR-styled, professional-oriented OM-D line and their consumer cameras.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725681806_1c7fcfa65f_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It may look cute and simple, but the PEN-F packs some serious punch in terms of technology and image quality. With a 20-Megapixel Micro Four Thirds (MFT) sensor, 5-axis IBIS and a build quality that rivals the best cameras out there, the PEN-F is certainly no slouch. Only the lack of weather sealing keeps it from being the perfect travel camera in my book.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p>Of course, a big part of the PEN-F’s appeal for travel is the exceptional collection of lenses available for the MFT system. With the new <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01LWC5IMC&amp;uk=B01LYHW9HA&amp;es=B01LYHW9HA">Olympus 12-100mm F4 PRO</a> zoom, for example, you can easily build a fantastic “one camera + one lens” travel kit. Add to that the new <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01LW4IFUI&amp;uk=B01LYTK8H6&amp;es=B01LYTK8H6">Olympus 25mm f/1.2 PRO</a> prime, and you’ve got yourself a two-lens kit capable of magic.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01AW10GM8&uk=B01AURIESW&es=B01AURIESW"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/680/31409202250_4c5b916deb_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Sony RX1R Mark II</h2>

<p>If you don’t want to bother with interchangeable lenses and just want to go as light as possible without compromising on image quality, you’ll be hard-pressed to find a better travel camera than the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B016N39J0O&amp;uk=B017BD5ZA8&amp;es=B017BD5ZA8">Sony RX1R Mark II</a>.</p>

<p>This technological marvel from Sony packs a superb 42-Megapixel Full Frame sensor, a fantastic EVF, and a top-class 35mm F/2 Zeiss lens into an impossibly small and light body. It also happens to have a pretty good AF system and a very handy macro mode for taking close-up shots.</p>

<p>On the minus side, the RX1R II is not weather sealed<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>, and battery life is pretty bad, so you’ll want to make sure you always carry a few spare batteries with you. This is a bit of an annoyance, but it’s not a deal breaker by any means, considering the performance you get from the camera.</p>

<p>The beauty of having a 42-Megapixel sensor in such a tiny camera body is that you have a <em>lot</em> of leeway for cropping your images, meaning you can mimic the field of view of longer lenses without any noticeable loss of image quality. In a way, it’s like having two or three lenses in one. Indeed, the RX1R II gives you two additional crop modes out of the box: 50mm and 70mm. This makes it a lot easier to live with the RX1R II as your only camera when traveling.</p>

<p>Alas, the other big problem with the RX1R II is price: at nearly $4,000, this is not an affordable camera by any means. That being said, if you have the money, this is one you’ll never regret buying.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B016N39J0O&uk=B017BD5ZA8&es=B017BD5ZA8"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5580/30940406044_4df4ba4b3d_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="landscape">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/548/31291151010_6bfb9b53de_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Landscape Camera: The Sony a7R Mark II</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>Landscape photography is often associated with travel, but the requirements are actually slightly different. Size and weight, while important, take a backseat to image quality here. Resolution and dynamic range are essential when it comes to capturing landscape images, and having a comprehensive line of high-quality wide angle lenses to choose from is important as well. Finally, weather sealing is also a much-welcome feature.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00ZDWGFR2&amp;uk=B010THXVNQ&amp;es=B010THXVNQ">Sony a7R Mark II</a> fulfills these requirements with ease. Its 42-Megapixel Full Frame sensor gives you all the detail and dynamic range you could want, and the 5-axis IBIS helps a lot when you want to leave the tripod behind. And since it’s dust and moisture resistant, using it in rough weather is not a problem either.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725687176_035a1e3405_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Best of all, though, are the lenses. The Zeiss <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01E8OBQS8&amp;uk=B01E8OBQS8&amp;es=B01E8OBQS8">18mm F/2.8</a> and <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00WIHXBK4&amp;uk=B00WIHXBK4&amp;es=B00WIHXBK4">25mm F/2</a> Batis lenses are incredibly sharp corner-to-corner and provide all the features of modern glass, as well as the signature Zeiss color and contrast. If you like to focus manually, there’s also the fantastic <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B019OUCQ9Y&amp;uk=B019OUCQ9Y&amp;es=B019OUCQ9Y">Zeiss 21mm f/2.8 Loxia</a>. As for zoom lenses, the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00NGTN25C&amp;uk=B00NVA7J1Y&amp;es=B00NVA7J1Y">Sony Zeiss FE 16-35mm F/4</a> is a solid performer, and I expect a higher-end F/2.8 G-Master version to be announced in 2017.</p>

<p>Overall, the a7R II is a fantastic landscape camera and as such, it more than earns a place in this guide. Fair bit of warning, though: this camera is getting a bit long in the tooth by Sony’s standards, and I expect to see an updated version at some point in early 2017. If you need a great landscape camera today, this is as good as it gets, but if you can wait, my advice would be to hold off on your purchase until we see what 2017 brings.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00ZDWGFR2&uk=B010THXVNQ&es=B010THXVNQ"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/773/31744669206_821821f645_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Fuji X-T2</h2>

<p>If the a7R II isn’t quite within your budget, you’ll be glad to know that the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">Fuji X-T2</a> is also a splendid landscape camera. The resolution bump to 24 Megapixels is much welcome, and the improved dynamic range and high-ISO performance of its X-Trans III sensor make it perfect for capturing even the most intricate details.</p>

<p>On top of that, Fuji has a rich lineup of wide-angle primes and zoom lenses, nearly all of which offer best-in-class image quality. The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B009L1HC2I&amp;uk=B009L1HC2I&amp;es=B009L1HC2I">14mm F/2.8</a> and <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00W6VZLFA&amp;uk=B00W6VZLFA&amp;es=B00W6VZLFA">16mm F/1.4</a> lenses are both awesome, and the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00FPKDPF2&amp;uk=B00HE5MXE0&amp;es=B00HE5MXE0">10-24mm F/4</a> and <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00RSQTDMA&amp;uk=B00SDC5LU6&amp;es=B00SDC5LU6">16-55mm F/2.8</a> are just as good as the primes optically, but offer the added convenience of a zoom.</p>

<p>Best of all, the Fuji X-T2 comes in at roughly half the cost of the a7R II, making it a very attractive proposition indeed.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01I3LNMAM&uk=B01I5LE51A&es=B01I5LE51A"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5591/31409203020_8e07d44bf7_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="action-sports">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/747/31663923555_bb1832b3a7_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Action/Sports Camera: The Fuji X-T2</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>Mirrorless cameras have traditionally lagged behind DSLRs when it comes to continuous autofocus performance, particularly subject tracking. DSLRs have dedicated phase-detection autofocus sensors that make tracking fast and accurate, but this technology was not available in mirrorless cameras until recently. Now, we’re finally starting to see on-sensor phase-detect AF systems that are fast enough to accurately track motion in all but the most demanding scenarios.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup></p>

<p>With that in mind, the best mirrorless camera for action and sports is a very close call between the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">Fuji X-T2</a> and the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01M586Y9R&amp;uk=B01M2WAE29&amp;es=B01M2WAE29">Sony a6500</a>, but ultimately the Fuji comes out on top.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31763114485_37133a905f_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Both cameras have class-leading AF systems, with the Sony offering more AF points, but the Fuji being more customizable. Discerning users will quickly learn to choose the appropriate AF mode for the Fuji in order to get consistently great results, while the Sony always feels like playing the lottery: sometimes it will work flawlessly, and others it will fail miserably. Having the option to configure the AF system’s behavior goes a long way towards getting the results you want, and that’s where the Fuji outperforms the Sony.</p>

<p>The a6500 does have a couple cool features that are missing from the X-T2, though. First up is the much-awaited touchscreen that allows you to select the focus point by simply touching the screen. This is a great feature but unfortunately it seems to be very slow and unresponsive, which makes it inadequate for fast action and sports shooting. Then there’s a Live View mode that nearly eliminates EVF blackout times during bursts and helps you keep your subject in the frame while panning, for example.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the Fuji X-T2 has dual SD-card slots, which is a must-have in a high-end camera these days and a strange omission in the a6500. The Fuji X-T2 also has a joystick to move the AF point around. Many people prefer the immediacy of dedicated physical controls over a touchscreen, so that’s up to you. Of course, the ideal solution would have been to include both, but for some reason Fuji opted not to build a touchscreen into the X-T2.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31763114975_749283f7f9_o.jpg" width="512"/>
    <p class="caption">The lack of high-quality native APS-C lenses for the Sony a6500 means you’re stuck using bigger and more expensive Full Frame lenses with it, which is not ideal.</p>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Clearly both cameras will be able to produce superb results once you figure out their respective quirks, but what ultimately gave the Fuji the win is the lens selection. While Fuji offers a fantastic lineup of fast zoom lenses that are great for action and sports, Sony has been neglecting their APS-C lineup for years. If you want to go with the a6500, your best bet is to use Full Frame lenses with it, which means you’ll be stuck carrying bigger, heavier, and <em>way</em> more expensive lenses that, to add insult to injury, will not even be as sharp on the a6500 as native APS-C lenses in most cases.</p>

<p>Using native APS-C lenses on APS-C bodies is almost always the better choice, and Fuji’s ecosystem is literally years ahead of Sony’s. So while both camera bodies are excellent, at the end of the day the Fuji X-T2 is the better buy.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01I3LNMAM&uk=B01I5LE51A&es=B01I5LE51A"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5591/31409203020_8e07d44bf7_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Olympus OM-D E-M1 Mark II</h2>

<p>Another very good camera to buy for sports shooting is the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01M4MB3DK">Olympus OM-D E-M1 Mark II</a>. This is a speed demon in every way, with a burst rate of up to 15 fps with full AF capabilities, or an insane 60 fps with focus locked to the first frame. Add to that a fantastic EVF and a solid, weather-sealed body and you get a pretty serious camera for the action-minded photographer.</p>

<p>Another strong point the E-M1 II has going for it is the lenses. The Olympus PRO zoom lenses are among the very best the industry has to offer: they’re super durable, weather-sealed, and have longer reach than comparable APS-C or Full Frame lenses. The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00NGSLSK4&amp;uk=B00NED5VHC&amp;es=B00NED5VHC">40-150mm F/2.8 PRO</a> zoom, for example, gets you all the way to a 300mm-equivalent field of view with a fast aperture and in a lens that is still fairly small and light. That’s impressive.</p>

<p>On the minus side, the E-M1 II still lags behind APS-C and Full Frame in terms of image quality. The new 20-Megapixel sensor is a welcome improvement but provides less cropping ability than its bigger-sensor competitors. Dynamic range and high-ISO performance are also a step behind what APS-C and Full Frame offer, a factor that comes into play when shooting in poorly lit arenas or stadiums. At the end of the day, you can’t cheat Physics.</p>

<p>Considering the image quality gap that exists, and considering that the E-M1 II is actually <em>more</em> expensive than either the Fuji X-T2 or the Sony a6500, there’s just not enough upside here to recommend it over the others for action shooting. It’s still a fantastic camera and easily a top pick for other uses such as wildlife photography, but this particular one belongs to the bigger guys.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01M4MB3DK"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/548/31665387001_bf9c48e179_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="wildlife">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/426/31742903415_5f6bc674d8_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Wildlife Camera: The Olympus OM-D E-M1  Mark II</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>A great wildlife camera needs to fulfill a few very important requirements, most of which the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01M4MB3DK">Olympus OM-D E-M1 Mark II</a> checks neatly.</p>

<p>First of all, it needs to be weather sealed. That’s non-negotiable. A lot can happen while you’re out there in the wilderness, waiting to capture the perfect shot of an elusive animal, so your camera needs to be able to handle pretty much anything Mother Nature throws at you. The E-M1 II is easily the toughest mirrorless camera yet, and one of the toughest cameras, period. It is splash-proof, dust-proof and freeze-proof, and so are the Olympus PRO lenses. Whatever the weather, if you’re tough enough to be out there in it, so is the E-M1 II.</p>

<p>Then there’s the matter of reach. It’s not always feasible or advisable to get up close and personal with certain animals, so you’ll want to have an outstanding telephoto lens in your arsenal. The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01950SVHY&amp;uk=B019MYY38O&amp;es=B019MYY38O">Olympus PRO 300mm F/4</a> prime lens gives you a 600mm-equivalent field of view in a lens that’s still small enough to carry anywhere. And with Olympus’ superb IBIS technology and the lens’ own image stabilization working together, you can easily capture tack-sharp photos handheld.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31616230062_86755ef12e_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Another important factor is speed. In wildlife photography you don’t usually get a second chance to capture the perfect shot — after all, wild animals are notoriously bad at following posing directions. This is where having a quick and accurate AF system, fast burst rate, and generous buffer depth matters most, and the E-M1 II is an industry leader in all of those things. With 121 cross-type hybrid AF points, a 15 fps burst rate with full AF capabilities, and a buffer that just keeps going forever, you won’t need a second chance to capture the next iconic National Geographic cover.</p>

<p>Size and weight are also important for wildlife photography. The beauty of the MFT system is that you can carry a complete professional setup in a relatively small bag, something that is even more important when traveling. Carting a massive pile of equipment around the African jungle is no fun, and with the E-M1 II, you won’t have to.</p>

<p>Overall, the E-M1 II is a great wildlife camera, but there’s a catch: many wildlife photographs are taken at night, or in places where light is scarce. In such cases, image stabilization is of no help because you want to maintain a sufficiently fast shutter speed in order to avoid motion blur in your subjects. Your only choice there is to raise your ISO value, and that’s where the E-M1 II struggles. Unfortunately, the smaller size of the MFT sensor means low light performance isn’t as good as APS-C or Full Frame, and there’s no way around it.</p>

<p>If you intend to do a majority of your wildlife shooting in good lighting conditions, the E-M1 II is a solid choice, and the best overall camera in this category. However, if you plan on spending much time shooting in dimly lit places, you may want to take a look at the honorable mention below, or even the <a href="#low-light">Low Light</a> pick further down in this guide.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01M4MB3DK"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/548/31665387001_bf9c48e179_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Fuji X-T2</h2>

<p>The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">Fuji X-T2</a> is almost as good as the E-M1 II in most situations, and even slightly better in some cases.</p>

<p>It’s weather-sealed, but not to the same extent. It has excellent long lenses, like the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B019Y5UBT6&amp;uk=B01ABQKAXY&amp;es=B01ABQKAXY">100-400mm F/4.5-5-6</a>, but they’re slower. It has a very good burst rate — 11 fps mechanical, 14 fps electronic — and a reasonably deep buffer, but both of those are slightly worse than the E-M1 II’s. It’s also a significantly bigger and heavier system once you start adding multiple lenses.</p>

<p>However, thanks to its bigger APS-C sensor, it’s also better than the E-M1 II in low light, which could make a big difference for night-time photographers. Whether that’s enough to tip the scales in its favor is entirely up to you. Of course, other cameras are even better than the X-T2 for low light photography, but if you go with one of those you’ll be stuck carrying even bigger and heavier lenses, and by then you start getting diminishing results. Wildlife photography is all about striking the right balance, and there’s a very good case to be made for the X-T2 here.</p>

<p>In fact, in a world where the E-M1 II didn’t exist, the Fuji X-T2 would have easily taken this category, and I would still recommend it over the Olympus for people who shoot primarily in poor lighting conditions, and those whose needs are not limited to wildlife photography. Basically, the more stuff you do with your camera, the more I would encourage you to pick up the X-T2 instead. The E-M1 II may be better at wildlife photography, but the X-T2 is better at nearly everything else.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01I3LNMAM&uk=B01I5LE51A&es=B01I5LE51A"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5591/31409203020_8e07d44bf7_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="walkaround-street">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5613/31663923475_8e177b4fe6_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Walkaround/Street Camera: The Sony RX1R Mark II</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>Street photography is another one of those areas with very specific requirements. Because the goal is usually to capture candid scenes as they unfold, a good street camera should be as small and inconspicuous as possible. People usually become self-conscious when being pointed at with a huge lens by a random stranger, which can lead to some awkward interactions, or worse. Now, street photography is of course a lot more than that, but you have to start somewhere.</p>

<p>My advice if you’re getting into street photography is to choose one focal length and stick to it. Zoom lenses may be convenient for general use, but in my experience they make you compositionally lazy. A fast prime lens will give you better image quality and the ability to keep your shutter speed fast enough to freeze movement even as light becomes dimmer.</p>

<p>As for which focal length is the best, this is a subject of much debate among photographers. Many people believe that 50mm is the most natural focal length, but I’m a big fan of the 35mm field of view. It is just wide enough to capture a bit more of the environment in your shots, but it’s not so wide that it distorts your subjects. Another interesting aspect of the 35mm focal length is that it will force you to step closer to your subject, which will go a long way towards making you more comfortable with the craft of street photography.</p>

<p>With those requirements in mind, the best camera for street photography right now is the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B016N39J0O&amp;uk=B017BD5ZA8&amp;es=B017BD5ZA8">Sony RX1R Mark II</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31763113745_cb53c96136_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This camera is so small and light that it’s hard to believe it has a 42-Megapixel Full Frame sensor inside. It also has a gorgeous 35mm F/2 Zeiss lens built into the body, which is just about perfect for street photography. And since you’ve got resolution to spare, you can easily crop your images to a 50mm field of view without any noticeable loss of quality.</p>

<p>The RX1R II also has a great retractable EVF and a much-improved AF system, making it a very compelling fixed-lens camera overall. The only downsides are battery life and price: at nearly $4,000, this is clearly not your average consumer camera. Those issues aside, if you’re into the “one camera, one lens” philosophy, it doesn’t get any better than this.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B016N39J0O&uk=B017BD5ZA8&es=B017BD5ZA8"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5580/30940406044_4df4ba4b3d_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Leica Q</h2>

<p>The <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00ZTIHIJY&amp;uk=B00ZTIHIJY&amp;es=B00ZTIHIJY">Leica Q</a> is a very interesting animal, and quite possibly the polar opposite of the Sony RX1R II.</p>

<p>Both are extremely high-end fixed-lens cameras and both are very good, but where the Sony goes for ultimate customizability and technical excellence, the Leica is all about removing cruft and focusing on the essentials.</p>

<p>Build quality-wise, the Leica Q is certainly a step above the Sony. It feels remarkably solid and dense, in a way that is very reassuring. Its EVF is superb, and the software menu is well thought-out. Nobody makes cameras like Leica, so this is hardly a surprise. It’s also a very user-friendly camera, and the shooting experience is about as intuitive as it gets. The Sony, on the other hand, can be a bit overwhelming with a seemingly infinite amount of menu items and customizable options.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725682916_f4eb86bb54_o.jpg" width="350"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Where the Leica simply can’t keep up with the Sony is in raw specs: resolution is only 24 Megapixels, as opposed to 42. This limits the amount of cropping you can do with the Leica, while the Sony is a lot more versatile.</p>

<p>As for focal lengths, the Leica Q has a 28mm F/1.7 lens, so it’s a bit wider than the Sony. The Leica gives you the choice to crop to both 35mm and 50mm fields of view in-camera, but this is where the lack of resolution hurts it. Had Leica built a higher resolution sensor into the Q, it would have been a much closer call between these two. As things stand, though, the Sony takes the win easily, especially considering the Leica Q is actually the more expensive of the two.</p>

<p>Still, if you value simplicity and focus in product design, the Leica Q remains a truly fascinating camera well worth your consideration.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00ZTIHIJY&uk=B00ZTIHIJY&es=B00ZTIHIJY"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/705/31409202830_4e4062c272_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="portrait-studio">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/145/31291151600_b32624eb4b_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Portrait/Studio Camera: The Sony a7R Mark II</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>Portrait and studio photography are all about image quality, so it’s no surprise the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00ZDWGFR2&amp;uk=B010THXVNQ&amp;es=B010THXVNQ">Sony a7R Mark II</a> takes this category.</p>

<p>With a 42-megapixel Full Frame sensor that delivers industry-leading image quality, high-ISO performance and dynamic range, the Sony a7R II is one hell of a camera. It also has some cool advanced AF features like Eye-AF, which is a great asset for portrait photography.</p>

<p>On top of that, Sony’s recent push to release more high-end Full Frame lenses is already paying off, with the E-mount offering a truly comprehensive range of professional-grade glass.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725687176_035a1e3405_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The new G-Master lenses, for example, are all best-in-class and provide all the image quality a photographer could ever need. Now there’s a full trinity of F/1.4 primes, and Sony also has a <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00U29GNEG&amp;uk=B00ULLSWSU&amp;es=B00ULLSWSU">90mm F/2.8 macro</a> lens that is so sharp existing resolution benchmarks can’t measure it accurately. On top of that, Zeiss is also doing wonderful things with the Batis and Loxia lines of lenses, with every new release becoming an instant hit. As far as portrait and studio photographers are concerned, all that’s missing now in the system is a fast 135mm prime lens, and I would be very surprised if such a lens didn’t see the light of day in 2017.</p>

<p>Fair bit of warning, though: the Sony a7R II is getting a bit long in the tooth by Sony’s standards, and I expect to see an updated version at some point in early 2017. If you need a great portrait/studio camera today, this is as good as it gets, but if you can wait, my advice would be to hold off on your purchase until we see what 2017 brings.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00ZDWGFR2&uk=B010THXVNQ&es=B010THXVNQ"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/773/31744669206_821821f645_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Hasselblad X1D</h2>

<p>This one’s a bit of a head-scratcher. The trend in the industry seems to suggest sensor size is becoming less relevant as high-ISO performance and dynamic range get better, and yet Hasselblad just released the first mirrorless Medium Format camera in 2016, and Fujifilm will follow suit in 2017. Go figure.</p>

<p>The likely explanation for that is that high-end studio photography is still all about huge sensors and insane resolutions. Behemoths like the Phase Ones of the world exist for a reason, and it’s nice to see companies innovating in that space with mirrorless technology.</p>

<p>With the X1D, Hasselblad managed to fit a 50-Megapixel Medium Format sensor into a mirrorless body that is considerably smaller than a Full Frame DSLR, which is an impressive technological achievement. Resolution is certainly enough for most applications, although considering the Full Frame Canon 5DS R has had a 50-Megapixel sensor for a while, it isn’t exactly Earth-shattering.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725681166_913c0512a1_o.jpg" width="400"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Now, the <a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1260272-REG/hasselblad_h_3013901_x1d_50c_medium_format_mirrorless.html">Hasselblad X1D</a> is technically a Medium Format camera because it has a sensor that’s larger than Full Frame but the truth is that, at 44 x 33 mm, it’s still very much on the small side of Medium Format. This means the image quality gains over Full Frame, while significant, will not be overwhelming.</p>

<p>As for lens selection, the X1D is compatible with the existing range of Hasselblad lenses for the H System, albeit with the use of an adapter. As of 2016, the native lens selection is limited to only three lenses, which makes the Hasselblad X1D a bit of a mystery and keeps it from seriously challenging the a7R II as this category’s winner. Things may change in 2017 if Hasselblad releases more lenses for the X1D or if the upcoming Fujifilm GFX takes the world by storm but for now, it is what it is.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="https://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1260272-REG/hasselblad_h_3013901_x1d_50c_medium_format_mirrorless.html"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/455/30940406594_491fc41f18_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article>
<article id="low-light" style="margin-bottom:50px;">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/67/31663923925_9d6a6c15ca_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Best Low Light Camera: The Sony a7S Mark II</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>When it comes to low light performance, there are three critical factors at play: sensor size, ISO performance, and image stabilization.</p>

<p>Sensor size is important because the larger the sensor, the more total light is captured by the camera. Pictures are basically light paintings so the more light you get, the cleaner your images will be. Bottom point: for the purposes of low light shooting, a larger sensor equals better.</p>

<p>ISO performance refers to the amount of detail, noise and color fidelity captured in an image at any given ISO setting. As sensor technology gets better, performance at high ISO values also improves. This in turn raises the maximum ISO value at which we can shoot while still getting usable images, allowing us to shoot in darker environments, or use faster shutter speeds to freeze movement, or narrower apertures to increase depth of field, even in dim conditions.</p>

<p>Finally, if you shoot handheld, image stabilization is also important because it allows you to use a slower shutter speed and/or a narrower aperture with a low ISO value while still getting sharp images. Image stabilization can’t compensate for moving subjects, though, it only compensates for camera shake.</p>

<p>With that in mind, the best camera for low light shooting is the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B0158SRJVQ&amp;uk=B015XT4TGS&amp;es=B015XT4TGS">Sony a7S Mark II</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725686226_85a1fcdaa6_o.jpg" width="450"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>While most modern cameras have a maximum usable ISO of 6,400 or thereabouts, you can still get perfectly usable images with the Sony a7S II at ISO 25,600 or even higher, depending on your tolerance for noise. This sort of high-ISO performance is just ridiculous, and miles ahead every other camera out there.</p>

<p>Between that, the 12.9-Megapixel Full Frame sensor and the 5-axis IBIS, the Sony a7S II can actually see in the dark, and is the uncontested winner in this category.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B0158SRJVQ&uk=B015XT4TGS&es=B015XT4TGS"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/329/31409201810_d5d377f4f8_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Sony a7S (original)</h2>

<p>The original <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00JIWXTXG&amp;uk=B00KPV1RW4&amp;es=B00KPV1RW4">Sony a7S</a>, announced in April 2014, was the first camera to offer such an impressive high-ISO performance, and continues to be a very good alternative today. All that’s missing here when compared to the newer a7S II is the 5-axis IBIS and the slightly more advanced AF system. That may be important to some people, but if you shoot primarily with a tripod — think astrophotography, for example — then it’s a non-issue.</p>

<p>If that’s your case, you’d be much better served by going with the original a7S instead, and putting the rest of the money towards a nice lens.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B00JIWXTXG&uk=B00KPV1RW4&es=B00KPV1RW4"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/373/30972164183_ea0983be81_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article></p>

<p class="card-separator">♧</p>


<p>There you have it. Throughout this guide I’ve laid out the best cameras the industry has to offer in each respective category. Hopefully you found something useful here.</p>

<p>However, while technology is certainly important, photography is first and foremost a creative discipline, and a craft. It’s nice to have the biggest sensor or the sharpest lenses, but when it comes to making a smart purchasing decision there are other factors that should be considered as well.</p>

<p>These factors can’t be measured by charts, or quantified by specs. I’m talking about character, and user experience. I’m talking about design. I’m talking about how a camera makes you feel, and whether shooting with it is an enjoyable process rather than a chore.</p>

<p>In order to account for these factors, I’ve decided to give out the first Editor’s Choice award in the history of <em>Analog Senses</em> to the best camera of 2016. And so, while there are cameras with arguably better specs out there, or cameras that are more expensive, the one I recommend for most people is the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">Fuji X-T2</a>.</p>

<p><article id="editors-choice" style="margin-bottom: 50px;">
    <div class="heading-icon">
        <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
            <img class="icon" src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/59/31548056401_94a5ce3156_o.png"/>
        </figure></notextile></div>
        <h1>Editor’s Choice Award 2016: The Fuji X-T2</h1>
    </div></p>

<p>As you’ve seen above, there’s no shortage of excellent cameras in the industry these days. However, for all that technical excellence, character is becoming increasingly harder to find.</p>

<p>Luckily, there are still manufacturers like Fuji that remain committed to a philosophy that doesn’t sacrifice character in favor of specs. At the end of the day, what we instinctively perceive as character isn’t limited to the way a camera looks or feels; it is something a lot more profound. To quote Steve Jobs, “<em>design is not just what it looks like and feels like. Design is how it works</em>.”</p>

<p>Fuji cameras are different, and the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">X-T2</a> is no exception. You can tell by details such as the perfect placement of dials and buttons, and the dedicated aperture rings on most lenses. The Fuji X-Series system is designed by photographers, for photographers, and it shows.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31763114485_37133a905f_o.jpg" width="512"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Using the X-T2 is a two-hands operation, as it should be. Once you get used to this workflow, it’s easy to notice the benefits: every essential parameter — including aperture, shutter speed, and ISO — is available right at your fingertips via dedicated hardware controls. Simple. Of course, you can still set everything to Auto and fire away without a care in the world, but if you’ve made it this far into this guide, something tells me you care a bit more about photography.</p>

<p>I’m admittedly a Sony shooter myself, but every day I’m tempted by the Fuji system, and the X-T2 in particular. In my time testing it, I quickly noticed that having all those dedicated controls made me want to shoot in manual mode all the time. If I were to own this camera I would definitely try and get used to that, not only because it would make me a better photographer by informing my understanding of light metering and the exposure triangle, but because it is just plain <em>fun</em>.</p>

<p>Then there’s the matter of Fuji’s gorgeous film emulations, including the new Acros. These manage to replicate the feel of some of Fuji’s iconic film stocks with a modern twist, and the results are fantastic. It’s easy to overlook this feature as gimmicky, but being able to share images that look finished straight out of camera is a huge benefit in many situations.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/30234487201_b82cded0e3_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>That being said, the Fuji X-T2 is not only about character; it is a technological marvel in its own right. It has a class-leading 24-Megapixel X-Trans III sensor and a state-of-the-art AF system. It also has a rugged, weather-sealed body, dual SD-card slots, and a top-shelf EVF. In terms of specs and features, it is very much a modern camera, but it’s also so much more than that.</p>

<p>The Fuji X-T2 is unique because it manages to marry the technical chops needed to succeed in the cutthroat market of 2016 with the intangible character Fuji has always instilled into their cameras. That’s no small feat, and it’s what makes the X-T2 stand out from the pack.</p>

<p>If you appreciate good design and love the craft of photography, you simply can’t buy a better camera these days.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01I3LNMAM&uk=B01I5LE51A&es=B01I5LE51A"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5591/31409203020_8e07d44bf7_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<h2>Honorable mention: the Fuji X-Pro 2</h2>

<p>Fuji’s X-Pro series of cameras is arguably even more special than the X-T series. Where the X-T2 manages to strike a near perfect balance between specs and character, the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01A8DUR74&amp;uk=B01AP7S4GE&amp;es=B01AP7S4GE">X-Pro 2</a> deliberately skews that balance in favor of character. This is a camera that won’t leave anyone indifferent.</p>

<p>The X-Pro 2 shares many of the features of the X-T2, to the point where both cameras are considered co-flagships of the X-Series system by Fuji. Both have the same 24-Megapixel X-Trans III sensor, weather sealing, dual SD-card slots, dedicated controls, image processor, film emulations, and more. The main differences between the two cameras are the overall aesthetic, the AF modes, the rear LCD screen, and the viewfinder.</p>

<p>The X-T2 goes for a standard SLR-like look, including a viewfinder hump. It also has an electronic viewfinder and a tilting LCD screen, like most mirrorless cameras these days. The X-Pro 2, on the other hand, is rangefinder-style camera and has a fixed LCD screen and a hybrid viewfinder — optical and electronic — that makes shooting with it an entirely different experience.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure>
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31725683546_5dc6b9a085_o.jpg" width="512"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>People who love classic rangefinder cameras will fall head over heels for the X-Pro 2. It really is a super fun camera to shoot with. If you’re coming from an SLR-like camera, shooting with a rangefinder takes some getting used to, but it’s actually very simple. The main advantage is that you’re always seeing the entire scene, not just the part of it that is captured by the field of view of your lens. This allows you to anticipate subject movement and compose your shots a lot more easily.</p>

<p>Another neat feature in the X-Pro 2 is that you can instantly switch from the optical viewfinder to the electronic one by flipping a lever on the front of the camera, meaning you’ll always be able to use the one that works best for any given situation. Smart.</p>

<p>The only real downsides of the X-Pro 2 when compared to its more mainstream sibling are the lack of a tilting LCD screen and the slightly less advanced AF system. The X-Pro 2 has a very competent AF system, but it lacks the customizable modes for subject tracking of the X-T2. Now, since both cameras share the same image processor, I fully expect this feature to be added to the X-Pro 2 in a future firmware update but for now, it is what it is.</p>

<p>Given the relatively minor technological differences between the X-Pro 2 and the X-T2, choosing between them is mostly a matter of personal preference. Go with the X-T2 if you like SLR-style cameras, you shoot fast-moving subjects, or you want to have a tilting LCD screen. Also, go with the X-T2 if you’re hesitating between the two; it’s just a safer option that will most likely please everybody.</p>

<p>That being said, if your shooting style is more deliberate, and you don’t mind putting in the time and effort it takes to master the rangefinder, there’s plenty to love about the X-Pro 2. It’s just a more interesting camera, and one that may make you fall in love with the craft of photography all over again.</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01A8DUR74&uk=B01AP7S4GE&es=B01AP7S4GE"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/695/31744670266_a2287401ca_o.png"/></a>
</section></p>

<p></article></p>

<p class="card-separator">♡</p>




<h2 id="final-words">Final Words</h2>


<p>2016 has been a great year for mirrorless photography. We’re now at a point where every system offers one or more cameras that can stand their ground against comparably-specced DSLRs, and in some cases handily outperform them. With every new release, the list of reasons to buy a DSLR keeps getting shorter.</p>

<p>Image quality has never been this good, and high-ISO performance keeps improving year after year. Focusing is finally at a point where subject tracking no longer sucks, and features like dual SD-card slots, IBIS and touchscreens are making their way into more and more cameras. Some manufacturers are even rolling out professional customer service networks across the world. This is what steady evolutionary progress feels like, and it’s great.</p>

<p>Sure, there are still people who need a DSLR today, and many who just prefer them. For all the benefits of mirrorless technology, DSLRs are not going anywhere. They won’t become obsolete, and they won’t be phased out anytime soon. That’s not the point.</p>

<p>The point is that you no longer <em>need</em> one to take wonderful images, even if you’re a professional. The myth that mirrorless cameras are for amateurs is finally losing steam. Good riddance.</p>

<p>There’s never been a better time to buy a camera, and if you’re willing to take a leap of faith and leave the mirror behind for good, I promise you’ll never look back.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<p>Thank you for reading this far.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" rel="footnote">6</a></sup> These guides take a long time to put together, so if you found it helpful, please take a minute to share it on your preferred social media platform. Thanks!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Half-frame film cameras used an 18×24 mm vertical (portrait) format, producing twice the pictures on a roll of 135 film as the regular 36×24 mm format.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>If you need weather sealing, the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00S6DBMOQ&amp;uk=B00SMPL4WI&amp;es=B00SMPL4WI">Olympus OM-D E-M5 Mark II</a> is a good choice, but it has a lower-resolution 16-Megapixel sensor. Of course, the flagship <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01M4MB3DK">OM-D E-M1 Mark II</a> is also weather sealed and packs a similar 20-Megapixel sensor as the PEN-F, but it is significantly bigger and heavier, and it costs twice as much.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Unfortunately, I couldn’t find any similar high-quality, fixed-lens cameras that are weather sealed. Both the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00ZTIHIJY&amp;uk=B00ZTIHIJY&amp;es=B00ZTIHIJY">Leica Q</a> and the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00NF6ZHNG&amp;uk=B00NEBL0XS&amp;es=B00NEBL0XS">Fuji X100T</a> lack weather sealing as well.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>To be fair, even the best mirrorless cameras are still a step behind what the best DSLRs can do when it comes to subject tracking, but now they are definitely usable, and the gap is closing fast.<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Unless you’ve already bought into the Sony Full Frame E-mount system or plan to do so in the future. If you already own an a7-series camera and one or more lenses, it may make more sense to go with the a6500 as a dedicated action/sports body and use the same lenses with both cameras.<a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Icons used throughout the guide:  Airplane by <a href="http://www.flaticon.com/authors/pixel-buddha">Pixel Buddha</a>; Picture, Podium, Stand, and Happy by <a href="http://www.flaticon.com/authors/madebyoliver">Madebyoliver</a>; Tiger and Moon by <a href="http://www.flaticon.com/authors/freepik">Freepik</a>; Gold medal by <a href="http://www.flaticon.com/authors/roundicons">Roundicons</a>. All from <a href="http://www.flaticon.com/">www.flaticon.com</a>.<a href="#fnref:6" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading my Early-2008, 24-inch iMac with an SSD]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/05/21/upgrading-my-early-2008-24-imac-to-an-ssd/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-11T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/05/21/upgrading-my-early-2008-24-imac-to-an-ssd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>UPDATE, July 16, 2016:</strong> This article was originally published on May 21, 2014. Since then, it’s consistently been the most popular piece on this site almost every month. The original text is still valid, but SSD recommendations are now outdated.</em></p>

<p><em>As of July 2016, the consumer-grade SSD I recommend is the <a href="http://amzn.to/2aiLWwq">Samsung 850 EVO</a>. If you want something fancier, both the <a href="http://amzn.to/2aiMx11">Samsung 850 Pro</a> and the <a href="http://amzn.to/29Krgv8">SanDisk Extreme Pro</a> are excellent, as well. That said, keep in mind that in this case the bottleneck will be your iMac’s 3 Gb/s SATA 2 interface, so any of these drives will have nearly identical performance. Prices vary slightly on Amazon but you can’t go wrong with any of these, so my advice would be to get whichever is cheaper at the moment.</em></p>

<p><em>Even though it will not be supported by the newly-announced macOS Sierra, my Early-2008 iMac is still my primary Mac. It’s a terrific machine and I have no plans to replace it anytime soon. The rest of the article has been preserved in its original form for historical accuracy.</em></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/14189051376_3e98590f1a_b.jpg" title="Set everything up in a comfortable environment and get to work!"/>
    <p class="caption">Set everything up in a comfortable environment and get to work!</p>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>A couple of weekends ago I finally had time for a project I’d been wanting to do for months: upgrading my iMac’s internal hard drive to an SSD. This is an account of how the upgrade went, the difficulties I found, and whether I recommend anyone do the same (Spoiler alert: yes, very much so). Before I begin, please note that this article is not a how-to manual, and as such it should never replace the excellent step-by-step guides available <a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Guide/iMac+Intel+24-Inch+EMC+2134+and+2211+Hard+Drive+Replacement/8968">on iFixit</a> and elsewhere on the Internet. I followed the iFixit guide throughout the entire process and if you’re thinking of upgrading your own iMac, I suggest you do the same. Also, the Amazon links in this article are affiliate links, so if you buy anything through one of those links, I’ll get a small kickback from Amazon. Thanks!</p>

<h2>Why</h2>

<p>Ask around the Internet and most people will tell you that the single most important upgrade you can make to an old computer is an SSD. It’s absolutely true, followed closely by adding more RAM. In old computers, the most frequent performance bottlenecks in day-to-day use are caused by having to wait for the hard drive. It normally takes the drive a few milliseconds to get ready to read/write the desired data and, worse than that, those milliseconds add up quickly as the drive gets filled, because it has to look for different pieces of data that are scattered across the drive’s surface, and that takes time. Moreover, if you’re short on RAM, the system will try to create Virtual Memory by writing data to disk instead of RAM, which takes significantly longer. What the combination of these two situations amounts to is simple: you start seeing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spinning_pinwheel">more beach balls</a>, your entire computer appears to be frozen for a few seconds at a time, and the general “snappiness” of the system is gone.</p>

<p>An SSD, on the other hand, has <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotational_latency#Rotational_latency">no moving parts to spin</a>, and it doesn’t have to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hard_disk_drive_performance_characteristics#SEEKTIME">go looking for pieces of data</a> anywhere, so all those waiting times are cut down to effectively zero. That’s the main reason people swear by their SSD’s: if you put a modern SSD inside an old computer, it’s like rolling the clock back a few years. In fact, your machine can perform better than it ever did, even when it was new.</p>

<h2>How</h2>

<p>My iMac is a 24-inch model from early 2008. It was the top-of-the-line configuration then, with a Core 2 Duo processor clocked at 3.06 GHz. About two years ago I upgraded it with the highest amount of RAM it can get: 6 GB. Apple officially supports only up to 4 GB, but <a href="http://eshop.macsales.com/memory/maxram">it’s been tested</a> many times on the Internet that these iMacs actually support up to 6 GB, so I decided to go for it and had no problems whatsoever. Then, about a year ago, my graphics card died. I thought long and hard about whether it was time to replace my then 5-year-old iMac, but I decided to take it to the Genius Bar and see how much it would cost to repair it instead. It turned out to be a relatively inexpensive repair, about $180, so I figured it was worth it to keep my iMac around a bit longer. I like to use my computers for as long as possible and this one had served me well, so I saw no compelling reason to spend upwards of $1000 to replace it.</p>

<p>Now it’s a year later and the iMac continues to perform admirably for a machine of its age. However, I was starting to feel a little uneasy about the internal hard drive, a 500 GB, 7200 RPM model from Seagate. Commercial-grade spinning hard drives have an average lifespan of about 5 years, so mine was probably nearing the end of its life. I do keep up-to-date backups so I was prepared for an eventual failure, but modern consumer SSD’s are finally affordable enough that upgrading the internal drive started to make a lot of sense. I’d rather anticipate the drive’s failure and deal with the upgrade process on my own terms.</p>

<p>As for what SSD to get, when you’re coming from a spinning hard drive this is probably not a critical issue, since there are massive performance gains to be made by switching to pretty much any modern SSD. Still, I’m a nerd, so I like to do my research and make an informed purchase whenever possible.</p>

<p><em><strong>WARNING:</strong> These SSD recommendations were originally published in May 2014 and are now outdated. Check the update notice above for the current recommended models.</em></p>

<p>Fortunately, the general consensus seems to be that right now, the best consumer SSD in terms of performance vs. price is <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/search/ref=as_li_qf_sp_sr_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;index=aps&amp;keywords=samsung%20840%20evo&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=T7JJVPYM6KUK7WC3">the Samsung 840 EVO</a>, so I decided to go with that one. The size question is trickier, though: prices scale almost linearly with capacity, so you don’t save much money by going bigger. On the other hand, it’s been suggested that the bigger flavors of the 840 EVO (500 GB, 750 GB and 1TB) have better performance and more durability. While that may well be the case, the smaller drives (120 GB and 250 GB) are already plenty fast and durable, so this is not a decisive point either.</p>

<p>I was initially leaning towards <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00E3W19MO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=211189&amp;creative=373489&amp;creativeASIN=B00E3W19MO&amp;link_code=as3&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=2X75ROL22WE6DWQK">the 500 GB model</a>, which retails on Amazon in Spain for 216€ (about $295). It would match my internal drive’s size, so I would not give up any space in the transition, which seemed like the best way to go. However, I never really used all the space in my internal drive. Most of my storage needs are for my media collection (music, TV shows, movies and photos), which I keep on an external drive anyway. I typically only use about 100 GB of internal storage, which include the OS, my applications, documents, my Dropbox folder and little more, so what’s the point of buying a large SSD if I’m not even going to use half of its capacity? For reference, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00E3W1726/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=211189&amp;creative=373489&amp;creativeASIN=B00E3W1726&amp;link_code=as3&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=P6V3VKDN3NZO3FO6">the 250 GB version</a> retails for 120€ (about $164). After careful consideration, I decided to buy two 250 GB drives instead of the 500 GB, and use the other one to upgrade my 13” Mid-2010 MacBook Pro. That way I could upgrade both Macs for only a little bit more money.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/14025500850_824955693e_b.jpg" title="Scary, I know, but it’s easier than it looks."/>
    <p class="caption">Scary, I know, but it’s easier than it looks.</p>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<h2>Getting my hands dirty</h2>

<p>Upgrading the hard drive in a Mid-2010 MacBook Pro is relatively simple, just follow <a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Guide/MacBook+Pro+13-Inch+Unibody+Mid+2010+Hard+Drive+Replacement/4305">the iFixit guide</a> and you’ll be fine. I will focus here on the iMac. In order to install a 2.5” SSD into an iMac, you need to use a special adapter. The iMac’s bay is designed to hold 3.5” drives, so if you try to install the SSD as-is, it will not be properly secured and it will move around inside the iMac. Obviously, you do not want that to happen. I recommend using the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002Z2QDNE/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B002Z2QDNE&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=KQ5JK6V62VQSJM6Z">Icy Dock EZConvert adapter</a>, which is cheap and will get the job done without any issues.</p>

<p>Other than that, all you need is a Torx T-8 screwdriver, a Torx T-6 screwdriver, two heavy-duty suction cups to remove the glass panel, and you’re good to go. Disassembling the iMac, especially for the first time, is a bit imposing and not for the faint of heart, but it really is quite simple. The whole process from disassembly to reassembly can probably be done in under an hour, if you know what you’re doing.</p>

<p>I have uploaded <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/analogsenses/sets/72157644313490407/">an album with some photos to my Flickr account</a>, in case you want to see it in more detail. Each photo includes a brief description of what’s going on. It’s fun to look at the pictures and think, “hey, I did that”, but there’s really nothing there that you won’t see on the iFixit guide.</p>

<p>I do have a few comments that I thought were not sufficiently clear on the guide, though:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>The screws that hold the aluminum bezel in place have different lengths depending on their position. I took some pictures with each screw next to its original hole to help me remember where each one went.</p></li>
<li><p>When you’re about to remove the LCD panel (<a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Guide/iMac+Intel+24-Inch+EMC+2134+and+2211+Hard+Drive+Replacement/8968#s34604">Step 11 on the iFixit guide</a>), <strong>DO NOT DISCONNECT THE LCD POWER CABLE FROM THE POWER SUPPLY END.</strong> Seriously. Instead, disconnect it from the other end, where it attaches to the LCD panel itself. It’s extremely difficult to reconnect that cable, since the awkward position underneath the power supply makes it almost impossible to handle. I didn’t connect this cable properly the first time and my iMac’s display would not turn on. After getting through the entire process, I had to disassemble everything again, including four additional screws that hold the power supply in place so that I could tilt it and gain access to the connector. I then realized I had bent one of the connector’s pins, which was causing the problem. It was only thanks to the comments section of the iFixit guide that I found out about this. They really should change the guide to state this more prominently, since it is a potentially dangerous situation: had the pin broken, I probably would’ve had to replace the entire power supply, with the added cost and difficulty that would have meant. This is the only complaint I have on what’s otherwise an excellent guide, but it’s kind of an important one.</p></li>
<li><p>When you’re mounting the SSD inside the adapter, thread the thermal sensor cable through one of the ventilation openings and attach the sensor to the SSD using duct tape. I found this to be easy with the Icy Dock adapter, which is one of the reasons I recommend using that one. A wrongly-attached thermal sensor may cause your iMac’s fans to work at full-speed all the time, thus killing one of the greatest features of the iMac: its near-silent operation.</p></li>
<li><p>This is probably an obvious thing, but I’ll say it anyway: this is a great opportunity to thoroughly clean up your iMac’s interior. I assure you, the amount of dust you’ll discover inside will surprise you. Make sure you clean everything before reassembling your iMac. I used a compressed-air spray to remove dust from the trickier components: fans, motherboard, speakers, etc. Put special care into making sure there are no dust particles caught between the LCD and the glass panel. Remember, a clean Mac is a happy Mac.</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>Restoring the System</h2>

<p>The last part of the process is, of course, getting your new SSD up and running. Here you have basically two options: you can restore from a previous Time Machine or <a href="http://www.shirt-pocket.com/SuperDuper/superduperdescription.html">SuperDuper!</a> backup, or you can start fresh by installing OS X from scratch. For the iMac, I decided to restore from a backup, since I’d made a clean install not too long ago. For the MacBook Pro, however, I chose to do a clean install instead. I booted the newly-assembled iMac from a SuperDuper! backup I had on an external drive and used SuperDuper! to restore the backup to the SSD. The restoring process took about 90 minutes and it was absolutely flawless. When it was done, I was up and running again without any issues whatsoever. I really cannot recommend SuperDuper! enough. If you own a Mac, you should definitely be using it.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/14211973414_fc9ab7e6b1_b.jpg" title="It’s Alive!"/>
    <p class="caption">It’s Alive!</p>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<h2>The Verdict</h2>

<p>Upgrading my 2008 iMac with an SSD has really given it a new lease of life. I couldn’t be happier with the result, and I sincerely recommend doing the same if you own one. The performance improvement is nothing short of spectacular: apps launch instantaneously, file transfers are a breeze and the entire system keeps up with my workflow without breaking a sweat. These days, computers are so over-specced that there really is no need to upgrade as frequently as before. The 24-inch iMac is an amazing computer, and it’s so well-built that it really makes sense to keep it around for as long as you possibly can. With the added performance of an SSD, my iMac will probably always be “fast-enough” for my needs, so I intend to keep it around until it breaks apart or it is no longer supported by new releases of OS X. Whatever comes first.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Product photography on the cheap: creating a studio-like environment at home]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/07/product-photography-on-the-cheap-creating-a-studio-like-environment-at-home/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T12:36:01+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/07/product-photography-on-the-cheap-creating-a-studio-like-environment-at-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/the-panasonic-lumix-g-20mm-f1-7-ii-asph-lens-review/">my review</a> of the Panasonic 20mm f/1.7 Micro Four Thirds lens for <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>, I tried a few new things for my product shots. I usually take these shots at home, in a variety of different real-life scenarios. Those tend to work well for the type of reviews we do at <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>, but there’s also something I really like about professional product shots. This time around, I wanted to try my hand at it and see what I could come up with.</p>

<p>My goal was to replicate the studio look you often see in professional product shots, so I decided to go for the same “white-room” look that my friend Josh Ginter often uses in <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/the-olympus-40-150mm-f2-8-pro-lens-review/">his own product reviews</a>.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187855919_0c5ebf2b97_o.jpg"/></p>




<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19751827794_b3472731b8_o.jpg"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">The Olympus 40-150mm f/2.8 PRO zoom. Images courtesy of <a href="http://thenewsprint.co">Josh Ginter</a>.</p>


<p>There are several ways to achieve this look, the most obvious one being shooting them in an actual studio with proper studio lighting and a solid white backdrop. Luckily, if you don’t have access to a studio or lack the financial means to rent one, there are other alternatives you can use to get about 90% of the way there without spending a dime. All it takes is a little improvisation and some clean-up work in post production.</p>

<p>The end result, I believe, stands up fairly well to scrutiny.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187741619_3c7672ae00_o.jpg"/></p>




<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187742389_043553d91a_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>Not too bad, is it? Now, let’s take a closer look at what it takes to get these results.</p>

<h2>Necessary gear</h2>

<p>In order to get a studio-like look in your product shots, this is what you’ll need:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>A fairly spacious surface to work on, preferably a desk or something similar.</p></li>
<li><p>A window next to which we can set up our workplace.</p></li>
<li><p>A large piece of solid white fabric —or your color of choice — which will act as our backdrop. It must be large enough to cover the entire desk and not have much texture to it. Think of bed sheets, for example. Of course, there are actual <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00SR2920C/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00SR2920C&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=WKRQU2YR672FVGV5">studio backdrops</a> you can buy and use, and they’re not particularly expensive, but in a pinch, bed sheets will do just fine.</p></li>
<li><p>A flat object we can prop up on our desk, creating a vertical surface to hold our backdrop in place. A computer screen, a television, a framed picture or something along those lines will work perfectly.</p></li>
<li><p>A large, reflective surface we can use as a reflector to minimize shadows. If you have a large standing mirror, that’s about perfect. If not, any smaller mirror or even a solid white surface will do.</p></li>
<li><p>Optional: If there’s not much light in your room or you want to keep the same framing across several shots, you will also need a tripod.</p></li>
<li><p>Optional: A second set of bed sheets to act as a diffusor.</p></li>
<li><p>A photo-editing application, like Adobe Lightroom.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>That’s pretty much it. Now let’s see how we can use all of this to create our own studio at home.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20374381165_2129903a5e_o.jpg"/></p>


<h2>Setting everything up</h2>

<p>As you may have guessed from the list above, the procedure is actually quite simple. We set up our desk next to a bright window, if possible at the brightest time of the day. In order to scatter the light and reduce shadows, we will need to cover the window with some semi-transparent material to act as a diffusor. This is where the second set of sheets may come in handy if your window doesn’t have blinds on it.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19751704774_23a8a1ee4d_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>Then we place our flat object on the desk resting up agains the wall to create a vertical surface on which to prop up our backdrop. In my case, my 24&#8221; iMac provided just about the perfect solution, since it stands on its own and doesn’t need a wall to lean on.</p>

<p>We then need to place our backdrop over the vertical surface in such a way that it covers the entire working surface, with some excess fabric left hanging over the sides and the front. If you’re using bed sheets or something like that, make sure to fold them a couple times to increase thickness and then give them a thorough ironing to minimize wrinkles. This will make out post production stage a lot easier. Also, be sure to place it in such a way that makes the intersection between the desk and the stand look seamless.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187738689_5ec06ce66e_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>Once the backdrop is in place, we need to set up our homemade reflector at the side, placing it opposite the window. This will reflect available light back on our working surface, giving the illusion of a second light source in the scene and eliminating excessive shadows.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19753452403_b9bb970564_o.jpg"/></p>




<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186395138_755981caa1_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>Once we have everything set up, we place our product on the working surface. Try to position it closer to the edge than to the backdrop, that way it will be easier to blur out the backdrop and give it a more uniform and less distracting appearance.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20380509961_95fe4dd320_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>Finally, we set up the tripod in front of our working surface and fire away.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19753450043_1e8fc4aff2_o.jpg"/></p>


<h2>Shooting tips</h2>

<p>In case it wasn’t clear, this article is not intended as a how-to guide to product photography. There are a million important aspects I haven’t even mentioned here that you should pay attention to. That said, this technique <em>will</em> give you a decent alternative for those situations where accessing a studio is just not feasible. With that in mind, here are a few general-purpose shooting tips you may find helpful:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Place the camera as close to your subject as possible while retaining proper framing. This will reduce depth of field and help separate the product from the background, which is ultimately the goal.</p></li>
<li><p>Use a long focal length, if possible. Choosing a focal length over 50mm (Full Frame equivalent) will minimize distortion and show the product’s relative proportions more accurately. The sweet spot for this type of shots is usually between 85 and 135mm.</p></li>
<li><p>In general, the more light the better, so be sure to take the shots during the brighter part of the day. If your diffusor takes away too much light, using a tripod will become a necessity.</p></li>
<li><p>Keep ISO as low as possible to minimize noise. If you use a tripod, you won’t have a problem with this, even if you need to use super slow shutter speeds — think of 1 second and beyond.</p></li>
<li><p>Keep in mind that the longer the focal length, the farther away you’ll need to stand in order to achieve a similar field of view. These two aspects are always in opposition, so choose the compromise that works best with your available space. This will also depend on the size and shape of the object you want to photograph.</p></li>
<li><p>If the object you’re photographing is full of shiny reflective surfaces, using a flash may not be a good idea. If not, try firing off a few shots with the flash to see if you like the effect. If your window is bright enough and your reflector is properly positioned, the flash shouldn’t be strictly necessary. Also, keep in mind that using a flash will completely eliminate any shadows from the scene. If you want to make sure crucial details aren’t masked by shadows, think about using it.</p></li>
<li><p>Try to keep the backdrop out of focus, but shoot with enough depth of field to ensure most of the product remains in focus. If you’re shooting with a fast prime, you’ll probably need to stop the lens down a bit to achieve this. Besides gaining you some depth of field, stopping down the lens slightly will also result in sharper pictures with less chromatic aberration and vignetting, which is also highly preferred in product photography.</p></li>
<li><p>Be sure to check your images for focus every now and then, and always before switching the product’s position on the desk. Also, don’t forget to review all your images before taking down your studio setup.</p></li>
</ul>


<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187735359_a041fa20f3_o.jpg"/></p>




<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19751700924_2d8a80f6dd_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>This is what you get straight out of camera when using this technique. It’s not bad, but we can do better. Let’s see how we can improve upon this in the post production stage.</p>

<h2>Post production</h2>

<p>Once we’ve taken the images, we’ll need to edit the files to remove any imperfections that remain. I will be using Lightroom here as a reference, but you can use whatever photo-editing application you want, provided they have a similar feature set. Luckily, most of them do.</p>

<p>Once we step into Lightroom, there are several things we can do. For starters, we need to set the appropriate white balance. Click on Auto and see if the image changes for better or worse. If you don’t like what you see, use the eye-dropper tool to set the gray point and click on the background, which should be white but not totally blown.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20348135596_1a239d7bc3_o.jpg" title="White balance corrected"/></p>


<p>We can also can change the tone curve. I like to use a medium contrast curve to emphasize lines a little bit better.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20365844102_2762ccb23c_o.jpg" title="Medium contrast tone curve selected"/></p>


<p>Then, we need to equalize the highlights and the shadows. In general, I have found boosting the shadows by about +30 and reducing the highlights by about -40 is a good place to start.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186312770_29dfb21146_o.jpg" title="Highlights and shadows adjusted"/></p>


<p>Next up, we apply a bit of sharpening and noise reduction to get everything looking nice and sharp. If you’ve shot at a low ISO setting, go easy on the noise reduction because just a little bit will go a long way, and we don’t want to smear the details. These are my usual sharpening and NR settings:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20187730499_97a075b656_o.jpg"/></p>

<p>Again, these are just to get you started. You should of course tweak them to find something you’re happy with.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186387978_df1cf350be_o.jpg" title="Sharpening and noise reduction applied"/></p>


<p>Now our picture should be looking fairly well, but the backdrop is probably still a bit distracting. In order to smoothen that out, we’re going to use Lightoom’s radial filter tool.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19753443193_a396e4a86b_o.jpg" title="Radial filter tool settings in Lightroom"/></p></p>

<p>We click on it, and then we draw an ellipsis around our object, making sure that we’re capturing everything. This tool will apply our settings to everything <em>outside</em> the ellipsis, so we need to make sure we get it all. We can also adjust the intensity of the transition between the inside and the outside of the ellipsis by clicking and adjusting the Feather slider.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186912548_fa50ce5e84_o.jpg" title="Radial filter tool in Lightroom applied"/></p>


<p>Once we’ve drawn the ellipsis and set the transition to something we like, we’re going to bring the Clarity and the Sharpness sliders all the way down to -100. This should greatly improve the appearance of the background.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20348132266_ff690427e5_o.jpg" title="Radial filter tool in Lightroom applied"/></p>


<p>In this case, the improvements are not that noticeable because framing was already quite tight, but if you have a wider composition, you’ll be able to appreciate it much more.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>At this point, your images should be pretty much finished. As you’ve seen, all it takes is a bit of improvisation and patience, and you can get pretty good results right at home and without spending a dime. Obviously, doing these shots in a proper studio will always be better, but if you ever find yourself without access to one, it’s good to know you have options.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20365840202_6a2c7de9c4_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>This technique works very well for small products like cameras, lenses and the like. If you need to take pictures of bigger objects, you’ll probably need to consider buying <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00SR2920C/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00SR2920C&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=analogsens-20&amp;linkId=WKRQU2YR672FVGV5">a proper studio backdrop</a> with a built-in support stand.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186309390_daf78f3550_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>You may think this whole procedure is just too much hassle to be worth it, but it really isn’t. You can set everything up and take it down in about five minutes, so it’s actually easier and faster than driving to the studio when you think about it. And it doesn’t even take that much effort in post production, because you can save most of these edits <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/s5emnf0mwhu0sg9/Product%20Photography%20At%20Home.lrtemplate?dl=0">as a Lightroom preset</a>. Then, all you need to adjust for each individual shot are the white balance and the size of the ellipsis for the radial filter, both of which you can do in literally under 30 seconds.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/20186384298_f1b62a8e94_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>I, for one, am pretty happy with how this experiment went, and you can bet I’ll be using this technique again for upcoming reviews. I love how incredibly simple it is, all things considered, and how great the results are. And, of course, not having to spend any money also helps.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning to work with models in photography]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/07/learning-to-work-with-models-in-photography/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T19:15:05+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/07/learning-to-work-with-models-in-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s no secret that working with models in photography can be challenging. One of the most interesting aspects of the photography course I took over the past few months was the chance to work with experienced models in a controlled environment. That was a great way to learn how to interact with them in a professional way and, more importantly, how to take the reins of a shoot in order to direct the session and get the results <em>you</em> want.</p>

<p>In this piece I’ll share a bit of my own experience during the course, as well as out there shooting in the real world. Hopefully that’ll give you an opportunity to learn from my mistakes and save yourself an awkward moment or two.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18871607424_a633b32525_o.jpg"/></p>


<h2>Before your first time</h2>

<p>There’s no doubt the first time you’re working with a model is a pretty intimidating experience. You’re probably not only inexperienced in being around models to begin with, but you’re also inexperienced when it comes to directing a serious shooting session. Those two things can add up and become more than you can handle, so it’s important to remain calm. The good news is, it really doesn’t need to be a stressful event, if you only take a couple precautions.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19306527180_ca844eb062_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Model: Neus Martín.</p>


<p>The first and most important of those precautions is to do your homework in advance. I really can’t stress enough just how critical this is. You should have a perfect idea of what you want to achieve long before the shoot even begins, and plan accordingly. There are several non-trivial aspects to every shoot that require preparation: the lighting, the backdrop, the location, the time of the day, whether you’ll need to provide makeup and/or clothing for the model and so on.</p>

<p>All those things <em>massively</em> affect the outcome and, in many cases, dictate your actions as a photographer and the actions of the model as your subject. Going to a session unprepared is pretty much like attempting to shoot a Hollywood movie without a script. Just don’t. Don’t worry though, we’ll take a more detailed look at all these things in a moment.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487696392_d8dc632f6d_o.jpg" title="Sara Gil"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Model: Sara Gil.</p>


<p>As for the being around models part, that’s something that will take some getting used to. You’re going to have to learn to deal with it progressively and trust that it will get easier the more you do it — because it will, and surprisingly quickly, in fact. If you feel intimidated by their good looks or are naturally shy, you could start out easy, by arranging a shoot with a model of the gender you’re not physically attracted to.</p>

<p>However, I think that would be the wrong way to go about this. I recommend simply taking things naturally and not worrying about it too much. Just remember you’re both there to work, not to socialize. Being open and friendly is great; being unprofessional isn’t.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19498460161_be74d7d9a9_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Model: Daniel García.</p>


<p>This is where being well prepared ahead of your shoot can prove to be life-saving. If you have a well-defined action plan, chances are you’ll be able to work your way through it despite some initial awkwardness. Soon the technical nature of the work will take over and you’ll start to relax. There’s nothing worse than having a model ask you for directions and not knowing what to say, so be sure to always have a couple ideas you can turn to whenever inspiration runs dry.</p>

<h2>Finding a model to work with</h2>

<p>If you don’t already know any models you’d like to work with, either in person or through mutual friends, take a look at some of the online photography networks that provide a way for models and photographers to meet. Sites like <a href="http://www.modelmayhem.com">Model Mayhem</a> — and <a href="https://www.litmind.com">Litmind</a> in Europe — are very popular and you’ll probably be able to find a nearby model that meets your requirements.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19306520148_9c10293a47_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<p>These websites are a great place to start, since they offer pretty good search engines that allow you to filter results by gender, age or any other physical attributes — hair and eye color, for example. If you can’t afford to pay the model, you can also filter the search results to show only models that are open to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_for_print">time-for-prints</a> arrangement.</p>

<p>This goes without saying but, should you decide to contact a model through one of these websites, be honest and upfront about what you’re looking for. Online services like these are entirely based on the honor system; they only work when the relationship is mutually beneficial. If you’re not really interested in working together, don’t contact a model. You wouldn’t do it in real life, so don’t do it online. And don’t back away from an already established deal unless you have a pretty good reason to do so.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487690952_3bf5a41f98_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<p>Also, don’t forget that, despite having tons of beautiful people on them, these are <em>not</em> dating websites. Everything you do as an individual user affects the rest of the community, so don’t be a jerk. Seriously.</p>

<h2>Managing expectations</h2>

<p>Before even meeting the model, both of you should have a clear idea of what to expect from the shoot. Will it be paid work or a time-for-prints arrangement? Who keeps the rights to the final images? These are potentially thorny issues, and you need to sort them out long before pressing the shutter release.</p>

<p><strong>If it’s a time-for-prints arrangement</strong>, state clearly and unequivocally whether you’ll be providing prints, digital copies of the images, or both. Also, reach an agreement on whether you’ll be providing the original, unedited shots or only your final edited selections, as well as how much post-processing work is to be expected in the final images. If you have a problem with giving the model your RAW files, say so explicitly. Personally, I’m not comfortable with giving models unedited shots or RAW files, because in my mind, I’m still responsible for the final quality of those images, which are essentially unfinished at that point. Having someone else make the edits seems wrong to me, but your mileage may vary. It also depends on how important each particular shoot is to you, personally.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18871605084_123054edd3_o.jpg"  title="Sara on Film"/></p>


<p><strong>If it’s paid work</strong>, make it perfectly clear who will be getting paid, and how much. Also, reach an agreement on when payment will be made. Typically you have three choices: before the shoot, after the shoot and upon delivery of the final images. You can fraction payment between two or more of those moments if you’re feeling unsure. Don’t let yourself be cornered into a situation you’re not comfortable with. If a model is not happy with your conditions — provided they’re reasonable, that is — it’s better to try and find another one.</p>

<p><strong>Sign a standard release contract.</strong> Regardless of whether it’s a time-for-prints arrangement or paid work, it can also be a good idea for both of you to sign a standard release contract in order to avoid any potential legal issues in the future. There are <a href="https://lessaccounting.com/blog/free-photography-contracts/">many templates</a> on the Internet you can use for that purpose. Nothing has to go wrong but if you’re concerned about this, better safe than sorry.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19494083625_aa8d772421_o.jpg"/></p>


<p><strong>Explain what you’re trying to achieve.</strong> If the shoot is intended to promote or review a product, say it. If you’re not going for flattering shots, tell the model in advance. And obviously, if you expect to take some nude shots, ask your model before. There’s nothing wrong with either of those things, but make sure the model knows about it and set expectations accordingly.</p>

<p><strong>Once the shoot is done</strong>, explain clearly what usage rights you’re granting for your images, and whether you require attribution upon further use. If you’re not ok with seeing your pictures popping up on the Web without attribution, try to explain your point of view to the model, as well as why this is important.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19307972009_7bfdf94f84_o.jpg"  title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<p><strong>Establish trust from the get go, and don’t break it.</strong> Never force a situation beyond the existing understanding. If you haven’t talked about nude shots before, don’t bring it up during the shoot, no matter how easy-going or open-minded the model may seem. You can absolutely ruin the mood of the entire session by creating an uncomfortable moment like that. And worst of all, the model may feel coerced into doing something that wasn’t previously discussed. You don’t want that. There’s always another day, so don’t rush things.</p>

<p><strong>Give the model the option to bring someone along for the shoot.</strong> This will help ensure your model feels safe, which will in turn make it a lot easier to work on creating compelling images together. Plus, you may even find yourself with two models to work with instead of just one.</p>

<h2>Preparing for the shoot</h2>

<p>We’ve already talked about how preparing for a shoot is essential to keep thing things productive and professional, but how does one do that, exactly? Here are a few of the elements you should consider.</p>

<p>The lighting is by far the most important aspect of any shoot, arguably even more important than the models themselves. The first major question you need to ask yourself is whether you want this to be a studio session or an outdoors shoot using, mostly or exclusively, natural light.</p>

<p>If it’s going to be a studio session, there are several things to plan for:</p>

<p><strong>What kind of background will you use?</strong> You can use a solid white background, a solid black background or something else altogether, but you’ll need to make your choice beforehand. If you want to use multiple backgrounds in the same session, think about which one you’d like to use first and have that put up in advance in order to maximize the amount of actual shooting time. If you want to use one particular background for the majority of the shots, go with that one first. Also, keep in mind that the light sources you place in the scene will significantly change the way the background appears in your images.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18872497594_e078927889_o.jpg" title="Sara Gil"/></p>


<p><strong>What kind of lighting?</strong> Continuous light applied without using a soft box renders sharp shadows and creates high contrast in a scene, which is great for emphasizing body lines and creating an artistic effect. A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soft_box">soft box</a>, on the other hand, creates much softer shadows and is generally more flattering for portraits, for example. And then there are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strobe_light">strobes</a>, which can be used to create some specific visual effects.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487681152_e781608971_o.jpg" title="Continuous Light"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Tip: Use continuous lights without a soft box in order to increase contrast and create sharp shadows for a dramatic effect.</p>


<p><strong>What about flash lighting?</strong> Flash lighting can be used on its own or in combination with other light sources, and can dramatically alter the way a scene looks. A flash can be pointed directly towards the subject — with or without a soft box — or it can be bounced off some other surface to achieve a more subtle effect. It can be used as the main light source in a scene, or to fill darker areas in an image. Depending on what you want to achieve, you will need to prepare your gear appropriately.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19495187665_0f8c61c256_o.jpg" title="Vanessa"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Tip: Flash lighting can be used to eliminate shadows on the model’s face. Model: Vanessa Martinez.</p>


<p><strong>How many light sources will there be in the scene?</strong> Will you use an extra light source for effect? These can add punch to an image. If you’re going to use several light sources, you’ll need to decide which one will act as the main source and which ones will be secondary. Keep in mind that different light sources may have different color temperatures, so there may be a color cast to watch out for.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18871594114_ffb5c0a38b_o.jpg" title="Sara"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Tip: In general, setting your camera’s white balance to match the main light source is a good way to go, but keep an eye on the images as you go.</p>


<p>Conversely, if it’s going to be an outdoors shoot using mostly natural light, pay attention to the following items:</p>

<p><strong>What type of light are you looking for?</strong> The most flattering light is usually the one that falls during the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_hour_(photography)">golden hour</a>”. This phenomenon occurs approximately during the fist couple hours of daylight just after sunrise, and the last two hours before sunset. At those times, daylight is warmer and falls laterally, producing longer shadows. By contrast, the mid-day Sun produces much harsher shadows and higher contrast, which are usually not desirable qualities when shooting with natural light. If you must shoot during the central hours of the day, try to pick a day with a cloudy forecast, or a location where you’ll be able to find some shade. Total amount of light will not be a problem, so it’s preferable to focus on the quality of it.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19306534470_ae780fe57a_o.jpg" title="Golden Hour"/></p>


<p><strong>Don’t forget your filters and lens hoods.</strong> If you’re shooting outside, you should always keep a polarizing filter on your lens at the very minimum. Natural light is pretty tricky, and reflections can be a real problem if you don’t have the proper equipment. A polarizing filter generally increases contrast and makes colors more rich, vivid and saturated. If you’re planning to shoot black and white images, a dark yellow filter will greatly increase contrast in the sky, for example. And if you want to achieve subject separation on a very bright day, you’ll need to use a neutral density filter in order to be able to shoot wide open without overexposing your shots. These are all very important elements when shooting outside, and planning for them in advance can prove invaluable during the shoot.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19468040416_7513a1af43_o.jpg" title="A storm approaches"/></p>


<p><strong>What’s the weather going to be like?</strong> It goes without saying, but scheduling a bikini shoot in the middle of winter might not be the best idea. Keeping the model comfortable goes a long way towards ensuring a productive session. Similarly, having a shoot interrupted by rain is something that should be avoided. If there’s a high probability of rain around the time of your shoot, try to reschedule or have a secondary location in mind, just in case. Ideally, your secondary location should have a roof, or a protected area where rain will not be a problem.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19495668265_bf124a0bfb_o.jpg"  title="Chilly day"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Tip: You should try to provide a comfortable working environment for your model. For example, if it’s going to get cold, bring a robe or something along those lines.</p>


<p><strong>Do you require permission to shoot at your venue of choice?</strong> Some venues like stadiums, museums, churches, institutional buildings and the like can be great locations for photos, but sometimes they have special rules in place that can be a problem for you. Tripods, for example, are usually not allowed in these places. Be sure to check with the proper authorities beforehand in order to save yourself the trouble of getting there only to be denied permission to shoot at the last minute. If you need to apply for permission, do so well in advance.</p>

<p><strong>Will you need additional help?</strong> Sometimes your own two hands are not enough. If you need a friend to hold a flash in place, or to carry some of the equipment, try to coordinate with the person <em>before</em> setting up a final date and time for the shoot. You don’t want to commit with the model only to find out later on that your friend can’t make it. Be serious and professional when scheduling your sessions and respect the model’s time as much as you respect your own.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19306522108_88492a469f_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<p>There are, of course, many more questions to be asked, but these should at least give you a reasonable starting point. Be sure to make a list of everything you’ll need, and go over that list before making the final date with the model.</p>

<h2>Directing the shoot</h2>

<p>Once you’ve prepared everything you’ll need and worked out the details with your model, it’s time to meet. This goes without saying, but: be on time. There’s nothing worse than arriving late to your own shoot. If you’re not able to show enough respect for the model to be on time, you’re already starting off on the wrong foot.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487701262_c5fa1b0477_o.jpg"/></p>


<p>First up, introduce yourself and ask a couple generic questions to break the ice. A smile goes a long way towards getting people to feel comfortable, so be nice.</p>

<p>Also, be respectful. If you don’t think you can pull off being respectful <em>and</em> nice, go for respectful first. Keep in mind that the model doesn’t know you and doesn’t know what kind of person you are, so don’t go for weird inside jokes that only your friends would understand. Similarly, don’t insist on making small talk if the model doesn’t want to. At the end of the day you’re both there to work. Getting along is preferred, but it’s not indispensable.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487681862_d8b55b8055_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<p>That said, remember that good models are comfortable with following directions — so give them. They actually <em>need</em> directions to do their work properly. Don’t be shy about saying what you need them to do in order for the shot to work. You can, for example, say that you like their hair better this way, or that you want them to stand up to emphasize the length of their legs.</p>

<p>Try to be positive and encouraging with your comments, give them an idea of what you want to achieve in the shot and they’ll get involved and help you. Have it be a collaborative effort, but always maintain control of the session yourself. Your goal is to get the shots <em>you</em> want, so act accordingly.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19498455541_48c457df67_o.jpg" title="Neus and the GR Echo"/></p>


<h2>Don’t forget to measure!</h2>

<p>If you’re working in a studio, measuring the different light sources is critical to achieve the desired effect. It’s easy to forget about this when you start taking pictures, but it’s essential to keep it in mind at all times.</p>

<p>The best way to do this is with a dedicated <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_meter">light meter</a>. These do not come cheap, but provide more flexibility over your camera’s built-in light meter. By placing the meter on the model’s skin, facing towards the light source, you’re measuring incident light directly, which means the resulting parameters will be correct regardless of the photographer’s shooting distance from the model. Also, it’ll guarantee that you won’t overexpose the skin to the point of blowing your highlights.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19494082185_207e9ebe4a_o.jpg"  title="Sara"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Tip: If you’re using an effect light to emphasize parts of the image, like the model’s hair in this case, you should position it so that the light meter gives a reading that is exactly one stop higher than the main light source.</p>


<p>Once you’ve got everything set up the way you like it, start shooting, but don’t forget to redo all your measurements whenever there’s a change in the scene. The tricky thing to remember here is that cameras don’t see the same way we do. Even an apparently insignificant change can have major consequences in the final picture. Whenever you alter the scene, even if it’s just by having the model take half a step forward, the entire lighting scheme changes.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18874350583_2716b1932d_o.jpg" title="Sara"/></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Failing to adjust for apparently small light variations in a scene can result in very poor images that are way beyond saving in post production.</p>


<p>Don’t assume you can just fix everything later in Lightroom. Being careful before releasing the shutter pays off later when you don’t have to correct the same mistake over and over again.</p>

<p>And of course, if you’re shooting film, following a proper metering routine becomes even more of a necessity, since you won’t be able to review your images during the shoot.</p>

<h2>Review your images</h2>

<p>Another hugely important thing to keep in mind — always, but even more so during your first time working with a model — is to check the results as you go. Don’t wait until you get home to review your images. It’s surprisingly easy to get into a groove and be overpowered by the creativity of the moment, but photography — particularly studio photography — is every bit as much a technical discipline as it is a creative one.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18873453323_f816355ef9_o.jpg" title="Daniel García"/></p>


<p>Don’t forget to check your exposures every now and then to confirm things are going as expected. Using your camera’s histogram feature can prove invaluable for this task, so pull it up alongside your images and ask yourself some of these questions:</p>

<p><strong>Are your shots properly in focus?</strong> Sometimes it’s not immediately obvious whether the focus is right, so be sure to check.</p>

<p><strong>Is the exposure correct?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Is the subject properly lit? What about the background?</strong></p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19487683082_c58a9a9a88_o.jpg" title="Sara"/></p>


<p><strong>Are the highlights blown? What about the shadows?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Is the framing what you were looking for?</strong> Are any parts of the model’s body — hands, waist, feet, etc. — being cut out of the frame? If so, was that intentional or an accident?</p>

<p><strong>Can you see both of your subject’s eyes?</strong> If not, was that an oversight?</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19498465751_ca113e2c47_o.jpg"/></p>


<p><strong>Is there sweat on the model’s skin?</strong> It’s especially important to keep an eye on this when using high-powered studio lights, because they emit a considerable amount of heat and can cause the model’s skin to perspire a little. You may not immediately notice it through your viewfinder, but tiny sweat drops will appear as blown highlights in the final images and even after correcting it in post production, you’ll lose the texture of the skin in those areas. The histogram will tell you if there are any blown highlights to look for. Be sure to keep a towel or a tissue box handy just in case.</p>

<p>These are questions that can make or break an image, and once the session ends there’s no going back. You don’t need to check <em>every single image</em> — a bad habit that is commonly referred to as “chimping” — but keep an eye on them from time to time, just to be safe. At the very least, review your images before changing the model’s posture or switching to a different scene and make sure you have at least one or two images you like before moving on. I find that’s a good compromise that works well for me.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18873444753_f91f43d2ea_o.jpg" title="Sara"/></p>


<p>Following these precautions will ensure you keep most things under control during your session. Now, not all types of shoots are the same, of course. Some of them are particularly sensitive and require special care. A good example of this are nude shoots.</p>

<h2>Shooting nudes (NSFW)</h2>

<p>Shooting nudes is one of the best creative and technical exercises in photography. Fine art nude photography is all about mastering the lighting, and playing with shadows to emphasize your model’s body lines. It’s almost like sculpting with light and it very much requires you to bring your A-game to the shoot.</p>

<p>This is not a moment for improvising. When a model is trusting you enough to get undressed, keeping things serious and professional becomes even more important.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19494085685_e0f998a0c8_o.jpg" title="Shooting Nudes"/></p>


<p>You should have a specific plan in mind for every shoot, but even more so for nude shoots. Do a bit of research and try to come up with a few poses you’d like to attempt. Also, work out the necessary lighting scheme in advance and try to have everything in place by the time the model arrives. You’ll still need to measure, but the less time the model needs to stand there waiting for you to get your act together, the better.</p>

<p>Another thing to keep in mind is that nude pictures can vary a lot depending on your model’s body type. Some build types are better suited for direct, harsh lighting, while others look better with a more diffuse light. If you’ve met your model before or have access to their online portfolio, try to think of their complexion when you’re researching, and choose poses and lighting schemes that will go well with their particular body type.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18873446993_7faf0a8bdb_o.jpg" title="Shooting Nudes"/></p>


<p>If possible, try to have a separated area where the model can have some privacy to get changed. You should also bring a robe or something along those lines in case the model prefers to be covered in between shots. Again, they may not actually end up using it, but merely knowing it’s there sends the right message and helps establish trust between the two of you. And if there’s one thing that’s absolutely indispensable for shooting nudes, it’s trust.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/19468026156_a2564b8ab7_o.jpg" title="Shooting Nudes"/></p>


<p>It’s also super important to act naturally. You’ll probably be nervous on your first few times, that’s perfectly normal. Don’t fight it. Try not to behave like you were just caught skipping class by your mom, and you’ll be fine. If it helps, remind yourself that we’re all naked below our clothes. It really is no big deal. Be aware that you’ll need to look at your model’s body to work the scene. That’s also ok. Don’t feel bad for looking, it’s part of your work. Just don’t stare. There’s a difference.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18871591134_7ac07b2717_o.jpg" title="Shooting Nudes"/></p>


<p>Take your time with each pose, and don’t rush things. When you’re nervous it’s tempting to try to do everything as quickly as possible, but if the end result is poor that doesn’t help anyone. Make sure your images are correct before moving on to the next pose.</p>

<p>Finally, the most important thing when you’re shooting nudes is giving clear, precise directions to the model. This will serve two purposes: one, it will help them do their job better and you get the results you want, and two, it will convey to the model an all-important piece of information: that you actually know what you’re doing.</p>

<h2>Final words: practice makes perfect</h2>

<p>To circle back to the beginning, working with models can be a challenging experience. As you’ve seen in this piece, there are many different elements to watch out for, and it takes a fair amount of work to do it right. That said, it’s also one of the most satisfying experiences in photography, and one of the best ways to learn new tricks and take a couple steps out of your comfort zone.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18873456313_90427beae0_o.jpg" title="Sara"/></p>


<p>As with everything in life, ultimately the key to doing it well is doing it often. Try getting the same shots with different models to get a better sense of what stays the same and what needs changing. Each person is unique and working with lots of different people is by far the best way to improve your skills.</p>

<p>In any case, it’s always better to keep things small at the beginning, and try new things as your confidence level rises. Don’t put too much pressure on yourself, try to enjoy the process and you’ll get the hang of it soon enough.</p>

<p>Just be prepared, because that’s when the real fun begins.</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18873458683_a0ddf1ae47_o.jpg"/></p>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Unless it’s a work-for-hire situation where the model is paying you to take their picture. In that case, obviously, having them provide directions is fine, but you should still have a few ideas of your own, in case they don’t know what to ask for.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
