<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T18:33:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CHANGER, by Matt Gemmell]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/22/changer-by-matt-gemmell/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-22T17:48:40+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/22/changer-by-matt-gemmell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matt Gemmell’s new novel, CHANGER, was released today. For those of us who are members on Matt’s personal site, this is a very special day. We’ve been walking alongside him right from day one, and we’ve watched with excitement and anticipation as he relentlessly inched closer and closer to the finish line. It’s been humbling to watch Matt deal with the struggle, all without ever losing faith in himself or his writing. Today, we all celebrate.</p>

<p>It’s been a great journey. Writing a book is no small deed — only the tree and the child missing now, I guess — and I for one feel very fortunate to have witnessed its birth from our tiny little window: Matt’s newsletter, <em><a href="http://mattgemmell.com/membership/">The Writer’s Life</a></em>.</p>

<p>Of course, the best part — you know, the actual reading — comes now. For what it’s worth, I’m only halfway through the first chapter and I’m already hooked. I’d say I’m surprised, but Matt always did have a way with words.</p>

<p>Now, if you’ll excuse me, I left a ruthless mercenary doing some pretty nasty things and I can’t wait to see what comes next.</p>

<p>Care to join me?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Gemmell’s membership so far]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/24/matt-gemmells-membership-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-24T18:15:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/24/matt-gemmells-membership-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matt Gemmell shares an interesting update on how his membership program is working so far:</p>

<blockquote><p>In a nutshell, I’m <em>hugely</em> pleased with how it’s turned out. I was so thrilled at the response, and it’s energising for me each week to remember that I have a group of people who enjoy my work enough to not just keep coming back to read my words, but to actually support the creation of new articles and books.</p>

<p>You can’t put a price on that sort of encouragement and validation. On my worst days, I can always log in and look at the membership roster, and get a boost from it.</p></blockquote>

<p>These updates are incredibly important and useful for those who, like me, hope to follow in Matt’s footsteps one day. Reading real stories from real people who have faced — and keep facing — your same fears and struggles is one of the best ways to stay motivated in your work.</p>

<p>The Internet usually shows a deeply skewed version of reality, where success stories are amplified several orders of magnitude, while failure stories are soon erased or, worse, never even shared to begin with. I’m incredibly happy for Matt and I’m glad to see he’s doing fine, but there’s no doubt in my mind he still would have written this piece even if the story had had a not-so-happy ending.</p>

<p>That’s what separates Matt from the vast majority of writers on the Web today: he’s not overly concerned with keeping up the pretense of perfection, because he respects his readers too much to not be 100% honest with them.</p>

<p>Matt is a rare breed of author, and I couldn’t be more proud to support his work. I’ve been a member since day one, and will continue being so for as long as he’ll keep the membership program alive. If you appreciate honesty and respect — not to mention first-class writing — I strongly encourage you to do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Gemmell’s new book, ‘Writing in Markdown’, is now available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/09/matt-gemmells-new-book-writing-in-markdown-is-now-available/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-09T12:38:17+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/09/matt-gemmells-new-book-writing-in-markdown-is-now-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Matt Gemmell’s new book is out today. It’s called <a href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/products/writing-in-markdown">Writing in Markdown</a>, and it’s the first in a new series of short books by publisher <a href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/">Five Simple Steps</a>. The series is called <a href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/blogs/news/35441605-introducing-fast-reads-a-new-series-of-books">Fast Reads</a>, and the idea is to create short, informative and densely packed books that are easy to read in one sitting and provide a comprehensive overview on any given topic. In Matt’s own words:</p>

<blockquote><p>I write every article on this site (and my articles for publication elsewhere, in magazines and online) in Markdown. All my notes are in Markdown files. My weekly <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/membership/">members-only newsletters</a> begin life as Markdown files. I even think in that format.</p>

<p>It was fitting, then, that I was offered the opportunity to write a Fast Read – the first in the series, no less – about using Markdown. I gladly accepted, and I’m pleased to announce that the book is now available.</p>

<p>It’s called <a href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/products/writing-in-markdown">Writing in Markdown</a>, it’s about 5,000 words long, and you can read it cover-to-cover in around twenty minutes. It costs £2.50 (or $3.80, or €3.50), and it’s available now.</p></blockquote>

<p>Like Matt, I do most of my writing in Markdown, including <em>all</em> of my writing here on Analog Senses, plus my regular collaborations in other sites like <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net">Tools &amp; Toys</a>.</p>

<p>I really enjoy the simplicity of the Markdown format, but I especially appreciate its power. Being able to write in a readable format that can be converted to HTML in a straightforward, no-nonsense way is a huge benefit in my work. If your work — or play — involves writing for the Web at all, you could probably benefit a great deal from using Markdown.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Note]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/05/the-note/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-05T19:39:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/05/the-note</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fantastic article by Shawn Blanc:</p>

<blockquote><p>By giving myself no room for wiggling around or making excuses, I’ve found that having this set time to write means I actually write more than if I were to wait only for inspiration to strike. I write more words in general (usually 1,500 words every day) than days when I wait for inspiration. And my writing is of a higher quality — my crappy first drafts are much less crappy.</p>

<p>And, though my timer is set for 30 minutes, more often than not by the time the half-hour is up, I’m firing on all cylinders and I will continue to write for another hour or three.</p>

<p>As someone who writes for a living, I cannot think of anything more important for me to do each day than to actually write.</p></blockquote>

<p>It’s an apparently simple lesson, but it so often goes unnoticed: if you care about doing something, <em>set a time for it.</em></p>

<p>This lesson applies to everything that matters: exercise, writing, reading, you name it. Anything worth doing takes time, and that time is not going to magically schedule itself. If you want to exercise more regularly, don’t just wait and see when you have some free time in the day to do it. Instead, make it your first priority in the morning, even if it means waking up earlier than usual and going to bed earlier at night. You’ll be surprised at how soon it becomes part of your routine, and that’s when the real fun begins.</p>

<p>I’m not saying it’s easy, but I am saying it’s worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chris Gonzales launches ‘Stellar Edits’]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/28/chris-gonzales-launches-stellar-edits/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-28T17:50:24+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/28/chris-gonzales-launches-stellar-edits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Exciting announcement by Chris Gonzales:</p>

<blockquote><p>This is where I come in. <em><strong>Stellar Edits</strong></em> is a professional editing service I’ve created to help indie creators publish their words with confidence. Everyone has a unique voice, and I want to help you strengthen yours.</p>

<p>Let’s tell your story better.</p></blockquote>

<p>Every time I’m working on a lengthy piece I wonder how some guys<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> are able to publish thousands of edited words per week without any noticeable decrease in quality or polish.</p>

<p>The reason I wonder is because writing is the easy part. It’s where all the fun happens and if you get in the zone, you can easily get through a whole piece in one sitting. The problem is, once you’re done writing you still have a long way to go if you want your piece to be polished and ready for publication. If you aspire to maintain a certain standard for your work, you have to <em>edit</em>.</p>

<p>And guess what? Editing is <em>hard</em>.</p>

<p>It’s hard not only because it’s less fun to do — which it is — but because as the original author, you’re probably not even equipped to edit your own words professionally. Great editing goes way beyond simple grammar-fixing, it’s all about making sure that the message gets through to the audience as clearly as possible and if you’re the one making the mistakes, you’re probably not going to be able to fix them on your own.</p>

<p>A brilliant editor you can trust is probably one of the most — if not <em>the</em> most — valuable assets any writer can have.</p>

<p>I’m really excited about this. Everything we can do to increase the level of polish and professionalism of the written Web is a win in my book, and Chris just scored a big one for the team. I know I would trust him with anything and I’m sure once you try his services, you’ll never look back.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Jason Snell, I’m looking at you.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
