<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photostories | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/photostories/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-06-21T17:45:31+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thailand 2024: a photo story]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2024/04/01/thailand-2024-a-photo-story/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T14:38:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2024/04/01/thailand-2024-a-photo-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a very special trip for me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been wanting to visit Thailand ever since January of 2019, when I first went to Hawaii with my life-long best friend Virginia and our friend Cristina. That probably still stands as the best trip of my life, and I find that&rsquo;s an excellent reason to just keep traveling.</p>

<p>Virginia and I both love traveling, and we even have a matching travel-inspired tattoo that celebrates our friendship and our shared love of discovering new places and cultures. After Hawaii, we both quickly agreed that Thailand would be a fitting way to follow up from that once-in-a-lifetime experience, so we planned to spend 2020&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s Eve there. Unfortunately, as we all know, the pandemic happened, and we were forced to postpone the trip until international travel was reasonably safe again. Then life got in the way, as it always does, and we haven&rsquo;t really had a chance to make it work until now.</p>

<p>This time our friends Sofia and Aurora joined us on the adventure, and the four of us booked a trip to Bangkok during 2024&rsquo;s Easter week.</p>

<p>And what a trip it was going to be.</p>

<div class='lr_embed' style='position: relative; padding-bottom: 50%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;'><iframe id='iframe' src='https://lightroom.adobe.com/embed/shares/5b61e31c72b04975af49923476739fc9/slideshow?background_color=%232D2D2D&color=%23999999' frameborder='0'style='width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;' ></iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris 2016: a photo story]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/03/paris-2016-a-photo-story/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T23:16:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/03/paris-2016-a-photo-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah, Paris. The City of Light. So much has been written about this beautiful city that I feel there’s nothing else I could add that would do it justice.</p>

<p>But it’s not just writers that are fascinated by Paris’s unique atmosphere. Au contraire. All kinds of artists have been inspired to produce their best work by this enchanting city: painters, photographers, actors, musicians, you name it. There’s just something special about it that seems to wake our imagination like perhaps no other place on this planet.</p>

<p>Paris is one of a kind, so when Miriam and I decided a few weeks ago that we would be spending New Year’s Eve there, my brain was immediately filled to the brink with wild expectations.</p>

<p>Since a regular article wouldn’t be appropriate for such a wonderful city, I came up with something that&rsquo;s new for the site: a photo story.</p>

<p>Just follow the title link to get to the beginning. I do hope you’ll enjoy it as much as we did.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1488/24475046170_c40288bc10_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
