<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photo essays | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/photo-essays/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-01-25T13:38:34+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A photo essay of the Alhambra]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/01/a-photo-essay-of-the-alhambra/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-01T17:29:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/01/a-photo-essay-of-the-alhambra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This summer I went to Granada to attend a friend’s wedding, and I had a chance to spend a day visiting the Alhambra. This photo essay is a collection of some of the best images I shot that day.</p>

<p>If you’ve never heard of the Alhambra, trust me when I tell you it is one of the most magical places on Earth. Or better yet, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> and <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/photo-essays/the-alhambra/">see for yourself</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="panorama">
<img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5750/31406887006_70442ea85e_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter Hiking in Navacerrada]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/03/11/winter-hiking-in-navacerrada/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T13:18:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/03/11/winter-hiking-in-navacerrada</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Sunday I went hiking in Navacerrada, one of the tallest mountain passes in central Spain. It’s a gorgeous place, covered by pine forests as far as the eye can see, and it’s perfect for hiking, even in the winter.</p>

<p>This photo essay on <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> tells the story of how the day went, along with some nice landscape shots. It was a fantastic experience, and one I can’t recommend enough.</p>

<p>If you’re ready for a micro adventure, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/photo-essays/winter-hiking-in-navacerrada/">the full photo essay</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Madrid’s food markets: San Antón]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/09/17/madrids-food-markets-san-anton/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-17T16:13:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/09/17/madrids-food-markets-san-anton</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My second photo essay was published today at <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> and once again, Madrid is its protagonist. This time around we take a look at one of Madrid’s recently renovated food markets, San Antón:</p>

<blockquote><p>Located in the centric quarter of Chueca and with 70 years of history, this impressive three-story building, known among the locals as <em>Mercado de San Antón</em>, has grown to become one of the most popular hangout places in town in recent years.</p></blockquote>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5633/21465768036_1e63c04ccd_o.jpg" title="Mercado de San Antón"/>
    <img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/586/20869272704_e7c0731c10_o.jpg" title="Mercado de San Antón"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This essay is the first in a 3-part series on Madrid’s food markets. Over the past few years, many of Madrid’s old markets have been deeply transformed, incorporating most of the features traditionally found in bars and even restaurants into their spacious layouts. While it may seem like an odd combination at first, the truth is that food markets are surprisingly great places for spending some time with friends, family or your significant other.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/578/21305062549_edc7951c61_o.jpg" title="Mercado de San Antón"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It’s no secret we love our food here in Spain, and these markets provide a great opportunity to taste several different bite-sized specialties from all over the Spanish geography. And of course, you can accompany these delicious treats with your beverage of choice, just the way we like it.</p>

<p>If that sounds awesome to you — and I promise you, it is — head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> to check it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A photo essay of Madrid’s El Rastro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/27/a-photo-essay-of-madrids-el-rastro/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-27T23:33:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/08/27/a-photo-essay-of-madrids-el-rastro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>El Rastro is Madrid’s traditional flea market, a place where there’s literally nothing that’s not for sale. Last Sunday I brought the camera with me and tried to capture some of its unique essence:</p>

<blockquote><p>With almost 300 years of history — early mentions of it date back to 1740 — El Rastro is probably the oldest flea market in all of Spain. Loved and visited by locals and tourists alike, El Rastro is as much an experience as it is a market. Everything has a price here, even a few things that really, <em>really</em> shouldn’t.</p></blockquote>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5735/20925048892_3356ae3e4c_o.jpg"/>
    <img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5690/20925049812_292d0dc1d1_o.jpg"/>
    <img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5748/20746736580_5dffdaf074_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>I really love El Rastro. If you’re ever stopping by Madrid, I can’t recommend visiting enough. You may not end up buying anything, but you’ll definitely go home with a couple interesting stories to tell, at the very least.</p>

<p>Head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> to check out <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/photo-essays/madrids-el-rastro/">the entire photo-story</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5824/20925050772_cbfac129d2_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
