<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tv | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/tv/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-06-21T17:45:31+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a list of American TV shows that have been renewed for another season — and the ones that haven’t]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/08/heres-a-list-of-american-tv-shows-that-have-been-renewed-for-another-season-and-the-ones-that-havent/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-08T22:13:06+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/08/heres-a-list-of-american-tv-shows-that-have-been-renewed-for-another-season-and-the-ones-that-havent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are so many excellent TV shows out there these days that it’s virtually impossible to keep track of everything. I don’t know about you, but the way I manage is by selecting a few shows — no more than five — to watch as they air, and leaving the rest for later binge-watching.</p>

<p>That usually works well for me, but if there’s something I hate is spending a few weekends binge-watching a show and getting really into it, only to find out it was canceled later.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>So, if you were wondering, this might be a good time to start watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3475734/">Marvel’s <em>Agent Carter</em></a>, and a <em>really</em> bad time to start watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3487382/"><em>Forever</em></a>.</p>

<p>And yes, I chose wrong both times.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2296682/">Dracula</a></em>, I’m looking at you.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How ‘Daredevil’ is Unlike Anything Marvel Has Done So Far]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/13/how-daredevil-is-unlike-anything-marvel-has-done-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-13T20:24:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/13/how-daredevil-is-unlike-anything-marvel-has-done-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>John Gholson, on the new Marvel TV Show that debuted on Netflix on Friday, April 10th:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong><em>Daredevil</em></strong> is unlike anything Marvel Studios has done. We got a look at the first five episodes of the 13-part season, and it’s nothing like the Marvel Studios films nor the spin-off shows from ABC. This is great news. This is a low-key, performance-driven crime drama, where the episodes don’t follow a tidy formula nor aim to move <em>Daredevil</em> kids meal toys. It’s street-level and human and it’s going to make a lot of fans of “ol hornhead” very, <em>very</em> happy.</p>

<p><em>Daredevil</em>, missing the luxury of a $200 million budget like its big-screen peers, is shot like an indie crime film (or a low-budget horror movie &ndash; lots of darkened rooms with one sickly amber key light) and makes the best use of its greatest resource, a talented cast. All of the players, from Deborah Ann Woll as the complex, troubled Karen Page to Bob Gunton as the smarmy “Owl” Leland Owlsley, command the screen with the same level of interest as the title character himself.</p></blockquote>

<p><em>Daredevil</em> always struck me as one of the most interesting Marvel characters, and also one of the most underrated. Unfortunately, the completely forgettable <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0287978/?ref_=fn_al_tt_2">2003 movie starring Ben Affleck</a> did more harm than good to the character’s popularity. Now it looks like we’re finally getting a decent show that makes the horned hero justice for a change.</p>

<p>If like me, you’ve been patiently waiting for <em>the man without fear</em> to return to the screen, it looks like this new show is everything we hoped for and more, and it “only” took 12 years. Oh well, if they don’t screw it up again, it’ll have been well worth the wait.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HBO reveals first teaser of True Detective’s Season Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/10/hbo-reveals-first-teaser-of-true-detective-s-season-two/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-10T19:56:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/10/hbo-reveals-first-teaser-of-true-detective-s-season-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It looks good. Very good:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4OfU7CGY5DQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>My first impressions are twofold:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I like the new cast, particularly Rachel McAdams as the female lead, and I&rsquo;ve had a soft spot for Kelly Reilly ever since I first saw her in <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0283900/"><em>The Spanish Apartment</em></a>. The male characters are also well cast in my opinion. I’m not so sure about Taylor Kitsch, but I’m a huge fan of Colin Farrell and Vince Vaughn.</p></li>
<li><p>That’s all well and good, but we were promised a new season featuring two female leads, and in the end we got three male and one female as the lead characters — Kelly Reilly was cast in a supporting role, apparently. I’m not saying that’s necessarily bad, but I was already expecting a different type of story and to be honest, I was quite excited about it.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>But like I said, it looks <em>very</em> good. I can’t wait.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
