<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: politics | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T20:08:02+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wait But Why: it’s going to be okay]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/11/10/its-going-to-be-okay/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-10T17:31:29+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/11/10/its-going-to-be-okay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tim Urban:</p>

<blockquote><p>People vote for hope and change when they’re in pain. When I watched the election last night, I didn’t see a bunch of assholes voting to be hateful, I saw a bunch of people going through a lot of suffering hoping for something better.</p>

<p>Which is why, if you’re a Hillary supporter, in addition to this being a time for disappointment and frustration, it should also be a time for reflection. Half your country voted for Trump. Over 50 million people—people with kids and parents and jobs and dogs and calendars on their wall with piano lessons and doctors appointments and birthday parties written in the squares. Full, three-dimensional people who voted for what they hope will be a better future for themselves and their family.</p></blockquote>

<p>I’m not an American, but I have a deep love of this country. I’m still dealing with a fair amount of anger over the result of the election myself, and I needed to read this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venezuelan opposition claims a rare victory]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/07/venezuelan-opposition-claims-a-rare-victory/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-07T18:31:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/07/venezuelan-opposition-claims-a-rare-victory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>William Neuman, reporting from Caracas, Venezuela, for <em>The New York Times</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Government opponents surged to a rare victory here on Sunday in key congressional elections framed by the country’s deep economic crisis, claiming a legislative majority for the first time in years and handing a significant setback to the heirs of former President <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/c/hugo_chavez/index.html?inline=nyt-per">Hugo Chávez</a> and his socialist-inspired movement.</p>

<p>The victory significantly alters the political balance in this deeply divided country and augurs a power struggle between the long-marginalized opposition and the government of President Nicolás Maduro, the successor and disciple of Mr. Chávez.</p></blockquote>

<p>Ever since Hugo Chávez was first elected President — 17 years ago yesterday, to the day — the National Assembly had been controlled by the government. This is a historic victory for the opposition, who will now hold the necessary votes to pass several long-awaited reforms, as well as to free their political prisoners, most notably <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leopoldo_L%C3%B3pez">Leopoldo López</a>, who was thrown in jail two years ago and is still serving the remainder of a 13-year prison sentence.</p>

<p>I don’t usually voice my political concerns here, but in this case I’ll say this: my girlfriend is from Venezuela. She moved to Spain in 2010 looking for a way out, but the rest of her family remains over there. For five years now she’s had to watch from afar as her own country and her loved ones suffered the consequences of a corrupt system. Today, she and many others — in Venezuela and all over the world — finally have a reason to celebrate, and to remain hopeful. And I couldn’t be happier for all of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ending Greece’s bleeding]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/06/ending-greeces-bleeding/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-06T10:31:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/06/ending-greeces-bleeding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Paul Krugman, writing for <em>The New York Times</em> on the outcome of the historic referendum that took place in Greece yesterday:</p>

<blockquote><p>But the campaign of bullying — the attempt to terrify Greeks by cutting off bank financing and threatening general chaos, all with the almost open goal of pushing the current leftist government out of office — was a shameful moment in a Europe that claims to believe in democratic principles. It would have set a terrible precedent if that campaign had succeeded, even if the creditors were making sense.</p>

<p>What’s more, they weren’t. The truth is that Europe’s self-styled technocrats are like medieval doctors who insisted on bleeding their patients — and when their treatment made the patients sicker, demanded even more bleeding. A “yes” vote in Greece would have condemned the country to years more of suffering under policies that haven’t worked and in fact, given <a href="http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/07/05/austerity-arithmetic/">the arithmetic</a>, can’t work: austerity probably shrinks the economy faster than it reduces debt, so that all the suffering serves no purpose. The landslide victory of the “no” side offers at least a chance for an escape from this trap.</p></blockquote>

<p>Yesterday, the Greek people overwhelmingly said no to fear, and no to the failed austerity policies of the Eurogroup. This was a historic decision with the potential to alter the course of the entire EU, and its first consequences are already being felt.</p>

<p>That said, I don’t necessarily agree with Krugman’s opinion that Greece leaving the Euro would be “<em>the best of bad options</em>”. In my opinion — and I’m admittedly no expert — there’s plenty of wiggle room to negotiate a viable deal within the confines of the Eurozone, but in order for that to happen, Greece’s creditors must shoulder their fair share of responsibility for what’s happened.</p>

<p>Alexis Tsipras’s government seems keen on reaching an agreement that would secure Greece’s future in the Eurozone, even going so far as <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/jul/06/greek-finance-minister-yanis-varoufakis-resigns-despite-referendum-no-vote">to sacrifice their own finance minister</a>, Yanis Varoufakis, in order to facilitate negotiations despite having won the referendum. The Greeks have done their part, now it’s time for the rest of the Eurogroup to pick up the ball.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Stiglitz: how I would vote in the Greek referendum]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/30/joseph-stiglitz-how-i-would-vote-in-the-greek-referendum/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-30T17:40:49+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/30/joseph-stiglitz-how-i-would-vote-in-the-greek-referendum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Joseph Stiglitz, one of the 2001 Nobel prize winners in economics, writing for <em>The Guardian</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>It is startling that the troika has refused to accept responsibility for any of this or admit how bad its forecasts and models have been. But what is even more surprising is that Europe’s leaders have not even <em>learned</em>. The troika is <em>still</em> demanding that Greece achieve a primary budget surplus (excluding interest payments) of 3.5% of GDP by 2018.</p>

<p>Economists around the world have condemned that target as punitive, because aiming for it will inevitably result in a deeper downturn. Indeed, even if Greece’s debt is restructured beyond anything imaginable, the country will remain in depression if voters there commit to the troika’s target in the snap referendum to be held this weekend.</p></blockquote>

<p>He goes on to argue that a yes vote would probably result in many years — possibly even <em>decades</em> — of sustained economic depression and financial ruin for Greece. As for the possibility of a no vote:</p>

<blockquote><p>By contrast, a no vote would at least open the possibility that Greece, with its strong democratic tradition, might grasp its destiny in its own hands. Greeks might gain the opportunity to <a href="http://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/new-beginning-for-greece-eurozone-exit-by-dennis-j--snower-2015-06">shape a future</a> that, though perhaps not as prosperous as the past, is far more hopeful than the unconscionable torture of the present.</p>

<p>I know how I would vote.</p></blockquote>

<p>In any case, today Greece <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2015/jun/30/greek-debt-crisis-day-of-decision-for-tsipras">issued a last-minute proposal</a> asking for a new 2-year bailout and some debt-relief. Should this proposal be accepted, Sunday’s referendum could potentially be rendered moot, possibly even canceled. The Eurogroup will hold <a href="https://twitter.com/J_Dijsselbloem/status/615890106814173184">an extraordinary session</a> today at 19:00 Brussels time to discuss the offer. The deadline expires at midnight.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[United States Supreme Court declares same-sex marriage a right in all 50 states]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/26/united-states-supreme-court-declares-same-sex-marriage-a-right-in-all-50-states/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-26T16:38:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/26/united-states-supreme-court-declares-same-sex-marriage-a-right-in-all-50-states</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adam Liptak, writing for <em>The New York Times</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>In a long-sought victory for the gay rights movement, the <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/organizations/s/supreme_court/index.html?inline=nyt-org">Supreme Court</a> ruled on Friday that the Constitution guarantees a nationwide right to <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/subjects/s/same_sex_marriage/index.html?inline=nyt-classifier">same-sex marriage</a>.</p>

<p>Justice Anthony M. Kennedy wrote the majority opinion in the 5 to 4 decision. He was joined by the court’s four more liberal justices.</p></blockquote>

<p>Huge day. This calls for a celebration.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
