<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: digtital life | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/digtital-life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2024-04-01T15:17:25+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marco Arment on the future of the dumbwatch]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/20/marco-arment-on-the-future-of-the-dumbwatch/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-20T22:59:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/20/marco-arment-on-the-future-of-the-dumbwatch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Apple Watch isn’t just a watch, interchangeable like any other. It’s an entire mobile computing and communication platform, and a significant enhancement to the smartphone, which is probably the most successful, ubiquitous, and disruptive electronic device in history.</p>

<p>Once you’re accustomed to wearing one, going out for a night without your Apple Watch is going to feel like going out without your phone.</p></blockquote>

<p>I think his reasoning is absolutely spot-on, but I disagree with his conclusion. Yes, going out without your Apple Watch will feel a lot like going out without your phone, except <em>your phone will still be in your pocket.</em> There&rsquo;s nothing important you’re left unable to do by leaving the watch behind, because you can just use your phone instead.</p>

<p>Actually, for the same reason I almost never pull my phone out of my pocket when I&rsquo;m out with friends, I believe I’d be extremely likely to <em>want</em> to leave the Apple Watch at home when I go out. I don&rsquo;t want to be interrupted by a million notifications all night long when I just want to have a good time and relax with some friends.</p>

<p>So, while I definitely appreciate everything the Apple Watch can do for me during the day, at night I still see myself wearing my nice dumbwatch instead. And if there&rsquo;s something I really need to do I can just take my phone out, get it over with, put it back in my pocket and go back to my whisky.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
