<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: coffee | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/coffee/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T18:33:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Ascaso i-Mini coffee grinder]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/07/05/the-ascaso-i-mini-coffee-grinder-review/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-05T18:45:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/07/05/the-ascaso-i-mini-coffee-grinder-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the <a href="http://amzn.to/29kjlYz">Ascaso i-Mini</a> coffee grinder was published today on <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>. I’ve owned the i-Mini for over three years now, and it’s one impressive little device.</p>

<p>If you’re at all interested in coffee, you probably know that good, high-end burr grinders are expensive, with the three or four most popular models costing between $350-$1,000. Unless you’re an enthusiast, that’s a lot of money to drop on a grinder.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <a class="fancybox" rel="galleryAscaso" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7124/28005597582_44c8300f3b_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7124/28005597582_44c8300f3b_o.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<pre><code>&lt;a class="fancybox" rel="galleryAscaso" href="https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7315/28030744171_9d02cfa185_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7315/28030744171_9d02cfa185_o.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>

<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>What’s remarkable about the i-Mini is that it can do almost everything these high-end grinders do, but it does it while keeping the price well under $300. In a community where fancy devices almost invariably carry a hefty premium, that’s no small feat.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about the Ascaso i-Mini grinder, head on over to <em><a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/the-ascaso-i-mini-coffee-grinder-review/">Tools &amp; Toys</a></em> for the full review.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <a class="fancybox" rel="galleryAscaso" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7432/27493405733_62a4cd4e61_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7432/27493405733_62a4cd4e61_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A fussy way to make coffee]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/21/a-fussy-way-to-make-coffee/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-21T18:47:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/21/a-fussy-way-to-make-coffee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/2015/01/21/when-used-properly/">Speaking of</a> AeroPress, Chase Gallagher’s review covers all the basics, including this wonderful <a href="http://vimeo.com/40980282">Sandwich video</a>:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/40980282 "></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>Charming, as ever. Here’s how Gallagher describes the process of using the AeroPress:</p>

<blockquote><p>Enter&hellip; the Aeropress. First, it’s the basic principle of the press pot. But they ad a syringe-style plunger (which creates serious air pressure) and the cleanliness of a paper filter. You measure out your grounds, add hot water, steep, press. That’s it. Clean up? Unscrew the filter assembly and plunge further and your grounds and filter go into the garbage (which automatically wipes clean the cylinder). A quick rinse and you’re set for a nice, gentle air dry.</p></blockquote>

<p>I’ve known about the AeroPress for a while now but honestly, I never felt enough interest to try it. Sure, I appreciate the simplicity, but my home espresso machine works perfectly and I’m just too set in my ways when it comes to making coffee. That said, the other day I walked into my local coffee shop to buy some freshly roasted beans and sure enough, the AeroPress was there, in all its plastic exuberance. I’m usually not one to believe in signs from the Universe, but I may have to give it a try, after all.</p>

<p>I’ll keep you posted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When used properly]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/21/when-used-properly/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-21T18:15:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/21/when-used-properly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Allen Pike has some advice for the makers of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AeroPress">AeroPress</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Side by side on a shelf with a more familiar coffee machine or french press, our beloved plunger is going to lose out. It’s unattractively packaged, strange, and its price seems too good to be true. I suspect the testimonials are intended to make it seem less weird, but beside the clean lines of a Bodum’s box they do the opposite. Shoppers looking for a gift are so turned off by AeroPress’ package that there is a market for <a href="http://shop.squaremilecoffee.com/products/aeropress-gift-box">aftermarket gift boxes</a>. A sad state for a great product.</p></blockquote>

<p>Sometimes it’s hard not to judge a book by its cover.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
