<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tools & toys | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/tools-and-toys/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-13T10:46:32+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the leather Bond Street by ONA]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/08/24/a-review-of-the-ona-bond-street-camera-bag/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-24T19:05:04+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/08/24/a-review-of-the-ona-bond-street-camera-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the leather Bond Street camera bag by ONA was published last month on Tools &amp; Toys. I’ve been slow to link to it because, well, life got in the way, but here it is.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36642414161_bf9b1e4b52_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This has become an instant favorite of mine. It’s a bag I use every single day, not just to carry my camera, but far more important stuff: my glucose meter and insulin pen. I had been searching for a stylish bag of the right size, and the Bond Street is just what I’d been looking for. Not too small, and not too big. Just <em>right</em>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/36734425326_901dc2a578_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>If you’re looking for not just a camera bag, but a great everyday bag, period, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/a-review-of-the-leather-bond-street-by-ona/">the full review</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sony Zeiss Distagon T* FE 35mm f/1.4 lens review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/03/28/the-sony-zeiss-distagon-t-star-fe-35mm-f-slash-1-dot-4-lens-review/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-28T20:56:35+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/03/28/the-sony-zeiss-distagon-t-star-fe-35mm-f-slash-1-dot-4-lens-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the stunning <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00U29GNBO&amp;uk=B00UJRSOB6&amp;es=B00UJRSOB6">Sony Zeiss Distagon T* FE 35mm f/1.4 ZA</a> lens was published today on <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>.</p>

<p>This review is a special one for me. I’d been after this lens since it was announced a few years ago, and ever since I finally got it this summer I’ve been fighting the urge to write my hot take on it.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/33705830965_9a23212ac9_k.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>It would have been fun, but this time I felt like I needed to use the lens for a good, long while before putting my thoughts out there. Rushing to judgement is never a good idea, and I really didn’t want to spoil this one because I had a feeling it was going to be one of my all-time favorite lenses.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/32892188043_cffa3c8af9_k.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Now, after six months or so I finally feel prepared to review this lens, and I’m happy to say my take on it remains as enthusiastic as it was on day one. The Sony Zeiss 35mm f/1.4 is an absolute stunner of a lens, and I’m so glad I bit the bullet and bought it despite the steep $1,600 price.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/33664787686_b38ead96ac_k.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>This is also a special review because it’s a pretty obvious love letter to Madrid — more so than any of my previous reviews. I’ve never been shy about telling people just how great a city Madrid is, but this is one of the first times when I feel like I’m actually able to show them. And it feels <em>great</em>.</p>

<p>If you have some time, grab yourself a nice beverage and head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/the-sony-zeiss-distagon-t-fe-35mm-f1-4-za-lens-review/">the full review</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="panorama">
    <img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/33549656222_c1de241b51_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Think Tank Retrospective 6 camera bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/01/09/a-review-of-the-think-tank-retrospective-6-camera-bag/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-09T12:23:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2017/01/09/a-review-of-the-think-tank-retrospective-6-camera-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My last review of 2016 was about one of the best camera bags I’ve ever used: the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01D2CTJVI&amp;uk=B01D2CTJVI&amp;es=B01D2CTJVI">Think Tank Retrospective 6</a>.</p>

<p>Now, long-time readers may know that I’ve owned the smaller <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B004XYZI0Q&amp;uk=B004XYZI0Q&amp;es=B004XYZI0Q">Retrospective 5</a> for a few years already. That means I knew what to expect from the new bag going in, and I’m happy to say it didn’t disappoint.</p>

<p>The Retrospective 6 has all of the strengths of the 5, but its larger size makes it a lot more versatile. I can easily carry a full kit with it, and the entire package is somehow still light enough on my shoulder that I don’t get tired, unlike my previous experience with the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01093D4HI&amp;uk=B00AEB3PPC">leather Brixton</a> by ONA.</p>

<p>The Retrospective 6 has quickly become my go-to bag, both for everyday use and for travel. That’s no small feat, I assure you. If you want to know more about it, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for the <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/a-review-of-the-think-tank-retrospective-6-camera-bag/">full review</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A photo essay of the Alhambra]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/01/a-photo-essay-of-the-alhambra/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-01T17:29:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/01/a-photo-essay-of-the-alhambra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This summer I went to Granada to attend a friend’s wedding, and I had a chance to spend a day visiting the Alhambra. This photo essay is a collection of some of the best images I shot that day.</p>

<p>If you’ve never heard of the Alhambra, trust me when I tell you it is one of the most magical places on Earth. Or better yet, head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> and <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/photo-essays/the-alhambra/">see for yourself</a>.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="panorama">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/31406887006_70442ea85e_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A review of the Beoplay H5 wireless earphones by B&amp;O PLAY]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/11/29/a-review-of-the-b-and-o-beoplay-h5-wireless-earphones/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-29T18:07:33+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/11/29/a-review-of-the-b-and-o-beoplay-h5-wireless-earphones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My review of the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01G491MSY&amp;uk=B01G491MSY&amp;es=B01G491MSY">Beoplay H5 wireless earphones</a> by B&amp;O PLAY was published today at <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>. These were very tricky to review, because as much as I love their <em>awesome</em> sound quality and their stunning design, they do have a fair number of quirks.</p>

<p>If you’re in the market for wireless earphones, you really should give the Beoplay H5 a good look. Head on over to <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em> for <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/a-review-of-the-beoplay-h5-wireless-earphones/">the full review</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
