<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gaming | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/gaming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-12T17:13:34+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The Last of Us Part II’ and ‘Uncharted: The Lost Legacy’ announced at PSX 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/05/the-last-of-us-part-ii-and-uncharted-the-lost-legacy-announced-at-psx-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-05T00:15:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/12/05/the-last-of-us-part-ii-and-uncharted-the-lost-legacy-announced-at-psx-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I must have been living under a rock all weekend, because I only just now came across these announcements. I can’t even begin to describe how excited I am about this one in particular:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/W2Wnvvj33Wo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p><a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00JK00S0S&amp;uk=B00LWRSJB2&amp;es=B00JLB8M1I"><em>The Last of Us</em></a> is hands down my favorite video game of all time, and its long-awaited sequel is looking every bit as awesome as I had hoped.</p>

<p>If you want to know more about the game, take a look at this PSX panel featuring Neil Druckmann, Ashley Johnson, Troy Baker, and Game Informer’s Andy McNamara. Great stuff:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gF1EQAtaZEo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>If that wasn’t enough to make your day, you’re in luck, because we also got <a href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2016/12/03/uncharted-the-lost-legacy-arrives-next-year-on-ps4/">a new <em>Uncharted</em> game announcement</a>. While technically a DLC, <em>Uncharted: The Lost Legacy</em> will be available as a standalone game purchase, and stars one of the most popular characters in the franchise — perhaps the one big character who didn’t appear on <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00GODZYNA&amp;uk=B00KW6W8VQ&amp;es=B00JZPEHCS"><em>Uncharted 4</em></a>. Can you guess who it is?</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/PZjx5ao7alw" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>This one’s also looking <em>very</em> impressive. I particularly love the change in tone and mechanics, with a lot more sneaking around. I think it’s going to be a fantastic game. Of course, there was also a PSX panel about this one, featuring Sid Shuman, the creative team at Naughty Dog, and actors Claudia Black (Chloe) and Laura Bailey (Nadine).</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4xbs1j1UcMA" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>Now, if we could just fast forward a couple years into the future, to a day when both of these games have already been released, that’d be great, thanksverymuch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncharted 4 is the best (and possibly last) game of its kind]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/10/uncharted-4-is-the-best-and-possibly-last-game-of-its-kind/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-10T19:25:17+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/05/10/uncharted-4-is-the-best-and-possibly-last-game-of-its-kind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chris Plante makes an astute observation about <em>Uncharted 4</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p><em>Uncharted 4</em> as a work of film is good, great even, and no less modern in tone and structure than what’s playing on television, let alone at a movie theater. And its minimalistic gameplay, early on, is just enough to keep the player engaged without distracting them from dialogue, which does the heavy lifting of playing catch-up on a story roughly 27 hours in. Were it a film, <em>Uncharted 4</em> could make a handsome sum in royalties for the number of times it will undoubtedly appear at Hollywood conferences and summits, where it will be picked apart for lessons on how to create the future of interactive cinema.</p></blockquote>

<p>And later:</p>

<blockquote><p>In <em>Uncharted 4</em>, the series’ new directors, Neil Druckmann and Bruce Straley, have done what David O. Russell originally sought out to do. Their <em>Uncharted</em> is respectful to the core themes of franchise, but rather than design a game that people would want to play and replay, they produced something that will be watched and re-watched. Druckmann and Straley made a fantastic <em>Uncharted</em> movie, and, in some perverse fashion, the first great film adapted from the world of games. That it arrives in an era of Twitch, where watching others play video games online is nearly as common, <em>Uncharted</em>, intentionally or not, has finally, and cosmically, aligned with industry trends.</p></blockquote>

<p>There’s no doubt the games in the <em>Uncharted</em> series are cinematic experiences just as much as they are gaming experiences. That said, I don’t think this creative trend is going to end anytime soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://amzn.to/1rRahR2"><em>Uncharted 4</em> was released today</a>, and it’s probably going to be the gaming industry’s best and most ambitious effort to date. This is the experience that will define the next generation of games. If you still haven’t got a copy, I don’t know what you’re waiting for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making of Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/07/the-making-of-uncharted-4-a-thiefs-end/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-07T17:44:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/04/07/the-making-of-uncharted-4-a-thiefs-end</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great documentary on the making of the upcoming — and final — game in the Uncharted series. I got goosebumps watching this:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bbx8iFxtrVU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>Can’t wait for the actual game to be released.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncharted 4: A Thief’s End trailer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/25/uncharted-4-a-thiefs-end-trailer/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-25T18:49:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/25/uncharted-4-a-thiefs-end-trailer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh boy, April 26 can’t come soon enough:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hh5HV4iic1Y" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony at E3 2015: the 11 most important announcements]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/16/sony-at-e3-2015-the-11-most-important-announcements/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-16T18:09:07+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/16/sony-at-e3-2015-the-11-most-important-announcements</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adi Robertson covers Sony’s announcements in yesterday’s E3 keynote for <em>The Verge</em>. There are plenty of awesome games coming, most notably among which are <em>The Last Guardian</em>, <em>Uncharted 4</em>, <em>Shenmue 3</em> and the long, long awaited remake of <em>Final Fantasy VII</em>, which is one of my all-time personal top-2 games:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Kznek1uNVsg" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>It appears Sony is throwing the kitchen sink at the PS4, and I couldn’t be happier. I suppose one could argue that these are all well-established franchises and that the lack of some high-profile new and original releases is somewhat worrying. Then again, any chance I can get to kick Sephiroth’s treacherous ass all over again is fine by me.</p>

<p>There are still a few months to go before any of these titles are available, and some of them won’t show up for well over a year but if they live up to their names, it’ll be well worth the wait.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
