<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-05T12:24:58+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thailand 2024: a photo story]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2024/04/01/thailand-2024-a-photo-story/"/>
    <updated>2024-04-01T14:38:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2024/04/01/thailand-2024-a-photo-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a very special trip for me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been wanting to visit Thailand ever since January of 2019, when I first went to Hawaii with my life-long best friend Virginia and our friend Cristina. That probably still stands as the best trip of my life, and I find that&rsquo;s an excellent reason to just keep traveling.</p>

<p>Virginia and I both love traveling, and we even have a matching travel-inspired tattoo that celebrates our friendship and our shared love of discovering new places and cultures. After Hawaii, we both quickly agreed that Thailand would be a fitting way to follow up from that once-in-a-lifetime experience, so we planned to spend 2020&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s Eve there. Unfortunately, as we all know, the pandemic happened, and we were forced to postpone the trip until international travel was reasonably safe again. Then life got in the way, as it always does, and we haven&rsquo;t really had a chance to make it work until now.</p>

<p>This time our friends Sofia and Aurora joined us on the adventure, and the four of us booked a trip to Bangkok during 2024&rsquo;s Easter week.</p>

<p>And what a trip it was going to be.</p>

<div class='lr_embed' style='position: relative; padding-bottom: 50%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;'><iframe id='iframe' src='https://lightroom.adobe.com/embed/shares/5b61e31c72b04975af49923476739fc9/slideshow?background_color=%232D2D2D&color=%23999999' frameborder='0'style='width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;' ></iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris 2016: a photo story]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/03/paris-2016-a-photo-story/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T23:16:52+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/02/03/paris-2016-a-photo-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah, Paris. The City of Light. So much has been written about this beautiful city that I feel there’s nothing else I could add that would do it justice.</p>

<p>But it’s not just writers that are fascinated by Paris’s unique atmosphere. Au contraire. All kinds of artists have been inspired to produce their best work by this enchanting city: painters, photographers, actors, musicians, you name it. There’s just something special about it that seems to wake our imagination like perhaps no other place on this planet.</p>

<p>Paris is one of a kind, so when Miriam and I decided a few weeks ago that we would be spending New Year’s Eve there, my brain was immediately filled to the brink with wild expectations.</p>

<p>Since a regular article wouldn’t be appropriate for such a wonderful city, I came up with something that&rsquo;s new for the site: a photo story.</p>

<p>Just follow the title link to get to the beginning. I do hope you’ll enjoy it as much as we did.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/24475046170_c40288bc10_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you identify the world cities from their 'naked' metro maps?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/01/can-you-identify-the-world-cities-from-their-naked-metro-maps/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-01T15:20:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/01/can-you-identify-the-world-cities-from-their-naked-metro-maps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GORUCK launches new 34-liter GR2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/24/goruck-launches-new-34-liter-gr2/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-24T18:34:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/24/goruck-launches-new-34-liter-gr2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today GORUCK launched a second version of my favorite travel backpack, the GR2. This new version is slightly smaller, having a 34-liter volume as opposed to 40 liters in the old one, and it’s designed to be more comfortable for shorter people to wear. I love my GR2 to death but I have to admit if I were buying mine today, I’d probably go with the smaller one.</p>

<p>The original GR2 can be a bit too much for some people. My girlfriend, for example, can’t pick it up when it’s full, and I find it a bit tiring after a few hours on my back. I don’t know how much of a difference 6 liters will make in practical use, but if you were slightly put off by the gargantuan size of the original GR2, now you have another choice.</p>

<p>That said, I don’t think this is about reducing weight, but increasing comfort due to the way the ruck sits on your back instead. It’s all about the shape of the ruck, rather than the size itself: the original GR2 is a pretty tall backpack, and sometimes it bumps against my butt when I’m wearing it. Personally I never found this to be uncomfortable enough to be a problem in real world usage, but of course your mileage may vary.</p>

<p>Here’s a couple of pictures from <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/reviews/the-goruck-gr2/">my review of the original GR2</a> over at <em>Tools &amp; Toys</em>, showing the ruck on me and my girlfriend for reference:</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18500612853_bece9111e7_o.jpg" title="GORUCK GR2 review over at Tools & Toys"></p>




<p class="extra-width"><img src="http://www.analogsenses.com/assets/images/flickr/18933885638_4fd0a3cb62_o.jpg" title="GORUCK GR2 review over at Tools & Toys"></p>




<p class="photo-credit">Top: original 40-liter GR2 on my back (5&#8217;7”). Bottom: original 40-liter GR2 on my girlfriend&#8217;s back (5&#8217;5”).</p>


<p>The recommended sizing guide goes: if you’re under 6 feet tall, go for the 34-liter version. 6 feet or taller, go with the 40-liter version. That seems a bit extreme to me. I’m 5&#8217;7&#8221; and I’d say I’m at the limit where the backpack is still reasonably comfortable to wear. Again, your mileage may vary, so please take these comments with a grain of salt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dan Moren travels with the Apple Watch]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/29/dan-moren-travels-with-the-apple-watch/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-29T18:12:07+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/05/29/dan-moren-travels-with-the-apple-watch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interesting observation by Dan Moren, writing at <em>Six Colors:</em></p>

<blockquote><p>But more to the point, <em>not a single person on my trip commented on the Apple Watch</em>. Despite my generally wearing short-sleeved shirts, which left the Watch clearly visible, I’ve concluded that most people’s brains simply register something worn on the wrist as a watch, and don’t bother giving it much further attention. (I’d also guess that as the Apple Watch isn’t on sale in Portugal—a country which doesn’t have any Apple Stores—there just isn’t much awareness of it as a product.)</p>

<p>But the more I thought about it, the more I realized that the Apple Watch wasn’t really any more of an opportunity theft than your average nice wristwatch. In fact, it’s arguably less attractive in many cases, given that mine is not <a href="http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/05/all-that-glitters-is-not-pure-gold/">made from gold</a>, and is far less valuable—and, to be honest, once parted with me, less <em>usable</em>—than an expensive luxury watch.</p></blockquote>

<p>One of the worst parts of being an early adopter of Apple devices is that you can get a lot of unwanted attention in the first few months and judging by what other reviewers have said, the Apple Watch appeared to be no different in that regard. I’m happy to see that this is not the case for everyone, or perhaps not the case everywhere.</p>

<p>However, there’s one caveat to this: the Apple Watch hasn’t been released in Portugal yet, so there’s no reason for people to be on the lookout for it. The real question is whether this apparent lack of interest will still be the norm after the watch hits Portuguese stores.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
