<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bicycles | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/bicycles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T18:37:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oakley in Residence restores three bicycles and returns them to their lucky owners]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/02/oakley-in-residence-restores-three-bicycles-and-returns-them-to-their-lucky-owners/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-02T16:42:49+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/07/02/oakley-in-residence-restores-three-bicycles-and-returns-them-to-their-lucky-owners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.oakley.com/in-residence">Oakley in Residence</a> is a hybrid between coffee shop and bike workshop that visits different places around the world. Previously based in Los Angeles, Oakley in Residence is now in London, where it will remain until the end of August.</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ihN0E5_UV4A" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>This is clearly a publicity stunt, but a pretty cool one at that. There&rsquo;s nothing quite like the feeling of reuniting with your long-lost bicycle. Kudos to Oakley for coming up with this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyclist films driver eating a bowl of cereal behind the wheel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/18/cyclist-films-driver-eating-a-bowl-of-cereal-behind-the-wheel/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T16:52:47+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/18/cyclist-films-driver-eating-a-bowl-of-cereal-behind-the-wheel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David Williams is a cycling instructor in Surrey, south-west London. He’s known on YouTube as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrWE9AKDjFcf60vApu50STw">Surrey Suburban Cyclist</a>, and he usually rides his bicycle with a camera mounted on his helmet. A few days ago he encountered something out of the ordinary: a middle-aged woman eating a bowl of cereal behind the wheel of her Land Rover. Check out the video:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0elsNDRqLtQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>I’m baffled at the things some people do. I can’t even begin to imagine how that woman could think it was ok for her to do such an incredibly stupid thing.</p>

<p>In related news, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/?title=Fausto_Coppi">Fausto Coppi</a> was not impressed:</p>

<p class="extra-width"><img src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/4/3712/18304785883_7951b6d485_o.jpg" title="Fausto Coppi having coffee and reading the newspaper in the velodrome."/></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do 20mph speed limits actually work?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/do-20mph-speed-limits-actually-work/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-02T20:14:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/do-20mph-speed-limits-actually-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interesting piece by Hayley Birch for <em>The Guardian</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Implicit in all of this is the idea that 20mph speed limits actually work. To reduce casualties they have to reduce speed, but not everyone agrees that they do. Asked whether he thinks Islington’s 20mph speed limits have made any difference, Aidan Farrow, a member of Islington <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/cycling">Cycling</a> Club who cycles thousands of miles on the roads every year, says he doesn’t think so. “My experience is that they’re ignored by many drivers,” he says. “I don’t think they’re enforced and I don’t think that drivers realise they’re there a lot of the time.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Long story short: 20mph zones would be great for improving safety but in reality, most drivers don’t actually respect the speed limit so they’re pretty much useless.</p>

<p>Madrid is a living example of this problem: over the past year many streets in the city have been fitted with 20mph lanes where cyclists have preference, but the reality is that they’ve done very little to improve the situation. Most drivers simply ignore the 20mph signs completely, using those new lanes as if they were regular lanes. Unless the city is willing to start handing out tickets for these infractions, there’s little hope for meaningful change to occur anytime soon.</p>

<p>Via <a href="https://twitter.com/grescoe/status/605799263847653377">Taras Grescoe</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 20 Most Bike-Friendly Cities on the Planet]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/the-20-most-bike-friendly-cities-on-the-planet/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-02T19:18:06+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/the-20-most-bike-friendly-cities-on-the-planet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a great day for bicycle fans out there, as the 2015 edition of <a href="http://copenhagenize.eu/index/index.html">the Copenhagenize Index</a>, which ranks the top-20 most bicycle-friendly cities in the world, was published today. Mikael Colville-Andersen, CEO of Copenhagenize Design Co., wrote a great feature for <em>Wired</em> analyzing the results and explaining how the ranking system works:</p>

<blockquote><p>You can read about <a href="http://copenhagenize.eu/index/criteria.html">our full methodology</a> here, but the key to a top spot is clear. You need serious advocacy, bike facilities, social acceptance, and a general perception that cycling is safe. You get extra points for a higher modal percentage—the share of residents who get around by bike as opposed to car or public transit—and for a 50-50 gender split among cyclists.</p>

<p>Of course, infrastructure is key. In Denmark and the Netherlands, a set of rules has evolved over a century. Tried and tested and proven to work, this established best practice is the model for cities everywhere. It includes making protected, one-way bike lanes that aren’t shared by cars, buses, or pedestrians. It means designing streets to limit the number and speed of cars in city centers, making public spaces safe and welcoming for everyone, not just drivers.</p></blockquote>

<p>This year’s results have been interesting. Focusing on Spain we have Seville, which was ranked an impressive 4th last year but goes down to the 10th position this year, followed in 11th place by Barcelona. These are the only two Spanish cities among the top 20 this year. Clearly, we can — and totally should — do better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salt Lake City Will Have First Protected Bike Intersection in the U.S.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/01/salt-lake-city-will-have-first-protected-bike-intersection-in-the-u-dot-s/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-01T17:46:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/01/salt-lake-city-will-have-first-protected-bike-intersection-in-the-u-dot-s</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jenn Stanley, writing for <em>Next City</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Unlike other cities that <a href="https://nextcity.org/daily/entry/us-city-bike-lanes-bike-safety">currently have</a> or are <a href="http://nextcity.org/daily/entry/boston-plan-protected-bike-lanes">building protected bike lanes</a>, this is the first time a city in the U.S. is building a fully protected intersection.</p>

<p>The city hopes that in addition to aiding cyclists, the new lane will increase local commerce. The area will also feature murals by local artists.</p></blockquote>

<p>Sounds like a very smart move. Check this video detailing the intersection:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gCNJPOYg8G4" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
