<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sports | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/sports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-05T11:52:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Usain Bolt and Michael Phelps: Twin Titans of the Modern Olympics]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/08/13/usain-bolt-and-michael-phelps-twin-titans-of-the-modern-olympics/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-13T19:56:47+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/08/13/usain-bolt-and-michael-phelps-twin-titans-of-the-modern-olympics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great piece by Christopher Clarey over at <em>The New York Times</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Michael Phelps and Bolt have been an Olympic one-two punch since 2008 in Beijing, where Bolt emerged to tear up the track while Phelps was already an absolute ruler in the pool.</p>

<p>On Saturday they will overlap briefly once more, with Phelps, now 31, finishing up one of the most remarkable meets of his career, and with Bolt, fast approaching 30, launching his meet with the first round of the 100 meters.</p></blockquote>

<p>What a generation of athletes. In case it wasn’t obvious, you’ll find me glued to my television both tonight and tomorrow night. If you’re coming over, please bring some cold beverages.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Curry’s 3-Point Record in Context: Off the Charts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/01/stephen-currys-3-point-record-in-context-off-the-charts/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-01T13:41:53+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/06/01/stephen-currys-3-point-record-in-context-off-the-charts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fascinating chart by Gregor Aisch and Kevin Quealy over at <em>The New York Times</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>How can we best put the gap between Curry and the best three-point shooters in history in context? Over the past 30 years, the number of 3-point field goals has trended steadily upward. If we project that trend into the future, 402 becomes a perfectly natural number of 3-point field goals for an N.B.A. player to make.</p>

<p>In the mid-2030s.</p></blockquote>

<p>Insane stats from the NBA’s best three-point shooter ever.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Muhammad Ali lighting the Olympic Torch, Atlanta 1996]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/15/muhammad-ali-lighting-the-olympic-torch-atlanta-1996/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-15T19:25:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/15/muhammad-ali-lighting-the-olympic-torch-atlanta-1996</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Better keep your tissues handy:</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gmzr3tZSHxU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p>Via <a href="http://www.tennisplanet.me/blog/2015/12/the-only-no-dry-eye-allowed-sporting-event-in-the-world-and-that-includes-eyes-not-in-attendance-add.html">Tennis Planet</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sepp Blatter to resign as FIFA President in wake of scandal]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/sepp-blatter-to-resign-as-fifa-president-in-wake-of-scandal/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-02T19:54:23+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/06/02/sepp-blatter-to-resign-as-fifa-president-in-wake-of-scandal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sam Borden, writing for <em>The New York Times</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>In a short speech delivered at the headquarters of FIFA, which oversees global soccer, Mr. Blatter said that “FIFA needs a profound restructuring” and that he had decided to step away from the organization where he had worked in various positions for 40 years. Mr. Blatter, 79, who spoke in French, then referred to his recent re-election by FIFA’s 209 member nations when he said, “Although the members of FIFA have given me the new mandate, this mandate does not seem to be supported by everybody in the world of football.”</p></blockquote>

<p>No shit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roger Federer’s Nine Racquets | The New Yorker]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/08/31/roger-federers-nine-racquets-the-new-yorker/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-31T10:55:37+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/08/31/roger-federers-nine-racquets-the-new-yorker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nice piece by Michael Steinberger on Priority 1 (P1), the company formed by Nate Ferguson and Ron Yu, who have been stringing racquets for professional tennis players for decades:</p>

<blockquote>Federer hired the duo on a trial basis at the Italian Open in May, 2004.  Two months later, Federer successfully defended his Wimbledon title. A few hours after the match, Ferguson and Yu heard a knock on the door of their rented house. Federer, dressed in a tuxedo for the Champions Ball, had stopped by to let them know that he was hiring them full-time.</blockquote>


<p>Great anecdote. I also agree with their view on the evolution of tennis as a sport:</p>

<blockquote>They said that the polyester strings, which can generate tremendous topspin, have made tennis less interesting. “It has changed; nobody comes to the net anymore,” Ferguson said. Yu nodded in agreement. “It has become a fitness sport, not a shot-making sport,” he said.</blockquote>


<p>This is one of the clearest examples in the sporting world of how technological advancements can actually make the game less interesting to watch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
