<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: history | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/history/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-05T11:52:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How WWI made wristwatches happen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/09/how-wwi-made-wristwatches-happen/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-09T23:55:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/03/09/how-wwi-made-wristwatches-happen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And speaking about watches, here&rsquo;s an amazing story by Linda Rodriguez on how the traditional pocket watch became the wristwatch we know today:</p>

<blockquote><p>It would take a global war to catapult the wristwatch onto the arms of men the world over. Though the wristwatch wasn’t exactly invented for World War I, it was during this era that it evolved from a useful but fringe piece of military kit to a nearly universal necessity. So why this war? Firstly, the development of the wristwatch was hastened by the style of warfare that soon became symbolic of the First World War: The trenches.</p>

<p>“The problem with the pocket watch is that you have to hold it,” explained Doyle. That wasn’t going to work for the officer at the Western Front – when an officer lead his men “over the top”, leaving the relative safety of the trenches for the pock-marked no man’s land in between and very possible death, he had his gun in one hand and his whistle in the other. “You haven’t got another hand in which to hold your watch.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Fascinating.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Princeton University receives the largest donation of rare books in its history, including the first six Gutenberg Bibles]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/02/18/princeton-university-receives-the-largest-donation-of-rare-books-in-its-history-including-the-first-six-gutenberg-bibles/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-18T18:07:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/02/18/princeton-university-receives-the-largest-donation-of-rare-books-in-its-history-including-the-first-six-gutenberg-bibles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interesting news from Princeton University:</p>

<blockquote><p>The <a href="http://www.princeton.edu/~rbsc/department/scheide/">Scheide Library</a> has been housed in Princeton&rsquo;s Firestone Library since 1959, when Scheide moved the collection from his hometown of Titusville, Pennsylvania. It holds the first six printed editions of the Bible, starting with the 1455 Gutenberg Bible, the earliest substantial European printed book; the original printing of the Declaration of Independence; Beethoven&rsquo;s autograph (in his own handwriting) music sketchbook for 1815-16, the only outside Europe; Shakespeare&rsquo;s first, second, third and fourth folios; significant autograph music manuscripts of Bach, Mozart, Beethoven, Schubert and Wagner; a lengthy autograph speech by Abraham Lincoln from 1856 on the problems of slavery; and Gen. Ulysses S. Grant&rsquo;s original letter and telegram copy books from the last weeks of the Civil War.</p></blockquote>

<p>What a fascinating development. I’m not a religious man, but I do love rare books, and the historical value of the first six Gutenberg Bibles is undeniable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
