<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: productivity | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T18:33:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drew Coffman’s To-Do deep dive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/08/drew-coffmans-to-do-deep-dive/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-08T17:40:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/12/08/drew-coffmans-to-do-deep-dive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Drew Coffman did an amazing deep dive on the best To-Do iOS apps. To call this “comprehensive” would be quite an understatement:</p>

<blockquote><p>I’ve always felt like I’m at my best when I’m at my most organized. Undoubtably, this is why I’ve always been drawn to calendar and task management apps — and it seems like the options and possibilities are <em>limitless</em> when it comes to choosing which app is right for you, and how to use it.</p>

<p>A common problem that occurs upon initially selecting an app, however, is that at first glance it’s extremely difficult to parse which one actually fits the way that your mind works. So, to answer the question of “which is right for you”, you have to determine what it is that you actually <em>need</em>, and which apps can provide the solutions in a way that feels most natural.</p></blockquote>

<p>Great, great work. Picking the right productivity app is no easy task — pun intended — because you must understand how each app works in order to figure out which one you like best. Unfortunately, that takes time and effort that could otherwise be devoted to doing actual work.</p>

<p>For example, I used to be a Things user, both on my Mac and on my iPhone, but it ultimately didn’t stick and I ended up abandoning both apps after a few months. Thanks to Drew’s piece, I now understand that Things was never the right app for me, because it simply wasn’t designed to fit the way I think about work.</p>

<p>Had I not read this piece, if I were to try a new productivity app today, my mind would have jumped straight to Omnifocus. That’s the app I’ve heard most of, it is made by people I respect, and it enjoys a sterling reputation in the iOS developer community. So it would have been an easy choice, at least on paper.</p>

<p>However, after reading Drew’s article, I don’t think Omnifocus is right for me, either. The truth is, everything he wrote about makes me think that either Todoist or Wunderlist would be much better suited for me, personally. And I <em>never</em> would have considered giving those apps so much as a chance if not for this piece.</p>

<p>If you’ve been struggling with your productivity app of choice, or are looking to try one for the first time, I can’t recommend this article enough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shawn Blanc announces The Focus Course]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/29/shawn-blanc-announces-the-focus-course/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-29T22:03:32+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/29/shawn-blanc-announces-the-focus-course</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a big day for Shawn. After many, many months working his ass off, today he finally unveiled the landing page for his upcoming course on productivity. In his own words:</p>

<blockquote><p>At the end of the day, <strong>it&rsquo;s all about giving our time and energy to the things which are meaningful</strong>. I want a lifestyle that is conducive to doing my best creative work without sacrificing a healthy work/life balance to get there.</p>

<p><strong>Living with diligence and focus is not a personality type — it&rsquo;s a skill we can learn.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>The Focus Course is a massive undertaking, and also a massive accomplishment. I’m really happy for Shawn, and I’m convinced it’s going to be a smashing success. If you care about productivity and living a life with purpose, you owe it to yourself to check it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Brooks on managing work across time zones]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/22/ben-brooks-on-managing-work-across-time-zones/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-22T19:53:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/04/22/ben-brooks-on-managing-work-across-time-zones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I greatly enjoyed this essay by Ben Brooks on how they manage their work across multiple time zones at Martian Craft:</p>

<blockquote><p>Once you have an idea who is in what time zone, and what everyone’s core hours are, it’s time to address the biggest problem in a multi-time zone office: <em>talking</em> about time. There isn’t a day that goes by where I don’t think: Slack why can’t you translate this time based on who is viewing it.</p>

<p>Instead, like many people, I bet you find yourself in this trap: “Is that my time, or your time?” That’s easily a 10 minute conversation to get everyone back on the same page. Even then, there is no guarantee that everyone knows exactly when something is supposed to take place.</p></blockquote>

<p>When there are lots of moving parts, having a well-defined system in place becomes essential.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tools &amp; Toys guide to setting up and maintaining a paperless home and office]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/05/the-tools-and-toys-guide-to-setting-up-and-maintaining-a-paperless-home-and-office/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-05T12:46:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2015/01/05/the-tools-and-toys-guide-to-setting-up-and-maintaining-a-paperless-home-and-office</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have long been a fan of paperless work practices. Doing everything we can to minimize our paper trail is important: there are many benefits — instantly searchable archives, for one — and absolutely zero disadvantages, so trying to avoid filling our offices with dead trees is pretty much a no-brainer for me.</p>

<p>This great guide over at Tools &amp; Toys gives you everything you need to get started on the transition to a pristine, paperless office. Of course, the real dream would be to not generate any paper to begin with, but unfortunately this is not yet feasible in todays’s world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little things that improve the way Shawn Blanc works on a Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/10/02/little-things-that-improve-the-way-shawn-blanc-works-on-a-mac/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-02T12:37:27+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2014/10/02/little-things-that-improve-the-way-shawn-blanc-works-on-a-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plenty of useful tips from Shawn here on how to use automation tasks as part of your workflow to improve daily productivity:</p>

<blockquote><p>Computers are great at doing the boring, automated stuff we don’t like to do. So why not automate common tasks (like performing backups of your computer), pre-make decisions for your computer to carry out on your behalf (such as auto-filing certain email newsletters), and generally just find ways to make yourself more efficient?</p></blockquote>

<p>Good stuff. He makes an interesting point towards the end:</p>

<blockquote><p>It can be easy to get hyper nerdy about this stuff, and to spend forever and a day tinkering and fiddling and “optimizing”. I listed out the above things not to say that you should be utilizing them as well, but instead to give you an idea of perhaps one or two ways that you could work smarter.</p></blockquote>

<p>He&rsquo;s right on the money here, and it made me think of this wonderful <a href="http://xkcd.com/1205/">xkcd comic</a> from last year:</p>

<p><a href="http://xkcd.com/1205/"><img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/is_it_worth_the_time.png" alt="Is It Worth the Time?" /></a></p>

<p>That could very well serve as a rough guideline, to keep things in perspective before you start going crazy with the automation scripts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
