<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photokina | Analog Senses]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/categories/photokina/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-09-08T18:33:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Álvaro Serrano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Fuji X-T2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/10/14/hands-on-with-the-fuji-x-t2/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-14T18:56:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/10/14/hands-on-with-the-fuji-x-t2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fuji has been pretty busy lately. The company made arguably the biggest splash at <a href="http://www.photokina.com/photokina/index-9.php">Photokina 2016</a> by announcing <a href="http://www.fujifilmusa.com/press/news/display_news?newsID=881070">an entirely new Medium Format system</a>, including the new GFX camera and an astonishing <em>six</em> lenses, to be released over the next few months.</p>

<p>The GFX was by far the most sought-after announcement at Photokina — after all, it’s not every day that you get to play with a 50-Megapixel Medium Format beast. Naturally, hands-on time was <em>extremely</em> limited, even more so considering the camera  — yes, there was only one — is still a pre-production unit.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I didn’t manage to get my hands on the GFX, but for what it’s worth, it looks like an impressive system. It’s certainly bigger and bulkier than <a href="http://www.hasselblad.com/x1d">Hasselblad’s new X1D</a> camera, but it remains roughly the same size as a Canon 5D-series body, which is a remarkable achievement. If Fuji’s price claims — well under $10k for the GFX body with one lens — end up being true, it will also be significantly more affordable than the rest of its Medium Format competitors, including the aforementioned X1D.</p>

<p>In fact, the GFX has the potential to be the camera that turns Medium Format digital photography into a feasible option for a wider range of professional photographers, not just those operating in extremely high-end, niche areas. It’s exciting.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_1" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8272/29690108734_5149425293_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8272/29690108734_5149425293_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:33%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_1" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5466/29689926773_e1aa244b58_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5466/29689926773_e1aa244b58_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_1" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8273/30234544261_1f42d4248b_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8273/30234544261_1f42d4248b_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_1" href="https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7582/29690114244_9b41b4003f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7582/29690114244_9b41b4003f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>However the situation plays out, Medium Format mirrorless systems appear to be here to stay. For now, both Hasselblad’s and Fujifilm’s offerings have their fair share of strengths and weaknesses, so we’ll see which one resonates more with prospective customers. The game is most definitely on.</p>

<p class="card-separator">♢</p>


<p>Now, Fuji may have captured the attention of many eyeballs at Photokina with the GFX, but the real star of their hands-on area was, of course, <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">the recently announced X-T2</a>. As the new flagship of Fuji’s widely acclaimed X-series system, the X-T2 fixes many of the shortcomings of <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00HYAL88W&amp;uk=B00I3I2D9W&amp;es=B00I3I2D9W">the original X-T1</a> while staying true to its essence. I had a chance to shoot with it for a while, as well as to chat about it at length with Fujifilm employee <a href="https://www.instagram.com/fauland.photography/">Peter Fauland</a>, and I have to say I came away very impressed. If you want to listen to my conversation with Peter, check out <a href="http://www.candid.fm/30">this special episode of Candid</a>, which was recorded on location at Photokina. And now, let’s take a closer look at the camera.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_2" href="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8662/30234504831_bdbc0700e4_o.jpg"><img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8662/30234504831_bdbc0700e4_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:56.55%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_2" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8136/30204543902_7bbd1659bb_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8136/30204543902_7bbd1659bb_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_2" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8277/30285517886_0bf1a4471f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8277/30285517886_0bf1a4471f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
        <p class="caption">Fujifilm employee <a href="https://www.instagram.com/fauland.photography/">Peter Fauland</a> was kind enough to show me <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">the new Fuji X-T2</a> and helped me test some of its new features.</p>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<h2>Design and build quality</h2>

<p>The Fuji X-T2’s body is a joy to hold and use. It looks very similar to the X-T1’s, but it has improved ergonomics and controls. The grip is slightly more recessed now, making it more comfortable with longer lenses, and there’s a switch on the top of the ISO and mode dials that locks/unlocks their position with a single click, instead of having to keep pressure on the switch as you rotate the dial.</p>

<p>The new body also has a clever tilting screen that can be tilted in both landscape and portrait orientations. This allows you to compose overhead or ground-level shots with ease, and is more flexible than your typical tilting screen. It doesn’t have a selfie mode, though, which may limit the camera’s appeal as a video-blogging tool. Not that it matters much, though; the X-T2’s certainly appears to have set more ambitious goals for itself.</p>

<p>Finally, there’s now dual SD card slots, so you can always have a backup of your pictures at the ready. No more losing pictures because of a faulty card. This is such a no-brainer feature that I can’t understand why some manufacturers — ahem, Sony — haven’t implemented it yet.</p>

<p>None of these differences are profound, or game-changing, but they didn’t need to be. The X-T1 was already an excellent body, and subtle improvements like these will make using the X-T2 even better.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_3" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8130/30234487201_b82cded0e3_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8130/30234487201_b82cded0e3_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:43.93%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_3" href="https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7531/30234495871_66b484027f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7531/30234495871_66b484027f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_3" href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5648/30023650240_3e5ff82c61_o.jpg"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5648/30023650240_3e5ff82c61_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:43.93%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_3" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7461/29690079914_f3aeaa3649_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7461/29690079914_f3aeaa3649_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_3" href="https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5692/29690069884_864f205fdb_o.jpg"><img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5692/29690069884_864f205fdb_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<h2>Image quality and performance</h2>

<p>The X-T2’s 24-megapixel X-Trans III sensor delivers stunning image quality, much like what we saw in <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01A8DUR74&amp;uk=B01AP7S4GE&amp;es=B01AP7S4GE">the X-Pro 2</a> earlier in the year. Dynamic range is great for an APS-C sensor, and the RAW files are quite malleable in post-production. The extra resolution over the 16-MP X-T1 is very welcome, and should eliminate any concerns about using Fuji’s X-Series system as a serious work tool. You can definitely print big with this camera, and you should be covered for most types of commercial work: weddings, product photography, fashion&hellip; The X-T2 can do it all. As high-resolution sensors become mainstream it’s becoming clear that you don’t <em>need</em> a Medium Format or even a Full Frame camera to pull off these types of jobs anymore.</p>

<p>Of course, all of Fuji’s film simulation modes are built into the X-T2, including <a href="https://mariusmasalar.me/photo-essay-b4d90fdb00e6">the stunning Acros</a>. And with the dual SD card slots, you can configure the camera to write JPEGs to one card while writing RAW files to the other. Now there’s no excuse not to make use of the gorgeous JPEGs Fuji cameras are known for.</p>

<p>I played with these at Photokina for a while, and it’s tons of fun. The Provia profile worked wonders for people shots, even in lighting conditions as challenging as an indoor hall with a variety of different light sources, each of which had its very own color temperature. The camera did a great job setting the white balance, and the images came out looking rich, detailed, and with just the right amount of contrast. It wasn’t perfect — some isolated shots had a clear yellow cast — but overall, it was impressive.</p>

<p>For reference, here’s a few image samples I shot with the X-T2 at Photokina. All of these were shot as JPEGs and have only been cropped and resized. No further edits were applied.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:45.66%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_4" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8274/30320259865_f068a346e2_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8274/30320259865_f068a346e2_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_4" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5764/30285353686_1f75e5075a_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5764/30285353686_1f75e5075a_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:45.66%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_4" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5497/30204382602_d57421178e_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5497/30204382602_d57421178e_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_4" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8418/29689736713_f70919cae4_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8418/29689736713_f70919cae4_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_4" href="hhttps://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5752/30320276625_904e22543b_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5752/30320276625_904e22543b_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        <p class="caption">The camera usually does a great job of setting the white balance, but it may fail in challenging lighting conditions. Notice the obvious yellow cast in the image above.</p>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>As far as performance goes, the X-T2 is a two-part story. First there’s the body, which is capable of shooting at up to 8 fps with full AF capabilities. That’s not bad at all, but things get even more interesting when you attach the X-T2’s power boosting grip.</p>

<p>The grip doesn’t just extend battery life into DSLR territory — Fuji claims up to 1,000 shots on a single charge — but it also improves performance significantly. With it, the burst rate goes up to 11 fps and the refresh rate of the EVF goes up to 100 fps, up from an already very good 60 fps. This will not only help you track your subjects more accurately; it will also eliminate any flickering due to artificial lights, which dramatically improves usability indoors.</p>

<p>Another new feature in the X-T2 is <a href="http://fujifilm-x.com/af/en/index.html">the improved autofocus system</a>, especially when it comes to subject tracking in C-AF. Fuji’s latest flagship has 5 different AF modes that allow you to fine-tune tracking behavior under several different circumstances, plus a sixth user-customizable mode. To make it easier to know which mode to use, each one is represented by a sample image in the menu. You can, for example, configure the camera to keep tracking the initial subject and ignore any obstacles. You can also tell it to look for accelerating/decelerating subjects. You can tell it to look for suddenly appearing subjects — which has a very descriptive picture of a skier jumping into the frame — or you can tell it to look for all kinds of erratic movements, a mode that Peter very aptly described as “total chaos”. The picture for that one is, fittingly, a tennis player during a match.</p>

<p>As far as I could tell during my brief testing, each of the new modes definitely changes the way the camera tracks motion, so this new AF system isn’t just a gimmick. The problem is, there’s a bit of a learning curve here, and it’s not always easy to know which mode is best suited to the task at hand despite the descriptive images. It took Peter and I over 15 minutes to get acceptable results in our two very simple test setups: sliding a water bottle in and out of view at moderate speed, with smooth left-to-right and back-to-front movements. We did get a fair amount of out of focus shots initially, but once we managed to find the appropriate mode for each case, tracking worked great. I would also expect the system to work better with people, especially faces. After all, a water bottle isn’t exactly the most exciting subject to track.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:45.66%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_5" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5713/30320270765_4df0dded30_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5713/30320270765_4df0dded30_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_5" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5488/29689750653_022ab112a4_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5488/29689750653_022ab112a4_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:45.49%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_5" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5587/30204381082_c59811951f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5587/30204381082_c59811951f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="X-T2_5" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5698/30204378322_d83d086db5_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5698/30204378322_d83d086db5_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>The point here is that the new AF tracking modes are a clear improvement, and they should bring the X-T2 to the front of the mirrorless pack when it comes to fast action shooting. They should also make it at least competitive with DSLRs, although to be fair, there’s still a bit of a gap here. It’s getting closer and closer with each new mirrorless generation, but for now, if shooting sports or similarly fast-paced action is your bread and butter, a high-end crop DSLR still looks like the best tool for the job. For those of us with more modest needs — just about everyone outside of professional sports shooters — the X-T2 should be more than enough to get the job done.</p>

<p>There’s also much to love about the X-T2 for video enthusiasts. The camera can now shoot 4K footage internally, and there are some great Fuji color profiles available for video, too. This has the potential to substantially reduce the amount of post-processing needed, and in fact most people will be able to get usable footage straight out of the camera. The X-T2 also has a new F-Log profile that greatly enhances dynamic range and that should makes color grading a lot easier. All in all, this is a solid offering, especially considering previous Fuji cameras have never been that great at video.</p>

<p>Overall, the X-T2 is an absolute powerhouse of a camera. In fact, the only omission I can think of is in-body image stabilization, something Fuji isn’t too keen on anyway. Fuji believes lens-based image stabilization to be a superior technology, and they’re sticking to it. Meanwhile, every other player in the industry is moving in the opposite direction, so we’ll see how this plays out in the end. For now, this doesn’t take much away from the X-T2 in practice; if their lens-based stabilization technology is good enough — and it is — then this is more of an academic debate than a practical one.</p>

<h2>Parting thoughts</h2>

<p>With the release of the X-T2, the Fuji X-Series system now represents everything I love about photography: great design, manageable size and weight, fantastic usability, awesome image quality, and a plethora of superb lenses to choose from. More importantly, it is a system designed by and for photographers, something that is easily noticeable upon spending just a few minutes with it.</p>

<p>It tempts me more than anything else out there.</p>

<p>As much as I love my Sony camera and my lenses, there’s just something missing there. They don’t feel like creative tools, more like exceptional technical instruments. They lack character, something Fuji cameras seem to have in spades.</p>

<p>Had I not committed to the Full Frame Sony system, picking up an X-T2 would be <em>so</em> easy. In fact, in some deep recess of my mind, I can see a version of myself that sells every piece of Sony kit he owns and puts the money towards <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01I3LNMAM&amp;uk=B01I5LE51A&amp;es=B01I5LE51A">the X-T2</a>, the <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00RSQTDMA&amp;uk=B00SDC5LU6&amp;es=B00SDC5LU6">16-55mm f/2.8</a> zoom, and the trio of <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B01KNXOCO8&amp;uk=B01KZ4XBA6&amp;es=B01KZ4XBA6">23mm f/2</a>, <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B016S28I4S&amp;uk=B016XNJ2JM&amp;es=B016XNJ2JM">35mm f/2</a> and <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&amp;us=B00HK8Z9AG&amp;uk=B00HXBROLC&amp;es=B00HXBROLC">56mm f/1.2</a> primes. He looks damn happy, and he would probably even come out ahead in terms of money. That version of myself haunts me every day.</p>

<p>But I guess commitments wouldn’t be called that if they were easy to make. Part of staying with a system for the long haul is learning to let go of passing temptations to switch. I still think <a href="/2016/01/13/gear-guide-the-best-full-frame-lenses-for-the-sony-e-mount/#landing-point">the Sony E-mount system</a> offers greater potential, and I hope it will be realized in the near future. A new Sony camera — be it the A7 III or the long-rumored A9 — with improved ergonomics and performance and dual SD card slots would go a long way towards easing my mind.</p>

<p>In the meantime, though, I can’t help but keep looking at the X-T2 and wonder&hellip; what if?</p>

<p><section class="product-link">
    <h4 class="buy-now">Buy it online</h4>
    <a href="http://amznlinks.com/global?user=analogsenses&us=B01I3LNMAM&uk=B01I5LE51A&es=B01I5LE51A"><img src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5488/30351393771_bc9d8226b2_o.jpg"/></a>
</section></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands-on with the Yi M1 MFT camera (image samples)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/09/27/hands-on-with-the-yi-m1-mft-camera/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-27T17:33:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/09/27/hands-on-with-the-yi-m1-mft-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week at Photokina, there was one announcement that surprised pretty much everyone. Chinese company Yi Technology — the camera branch of smartphone manufacturer Xiaomi — just became a new Micro Four Thirds player by announcing the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/YI-Mirrorless-Digital-Camera-42-5mm/dp/B01CW4CNKG/?tag=analogsens-20">Yi M1</a>, a small camera with clean lines and a minimalist design, a classic look very reminiscent of Leica cameras.</p>

<p>The Yi M1 comes in your choice of silver — <em>Ice Silver</em>, actually — or <em>Storm Black</em>. Let’s just get it out of the way: yes, it looks <em>a lot</em> like the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Leica-018-181-Mirrorless-3-7-Inch-Anodized/dp/B00K0PJV3M/?tag=analogsens-20">Leica T</a>. And no, that doesn’t bother me one bit. After all, if you’re going to be “inspired” by someone else’s design, Leica is definitely not a bad role model to choose.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-1" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8187/29672622230_bd22531181_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8187/29672622230_bd22531181_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:35.22%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-1" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8076/29966280065_cc4986c969_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8076/29966280065_cc4986c969_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-1" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8397/29852271782_30bdc699b0_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8397/29852271782_30bdc699b0_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-1" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8135/29339651693_9e30947b02_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8135/29339651693_9e30947b02_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<h2>Build quality and features</h2>

<p>The Yi M1 has plenty of substance to go with its looks, though. It packs a 20-megapixel Sony sensor inside, similar to the ones found in the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Olympus-V204060SU000-PEN-F-Body-Only-Silver/dp/B01AW10GM8/?tag=analogsens-20">Olympus PEN-F</a> and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Panasonic-DMC-GX8SBODY-Mirrorless-Camera-Stabilization/dp/B011B8QX32/?tag=analogsens-20">Panasonic GX8</a>, so resolution and dynamic range should be in the same ballpark as what you get with those cameras.</p>

<p>The camera is able to record 1080p video at 60 fps, but also 4K video at 30 fps, which will be great news for those looking for a competent video-blogging camera that won’t break the bank.</p>

<p>On the ergonomics front, the Yi M1 is very light, weighing only 280 g. The grip is comfortable enough if you’re shooting with small lenses, but if I were to mount heavier glass on it I’d definitely want to have something a bit more substantial.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-2" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5512/29932213686_63c0dbc5b2_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5512/29932213686_63c0dbc5b2_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:37.12%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-2" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8116/29932291386_e86f4aa55f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8116/29932291386_e86f4aa55f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-2" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5259/29672705070_f9980fc6ac_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5259/29672705070_f9980fc6ac_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-2" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8072/29966141805_5a7ae3d2e6_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8072/29966141805_5a7ae3d2e6_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>The Yi M1 also has a nice touchscreen that responds very well to touch, and the menus seem very clear and intuitive to use. Just swipe right to bring up the menu, then swipe up or down to navigate through the different pages to access your desired option. I really like how this was implemented.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:33.18%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-3" href="https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7696/29339014044_e9dfc09374_o.jpg"><img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7696/29339014044_e9dfc09374_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-3" href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8072/29932219056_10e4ba5336_o.jpg"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8072/29932219056_10e4ba5336_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-3" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8598/29883268641_3d2942fa4d_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8598/29883268641_3d2942fa4d_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        <p class="caption">You can change which parameter is operated by the control dial just by tapping one of the options displayed on the screen.</p>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>The camera only has one physical control dial — besides the main mode dial and the ON/OFF switch — but switching from aperture to shutter speed control only takes a single tap on the rear LCD, so I’m calling this an acceptable compromise. The dial itself feels surprisingly well, as do the rest of the buttons on the camera — all two of them. Of course, the body is still mostly made out of plastic, although the lens mount is made of metal. There’s no electronic viewfinder or built-in flash, but the camera does have a hotshoe, so perhaps those will be added down the road as external accessories.</p>

<p>All in all, this is a decently made camera with basic dedicated hardware controls, which is understandable in this category.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-4" href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8704/29338918264_cd4ded3ace_o.jpg"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8704/29338918264_cd4ded3ace_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:37.12%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-4" href="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8094/29339767843_cf56524d55_o.jpg"><img src="https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8094/29339767843_cf56524d55_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-4" href="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8081/29672663510_d5873f4aca_o.jpg"><img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8081/29672663510_d5873f4aca_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-4" href="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8545/29339043204_5db4f6c49f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8545/29339043204_5db4f6c49f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>Where the Yi M1 hopes to differentiate itself from the pack, however, is with the connectivity features. The camera has Bluetooth Low Energy and WiFi, and there’s a dedicated smartphone companion app — available on both Android and iOS — that will make it very easy to share pictures to your social network or cloud service of choice. I didn’t have a chance to test this feature, but according to two Yi representatives, the company is betting heavily on it to be one of the camera’s main selling points.</p>

<p>For what it’s worth, the current smartphone camera companion app is not exactly brimming with excellent choices, so if they manage to nail this aspect, I could definitely see it becoming popular.</p>

<p>Speaking of social sharing, there’s another feature in the Yi M1 that strikes me as extremely clever. They’re calling it Master Guide, and it’s basically a collection of compositional guidelines to help you get tried-and-true portrait poses of your subjects. If you’re lacking some inspiration but still want to get nicely posed shots, this will come in super handy. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rO82uWQCgFU">this video</a> to see how the feature works. Brilliant!</p>

<p><div class="video-wrapper"><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rO82uWQCgFU" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div></p>

<p class="caption">The Master Guide feature is an extremely clever idea, and one I would like to see other manufacturers adopt.</p>


<h2>Pricing and availability</h2>

<p>The other main selling point, of course, will be price. The Yi M1 will be released in the US on October 12, and it will start at $499 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/YI-Mirrorless-Digital-12-40mm-F3-5-5-6/dp/B01CW4CQW6/?tag=analogsens-20">with a lens</a>, which is a terrific value for the amount of technology that you get. Besides, being a Micro Four Thirds camera, the Yi M1 will be compatible with the entire MFT lens catalog from both Olympus and Panasonic, as well as third party manufacturers like Sigma and Voigtlander. This is one of the perks of entering a fully mature system: you don’t need to develop everything yourself from scratch. Smart move.</p>

<p>That being said, Yi also announced two new lenses of their own: a typical 12-40mm f/3.5-5.6 zoom lens, and a more interesting 42.5mm f/1.8 Macro lens. Both lenses are mostly made out of plastic and are very light and compact. What is surprising, though, is that the camera will also be available in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/YI-Mirrorless-Digital-12-40mm-F3-5-5-6/dp/B01CW4CKHW/?tag=analogsens-20">a very nice kit with <em>both</em> lenses</a> for $699, which is still a pretty good value, except I don’t really see the point in owning the kit zoom. I’d much prefer to get the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/YI-Mirrorless-Digital-Camera-42-5mm/dp/B01CW4CNKG/?tag=analogsens-20">kit with just the prime lens</a> for $599, but maybe that’s just me.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-5" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5252/29339693773_b7f3fa8231_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5252/29339693773_b7f3fa8231_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:37.12%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-5" href="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8062/29339680663_3511c2fdca_o.jpg"><img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8062/29339680663_3511c2fdca_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-5" href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8752/29338929544_2e08e69380_o.jpg"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8752/29338929544_2e08e69380_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-5" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5706/29966158305_b0fcbab132_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5706/29966158305_b0fcbab132_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<h2>Performance and image quality</h2>

<p>Now, I know what you’re thinking: <em>All that’s well and good, but how’s the image quality? Where are those images samples you mentioned in the title?</em></p>

<p>Glad you asked. Actually, all images in this article were taken with the Yi M1 and the 42.5mm prime, so feel free to inspect them as much as you want. For a bit of context, these were shot at the Yi stand in Photokina under artificial light — and not very much of it, at that. They should provide for an interesting real-world example of the kind of performance you should expect from this camera.</p>

<p>Of course, these are somewhat edited and heavily compressed JPEGs for the web, so if you want to play with the RAW files yourself, I’ve also uploaded a few of them <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/8lqv381ed5bkan8/AAAgL9WYr5kd9lkwKe3cjjCFa?dl=0">to Dropbox</a>. I can’t promise they’ll stay up indefinitely so if you’re interested, be sure to grab them while they’re hot. And speaking of the files, the camera uses the standard Adobe DNG file format, so it is already supported by pretty much every photo-editing app out there, including Lightroom.</p>

<p>Low-light performance seems to be right in line with the other MFT cameras that use this 20-megapixel sensor: images are clean at up to ISO 3,200, but they are still quite usable at ISO 6,400. The extra resolution means you can trade some of that detail for a bit more aggressive noise reduction and still come out ahead in terms of image quality. Shadow recovery also seemed perfectly adequate, and the files take sharpening very well.</p>

<p>I did notice that the camera’s built-in light meter had a strong tendency to underexpose, and I regularly needed to boost exposure in post production, in some cases by as much as 1.2 stops. This may have been due to the challenging lighting conditions, though, so I wouldn’t consider it a problem just yet. And you can always use the exposure compensation feature anyway, so once you figure out the bias, it’s not a big deal.</p>

<p>AF performance was a bit on the slow side. The camera didn’t hunt for focus very much, but it was just slow. Now, I only got to test the camera with the two Yi-made lenses so performance may be better with, say, Olympus primes, which are some of the fastest-focusing lenses for the system. Again, the poor lighting conditions made it difficult for me to test this feature extensively, so I can’t speak for the camera’s AF performance in better conditions.</p>

<p>What was most surprising to me is the fact that the camera doesn’t support manual focusing at all. The focusing ring on both lenses is merely cosmetic, which is just surreal. It’s unclear at this point if this is a firmware or hardware limitation — meaning, MF might work with other lenses — but in its current state it is just silly.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:37.12%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-6" href="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8506/29672582220_da3d5fa213_o.jpg"><img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8506/29672582220_da3d5fa213_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-6" href="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5263/29883173661_eeaea94ef4_o.jpg"><img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5263/29883173661_eeaea94ef4_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-6" href="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8337/29339697903_370827620c_o.jpg"><img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8337/29339697903_370827620c_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<p>As for the lenses, I didn’t shoot much with the zoom lens, but I have to say I was pleasantly surprised by the 42.5mm lens. It is very sharp and chromatic aberration is reasonably well controlled — there are traces of it here and there, but at this price point we certainly can’t complain. Normally I wouldn’t even look at this lens because the excellent <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Olympus-M-ZUIKO-Digital-Panasonic-Cameras/dp/B00CI3R53W/?tag=analogsens-20">Olympus 45mm f/1.8</a> prime is one of my favorite lenses, but the Yi prime has a neat trick up its sleeve that has me questioning my love for the Oly: the macro mode.</p>

<p>Flicking a switch on the lens barrel, you get to take macro pictures, which adds a whole new dimension to the lens and greatly expands its shooting capabilities. Unfortunately, the aperture goes down to f/3.5 when you’re shooting in macro mode, but that’s a small price to pay for the feature.</p>

<p><section class="photoset">
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
        <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-7" href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8271/29338925784_13b5d6656c_o.jpg"><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8271/29338925784_13b5d6656c_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
    </figure></notextile></div>
    <div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="sidebyside">
        <div class="stretchy-wrapper" style="padding-bottom:37.12%">
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-7" href="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8238/29672698330_003093d7a8_o.jpg"><img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8238/29672698330_003093d7a8_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
            <a class="fancybox" rel="YiM1-7" href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5789/29966317785_7a3c43e08f_o.jpg"><img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5789/29966317785_7a3c43e08f_o.jpg" alt="" /></a>
        </div>
    </figure></notextile></div>
</section></p>

<h2>A darn good first impression</h2>

<p>I must admit that when I first heard of the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/YI-Mirrorless-Digital-12-40mm-F3-5-5-6/dp/B01CW4CKHW/?tag=analogsens-20">Yi M1</a>, I didn’t give it much credit. It just felt like a cheap attempt at copying the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Leica-018-181-Mirrorless-3-7-Inch-Anodized/dp/B00K0PJV3M/?tag=analogsens-20">Leica T</a>.</p>

<p>However, after playing with it for a while, it strikes me as a very compelling first-entry into the Micro Four Thirds arena. It’s not weather-sealed, it feels plasticky, and it doesn’t focus very fast, but all those things don’t matter when you look at the pictures you can take with it.</p>

<p>This camera packs some serious punch, and it shouldn’t be underestimated. The entry level to the Micro Four Thirds system just got a heck of a lot better, and both Olympus and Panasonic will have to raise the bar accordingly. Imagine what this company could do two or three years from now, once they’ve had time to iron out the kinks, if they decide to pursue the higher end of the market.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5328/29852208452_aa7ca39c74_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>During my visit to their stand, one of the Yi representatives I spoke with noticed my <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Alpha-Mirrorless-Digital-Camera/dp/B00PX8CHO6/?tag=analogsens-20">Sony a7 II camera</a>, then looked me in the eye very seriously and said: “<em>your camera is for work. Our camera is for life</em>”. They just may be onto something here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photokina Diaries: Hands on with the new Sony a99 Mark II]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/09/20/photokina-diaries-the-sony-a99-mark-ii/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-20T14:59:57+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.analogsenses.com/2016/09/20/photokina-diaries-the-sony-a99-mark-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Greetings from beautiful Cologne, Germany! In case you missed the recent talk on Twitter, I’m attending <a href="http://www.photokina.com">Photokina</a> for the first time, and so far I’m really loving the show. If you want to stay up to date, keep an eye on Analog Senses, <a href="http://www.candid.fm">Candid</a>, and <a href="http://toolsandtoys.net">Tools &amp; Toys</a> during the week to make sure you get all Photokina-related coverage. It’s going to be a blast!</p>

<p>Today I was invited to a private Sony press event where the company briefed us on the newly announced <a href="http://presscentre.sony.eu/pressreleases/sony-launches-new-flagship-a-a-mount-camera-the-a99-ii-1565273">a99 Mark II</a> camera. Long story short, it’s an extremely compelling camera, and I was very impressed with many of the features Sony built into this new flagship.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8494/29700351322_f4c5a8189a_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">This is where the private Sony press conferences are held. Mum’s the word!</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The a99 II includes a new 42MP back-illuminated sensor, which is similar to the one found in the a7R II. However, Sony has created a new front-LSI image processor which takes some of the workload from the BIONZ X image processor, and the company said they expect the new camera to outperform the a7R II in low light situations, although they didn’t say by how much.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="extra-width">
<img src="https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8301/29730888791_00185239d1_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">The Sony a99 Mark II, the new flagship in the A-mount system. Photo credit: Sony.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8340/29777564506_c3304a1568_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">The sensor in the a99 II has similar specs to the one in the a7R II, but Sony says low light performance should be improved thanks to the new front-LSI image processor.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>On the speed front, the a99 II is capable of shooting up to 12fps at the full 42MP resolution and with full AF capabilities, which is very, very impressive. And for the first time, they’re displaying the state of the memory buffer on screen, so you know how many frames you can shoot before your camera slows down. For what is worth, it never froze on me during the hands-on time I spent shooting with it. These buffers are <em>deep</em>.</p>

<p>Sony has also included the Live View mode they introduced with the a6300, which allows you to see the action in real-time through the viewfinder as you shoot, making it easier to track moving subjects while shooting in burst mode. This mode is limited to 8fps, though, as in the a6300. There’s a big difference between shooting in Live View mode and shooting in the regular EVF mode, and I very much prefer to use Live View when shooting bursts.</p>

<p>The a99 II also includes many of the nice features found in the a7-series cameras, including a superb EVF and 5-axis in-body image stabilization. Sony says the IBIS system in the a99 II can compensate for up to 4.5 stops, which is pretty good, and probably a bit better than the E-mount cameras can do in real-world shooting.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8677/29700346452_2abef20ee2_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">The a99 II includes a newly designed 5-axis image stabilization system that is capable of providing up to 4.5 stops of compensation according to Sony.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>But perhaps the most remarkable feature in the a99 II is, of course, the new AF system. Sony has improved the dedicated AF sensor — which is the trademark of the A-mount — with 79 AF points, 15 of which are cross-type. However, for the first time, they’ve combined those with the 399 on-sensor phase-detection AF points to convert all 79 AF points into hybrid cross-type AF points.</p>

<p>What does that mean? Well, the normal AF points inside the dedicated AF system are tweaked to detect horizontal lines, while the 399 on-sensor AF points are configured to detect vertical lines. By combining both systems, the 79 horizontal AF points overlap with some of the 399 vertical AF points, resulting in 79 hybrid cross-type AF points which, according to Sony, provide much more responsive and accurate AF performance.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8363/29777559686_f50d2692bf_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">The a99 II features a hybrid AF system: a translucent mirror deflects a small fraction of incoming light to a dedicated AF sensor with 79 phase detection points, but the camera also has 399 on-sensor phase detection points.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Finally, to round-up the impressive AF system, face detection and Eye AF are also included, both of which make taking pictures of people a lot easier. I’m used to having these features on my a7 II, and I wouldn’t give them up for anything.</p>

<p>All in all, the a99 II is a worthy addition to the A-mount system, and clearly the new flagship camera from Sony. It either matches or exceeds the performance and feature set of the a7R II, and it does so while retaining the identity of the A-mount. I’m all for mirrorless cameras, but if you prefer a more classic DSLR style, this one should definitely be near the top of your list.</p>

<h2>Hands-on: lightning fast, but heavy</h2>

<p>During my hands-on time with it, I got to shoot several couples of dancers with a variety of styles, ranging from classic ballet to capoeira, all in a well-lit studio. The camera performed admirably, especially considering the difficulty of the situation. AF was snappy and accurate with the 70-200 f/2.8 zoom lens, and it managed to track the dancers very well. I did get the occasional out of focus shot when one dancer would cross in front of the other, which brings me to another new feature found in this camera.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8123/29777617706_5117a59423_k.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>For the first time in a Sony camera, you can configure the AF system to keep focus on the subject that’s being tracked and ignore interruptions, or to switch focus to the closer subject. I didn’t have time to go that deep in the menu system during the event (all we had was like 10-15 minutes with it), but I expect the minor issues I saw to be solved by using the proper AF configuration.</p>

<p>Face detection also worked brilliantly, and it considerably improved the accuracy of the autofocus systems when shooting these dancers. Without face detection, the camera would sometimes focus on a dancer’s torso or limbs, whereas with face detection on, it would almost always find their faces. Of course, no camera is going to be able to get 100% of your shots in focus, but the a99 II certainly got close.</p>

<p>On the minus column, there’s no question this is a heavy camera. Between the a99 II and the 70-200mm f/2.8 lens, the combination was heavy enough that my arms were starting to get tired after just a few short minutes of shooting. If size and weight are a primary concern for you, I’d probably advise you to take a look at Sony’s E-mount offerings instead.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8410/29813614365_c7a8bf5b4e_o.jpg"/></p>

<p class="caption">I got to test the camera with the Sony 70-200mm f/2.8 SSM II lens, and the combination performed brilliantly, although it was pretty heavy. Photo credit: Sony.</p>


<p></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Unfortunately, the units we tested are still pre-production models, so we couldn’t take the images home with us. That’s why I couldn’t include any pictures of the session in this post. I could, however, take pictures of the camera with my own, so here’s a nice shot of the actual new a99 II for your viewing pleasure.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class="full-width">
<img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8465/29777591976_f26f32e586_o.jpg"/>
</figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The a99 II is the only new product Sony has announced at Photokina, but the company has a massive stand in the main area and I do hope to get some hands-on time with some of the more recent E-mount products, so stay tuned for more!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
